<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mac on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/mac/</link><description>Recent content in mac on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 14:31:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Play/pause button stopped working in OS X Mavericks</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/30/playpause-button-stopped-working-in-os-x-mavericks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 14:31:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/30/playpause-button-stopped-working-in-os-x-mavericks/</guid><description>My play/pause button mysteriously stopped working in iTunes and VLC mysteriously this week on my laptop. It affected the previous track and next track buttons as well. It turns out that my Google Music extension in Chrome stole the keyboard bindings after the extension updated this week.
If your buttons stopped working as well, follow these steps to check your keyboard shortcuts in Chrome:
Choose Preferences in the Chrome menu in the menu bar Click Extensions in the left sidebar Scroll all the way to the bottom of the page Click Keyboard Shortcuts Look at the key bindings in the Google Play Music section Your shortcuts might look like the ones shown here in an Apple support forum.</description></item><item><title>One month using a Linux laptop at work: Back to the Mac</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/22/one-month-using-a-linux-laptop-at-work-back-to-the-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 02:38:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/22/one-month-using-a-linux-laptop-at-work-back-to-the-mac/</guid><description>This post has been a bit delayed, but I want to follow up on the post I wrote last month about moving from OS X to Linux at work. I started out with a Lenovo Thinkpad X1 Carbon along with Fedora 19 and KDE. Although most things went really well, there were a few deal-breakers that sent me back to the Mac.
Just to give you an idea of my daily workflow, much of my day revolved around my calendar and email.</description></item><item><title>virt-manager won’t release the mouse when using ssh forwarding from OS X</title><link>https://major.io/2013/03/20/virt-manager-wont-release-the-mouse-when-using-ssh-forwarding-from-os-x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 05:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/03/20/virt-manager-wont-release-the-mouse-when-using-ssh-forwarding-from-os-x/</guid><description>The latest versions of virt-manager don&amp;rsquo;t release the mouse pointer when you&amp;rsquo;re doing X forwarding to a machine running OS X. This can lead to a rather frustrating user experience since your mouse pointer is totally stuck in the window. Although this didn&amp;rsquo;t affect me with CentOS 6 hosts, Fedora 18 hosts were a problem.
There&amp;rsquo;s a relatively elegant fix from btm.geek that solved it for me. On your Mac, exit X11/Xquartz and create an ~/.</description></item><item><title>Quick access to OpenPGP tasks with GPGTools in OS X</title><link>https://major.io/2013/02/08/quick-access-to-openpgp-tasks-with-gpgtools-in-os-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 19:05:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/02/08/quick-access-to-openpgp-tasks-with-gpgtools-in-os-x/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of the GPGTools suite for Mac for quite a while but I discovered some neat features when right-clicking on a file in Finder today. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit disappointing that I didn&amp;rsquo;t find these sooner!
Encrypting files is simple: just click OpenPGP: Encrypt File and a window will pop asking you which key you&amp;rsquo;d like to use for encryption. You also have the option of encrypting it with a password.</description></item><item><title>Going back to Linux as a desktop</title><link>https://major.io/2012/10/12/going-back-to-linux-as-a-desktop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 13:43:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/10/12/going-back-to-linux-as-a-desktop/</guid><description>Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been exclusively using a Mac for everything but servers since about 2008, I found myself considering a move back to Linux on the desktop after seeing how some people were using it at LinuxCon. My conversion from the iPhone to Android was rocky for a very brief period and now I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a reason to ever go back. I approached Linux in the same way and ordered a new ThinkPad shortly after returning from the conference.</description></item><item><title>Building vpnc with openssl support via MacPorts on Mac OS X</title><link>https://major.io/2012/07/31/building-vpnc-with-openssl-support-via-macports-on-mac-os-x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 04:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/07/31/building-vpnc-with-openssl-support-via-macports-on-mac-os-x/</guid><description>If you install vpnc via MacPorts on OS X, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that you have no openssl support after it&amp;rsquo;s built:
$ sudo port install vpnc ---&amp;gt; Computing dependencies for vpnc ---&amp;gt; Cleaning vpnc ---&amp;gt; Scanning binaries for linking errors: 100.0% ---&amp;gt; No broken files found. $ sudo vpnc vpnc was built without openssl: Can't do hybrid or cert mode. This will cause some problems if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to use VPN with a Cisco VPN concentrator which uses SSL VPN technology.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to OpenStack Swift with Cyberduck using swauth</title><link>https://major.io/2012/07/18/connecting-to-openstack-swift-with-cyberduck-using-swauth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 20:21:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/07/18/connecting-to-openstack-swift-with-cyberduck-using-swauth/</guid><description>Connecting to an OpenStack Swift instance that is using swauth for authentication is quite easy within Cyberduck on the Mac. Open Terminal.app and run this command:
defaults write ch.sudo.cyberduck cf.authentication.context /auth/v1.0 Keep in mind that this changes the authentication URI for all OpenStack swift connections made by Cyberduck. If this isn&amp;rsquo;t what you want, you can easily set it back to the default by running:
defaults write ch.sudo.cyberduck cf.authentication.context /v1.0 There&amp;rsquo;s more information about these settings in Cyberduck&amp;rsquo;s Swift Howto.</description></item><item><title>Handy hints for using dtrace on the Mac</title><link>https://major.io/2012/03/10/handy-hints-for-using-dtrace-on-the-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 18:49:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/03/10/handy-hints-for-using-dtrace-on-the-mac/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Linux tools which allow you to monitor things in great detail. Some of my favorites are strace, the systemtap tools, and sysstat. Finding tools similar to these on a Mac is a little more difficult.
There&amp;rsquo;s a great blog post from Brendan Gregg&amp;rsquo;s blog that covers a lot of detail around dtrace and its related tools:
http://dtrace.org/blogs/brendan/2011/10/10/top-10-dtrace-scripts-for-mac-os-x/ One of the handier tools is iosnoop.</description></item><item><title>Getting online with a CradlePoint PHS-300 and an AT&amp;T USBConnect Mercury</title><link>https://major.io/2011/12/16/getting-online-with-a-cradlepoint-phs-300-and-an-att-usbconnect-mercury/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 07:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/12/16/getting-online-with-a-cradlepoint-phs-300-and-an-att-usbconnect-mercury/</guid><description>Anyone who has used a 3G ExpressCard or USB stick knows how handy they can be when you need internet access away from home (and away from Wi-Fi). I&amp;rsquo;ve run into some situations recently where I needed to share my 3G connection with more than one device without using internet sharing on my MacBook Pro.
That led me to pick up a CradlePoint PHS-300 (discontinued by the manufacturer, but available from Amazon for about $35).</description></item><item><title>DisplayLink USB to DVI issues in OS X Lion</title><link>https://major.io/2011/11/17/displaylink-usb-to-dvi-issues-in-os-x-lion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 13:38:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/11/17/displaylink-usb-to-dvi-issues-in-os-x-lion/</guid><description>I added a DisplayLink USB to DVI adapter to my MacBook Pro a while back and it occasionally has some issues where it won&amp;rsquo;t start the display after connecting the USB cable. My logs in Console.app usually contain something like this:
The IOUSBFamily is having trouble enumerating a USB device that has been plugged in. It will keep retrying. (Port 4 of Hub at 0xfa100000) The IOUSBFamily was not able to enumerate a device.</description></item><item><title>Installing irssi via MacPorts on OS X Lion 10.7.1</title><link>https://major.io/2011/09/30/installing-irssi-via-macports-on-os-x-lion-10-7-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 13:24:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/09/30/installing-irssi-via-macports-on-os-x-lion-10-7-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve floated back and forth between graphical IRC clients and terminal-based clients for a long time. However, I was sad to see that irssi wouldn&amp;rsquo;t build via MacPorts on OS X Lion. During the build, I saw quite a few errors from the compiler:
-E, -S, -save-temps and -M options are not allowed with multiple -arch flags Sure enough, when I looked at the lines in the output, both x86_64 and i386 were passed to the compiler:</description></item><item><title>Highlight IP addresses with a double click in Firefox</title><link>https://major.io/2011/08/16/highlight-ip-addresses-with-a-double-click-in-firefox/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 12:46:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/08/16/highlight-ip-addresses-with-a-double-click-in-firefox/</guid><description>My daily work involves working with a large number of servers and one of my frustrations with Firefox is that it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to select an entire IP address with a double click with the default settings. Although it works right out of the box with Safari, you have to make a configuration adjustment in Firefox to get the same behavior.
To change the setting in Firefox, open up a new Firefox tab and go to about:config in the browser.</description></item><item><title>Sticky shift key with synergy in Fedora 12</title><link>https://major.io/2010/03/03/sticky-shift-key-with-synergy-in-fedora-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 02:44:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/03/03/sticky-shift-key-with-synergy-in-fedora-12/</guid><description>My synergy setup at work is relatively simple. I have a MacBook Pro running Snow Leopard that acts as a synergy server and a desktop running Fedora 12 as a synergy client. On the Mac, I use SynergyKM to manage the synergy server. The Fedora box uses my gdm strategy for starting synergy at the login screen and in GNOME.
I kept having an issue where the shift key would become stuck regardless of the settings I set for the client or server.</description></item><item><title>Change the escape keystrokes in screen</title><link>https://major.io/2010/01/07/change-the-escape-keystrokes-in-screen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 14:11:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/01/07/change-the-escape-keystrokes-in-screen/</guid><description>One of my favorite (and most used) applications on any Linux machine is screen. Once you fire up a screen session, you can start something and keep it running indefinitely. Even if your internet connection drops or you accidentally close your terminal window, the screen session will remain open on the remote server.
Detaching from a screen session is done by pressing CTRL-A and then d (for detach). However, when I&amp;rsquo;m on my Mac, CTRL-A and CTRL-E send my cursor to the beginning and end of lines, respectively.</description></item><item><title>Disable acceleration for Apple’s Magic Mouse</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/03/disable-acceleration-for-apples-magic-mouse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 13:55:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/03/disable-acceleration-for-apples-magic-mouse/</guid><description>Edit: After further research, I found that this fix only adjusts the speed at which your mouse moves. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything for the acceleration curve.
I recently picked up a Magic Mouse and discovered that I like almost all of its features. The biggest headache is the funky mouse acceleration curve that it applies by default. When you make small movements, they barely even register on the screen. When you make big movements and slow down a little mid-move, the pointer slows down much too rapidly.</description></item><item><title>Fix MacFusion on Snow Leopard</title><link>https://major.io/2009/08/28/fix-macfusion-on-snow-leopard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 16:21:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/08/28/fix-macfusion-on-snow-leopard/</guid><description>Running OS X 10.6.3? William Fennie found a fix on Google Groups.
First off, credit for this fix on OS X 10.6.2 goes to Geoff Watts from his two tweets.
If you&amp;rsquo;re using Snow Leopard, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that the current version of MacFusion refuses to complete a connection to a remote server. You can fix this in two steps:
First, quit MacFusion.
Second, open System Preferences and then open the MacFUSE pane.</description></item><item><title>Enabling VNC as a pseudo-KVM with VMWare Server</title><link>https://major.io/2009/03/24/enabling-vnc-as-a-pseudo-kvm-with-vmware-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 01:28:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/03/24/enabling-vnc-as-a-pseudo-kvm-with-vmware-server/</guid><description>Mac users feel a little left out when it comes to VMWare Server clients. There&amp;rsquo;s one for Windows and Linux, but Mac users are out of luck. Sure, you can VNC into a Linux box, use X forwarding, or use RDC to access a Windows box, but a real Mac client would really be helpful.
However, I stumbled upon some documentation that will allow you to VNC to a VMWare Server VM&amp;rsquo;s main screen.</description></item><item><title>Syncing an iPhone with a new Mac without hassles</title><link>https://major.io/2008/11/02/syncing-an-iphone-with-a-new-mac-without-hassles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 16:56:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/11/02/syncing-an-iphone-with-a-new-mac-without-hassles/</guid><description>I know I usually talk about Linux server related topics on this blog, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud of what I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out this morning on my Mac. As you know, the iPhone can really only fully sync with one machine, and if you want to connect it to a new Mac that you&amp;rsquo;ve purchased, you have to fully erase the iPhone and start over. (Of course, if you used the Migration Assistant to set up your new Mac, this won&amp;rsquo;t be necessary.</description></item></channel></rss>