<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lenovo on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/lenovo/</link><description>Recent content in lenovo on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/lenovo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disable Nvidia GPU on the Thinkpad T490</title><link>https://major.io/2020/01/24/disable-nvidia-gpu-thinkpad-t490/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/01/24/disable-nvidia-gpu-thinkpad-t490/</guid><description>I wrote about installing Linux on the Lenovo ThinkPad T490 last month and one of the biggest challenges was getting graphics working properly. The T490 comes with an option where you can get a discrete Nvidia MX250 GPU and it packs plenty of power in a small footprint.
It also brings along a few issues.
Awful battery life There are many times where it would be helpful to fully disable the Nvidia card to extend battery life when graphics processing is not needed.</description></item><item><title>Thinkpad T490 Fedora install tips</title><link>https://major.io/2019/12/12/thinkpad-t490-fedora-install-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/12/12/thinkpad-t490-fedora-install-tips/</guid><description>🔨 WORK IN PROGRESS! I&amp;rsquo;m still finding some additional issues and I&amp;rsquo;ll write those up here as soon as I find some solutions.
Thinkpad T490 With my 4th Gen X1 Carbon beginning to age (especially the battery), it was time for an upgrade. I now have a T490 with a 10th gen Intel CPU and a discrete NVIDIA MX250 GPU. This laptop spec was just released on Black Friday!</description></item><item><title>Review: Lenovo X1 Carbon 3rd generation and Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2015/03/30/review-lenovo-x1-carbon-3rd-generation-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/03/30/review-lenovo-x1-carbon-3rd-generation-and-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://major.io/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/ThinkPad-Carbon-X1.jpg" alt="1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a &lt;a href="../../2015/02/03/linux-support-dell-xps-13-9343-2015-model/">boatload of challenges&lt;/a> with what I thought would be my favorite Linux laptop, the &lt;a href="http://www.dell.com/us/p/xps-13-9343-laptop/pd">Dell XPS 13 9343&lt;/a>, I decided to take the plunge on a new &lt;a href="http://shop.lenovo.com/us/en/laptops/thinkpad/x-series/x1-carbon/">Lenovo X1 Carbon (3rd gen)&lt;/a>. My late-2013 MacBook Pro Retina (MacbookPro11,1) had plenty of quirks when running Linux and I was eager to find a better platform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fixing the Lenovo X1 Carbon’s washed out display</title><link>https://major.io/2013/01/08/fixing-the-lenovo-x1-carbons-washed-out-display/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 16:30:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/01/08/fixing-the-lenovo-x1-carbons-washed-out-display/</guid><description>Although the X1 Carbon has a much better looking display than the T430s, it still looked a bit washed out when I compared it to other monitors right next to it. The entire display had a weak blue tint and it was difficult to use for extended periods, especially at maximum brightness.
A quick Google search took me to a LaunchPad entry about a better ICC profile for the X1 Carbon.</description></item><item><title>Handy settings for the touchpad/clickpad in the Lenovo X1 Carbon</title><link>https://major.io/2012/12/28/handy-settings-for-the-touchpadclickpad-in-the-lenovo-x1-carbon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/12/28/handy-settings-for-the-touchpadclickpad-in-the-lenovo-x1-carbon/</guid><description>UPDATE:I&amp;rsquo;ve found a better configuration via another X1 Carbon user and there&amp;rsquo;s a new post with all the details.
The Lenovo X1 Carbon comes with a pretty useful clickpad just below the keyboard, but the default synaptics settings in X from a Fedora 17 installation aren&amp;rsquo;t the best for this particular laptop. I found some tips about managing clickpads in a Github Gist about the Samsung Series 9 and I adjusted the values for the X1.</description></item></channel></rss>