<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ruby on rails on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/ruby-on-rails/</link><description>Recent content in ruby on rails on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 17:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/ruby-on-rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing a Ruby on Rails application without using a database</title><link>https://major.io/2009/01/09/writing-a-ruby-on-rails-application-without-using-a-database/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/01/09/writing-a-ruby-on-rails-application-without-using-a-database/</guid><description>Some of you may be wondering “why would you want to use Rails without a database?” There are several situations why a database would not be needed, and I&amp;rsquo;ve run into quite a few of them. One of the specific cases was when I wanted to write a web interface for an application that only had a REST interface available to the public.
If you find yourself needing to write a Rails application without a database, just do the following:</description></item><item><title>Enabling Ruby on Rails support for a domain in Plesk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/08/11/enabling-ruby-on-rails-support-for-a-domain-in-plesk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 01:16:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/08/11/enabling-ruby-on-rails-support-for-a-domain-in-plesk/</guid><description>If you have Plesk 8.1 or later, you have support available for Ruby on Rails. Unfortunately, clicking the FastCGI checkbox in Plesk won&amp;rsquo;t get you all of the support you need (and expect). The folks over at Parallels created a relatively simple process to get Ruby on Rails working properly on your site:
Go to your domain that you want to adjust, and click Setup. Make sure the CGI and FastCGI options are enabled.</description></item></channel></rss>