<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>storage on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/storage/</link><description>Recent content in storage on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 02:12:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dual-primary DRBD with OCFS2</title><link>https://major.io/2011/02/13/dual-primary-drbd-with-ocfs2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 02:12:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/02/13/dual-primary-drbd-with-ocfs2/</guid><description>As promised in one of my previous posts about dual-primary DRBD and OCFS2, I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a step-by-step guide for Fedora. These instructions should be somewhat close to what you would use on CentOS or Red Hat Enterprise Linux. However, CentOS and Red Hat don&amp;rsquo;t provide some of the packages needed, so you will need to use other software repositories like RPMFusion or EPEL.
In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll be using two Fedora 14 instances in the Rackspace Cloud with separate public and private networks.</description></item><item><title>GlusterFS on the cheap with Rackspace’s Cloud Servers or Slicehost</title><link>https://major.io/2010/05/27/glusterfs-on-the-cheap-with-rackspaces-cloud-servers-or-slicehost/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/05/27/glusterfs-on-the-cheap-with-rackspaces-cloud-servers-or-slicehost/</guid><description>NOTE:This post is out of date and is relevant only for GlusterFS 2.x.
*High availability is certainly not a new concept, but if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that frustrates me with high availability VM setups, it&amp;rsquo;s storage. If you don&amp;rsquo;t mind going active-passive, you can set up DRBD, toss your favorite filesystem on it, and you&amp;rsquo;re all set.If you want to go active-active, or if you want multiple nodes active at the same time, you need to use a clustered filesystem like GFS2, OCFS2 or Lustre.</description></item></channel></rss>