<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rpm on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/rpm/</link><description>Recent content in rpm on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 15:24:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/rpm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Import RPM repository GPG keys from other keyservers temporarily</title><link>https://major.io/2017/09/20/import-rpm-repository-keys-from-other-keyservers-temporarily/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 15:24:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/09/20/import-rpm-repository-keys-from-other-keyservers-temporarily/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through some patches to OpenStack-Ansible lately to optimize how we configure yum repositories in our deployments. During that work, I ran into some issues where pgp.mit.edu was returning 500 errors for some requests to retrieve GPG keys.
Ansible was returning this error:
curl: (22) The requested URL returned error: 502 Proxy Error error: http://pgp.mit.edu:11371/pks/lookup?op=get&amp;amp;search=0x61E8806C: import read failed(2) How does the rpm command know which keyserver to use? Let&amp;rsquo;s use the --showrc argument to show how it is configured:</description></item><item><title>CoreOS vs. Project Atomic: A Review</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/13/coreos-vs-project-atomic-a-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 03:57:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/13/coreos-vs-project-atomic-a-review/</guid><description>This post hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in quite some time.Many of these comparisons still hold true but some don&amp;rsquo;t. Updating this post is on my list of to-do&amp;rsquo;s. - MH 2015-04-25
You&amp;rsquo;ve probably been living under a rock if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about Docker. It simplifies the deployment and management of Linux containers better than anything else I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far. Many ecosystems are growing with Docker at the core and two of the most popular hosting platforms for Docker are CoreOS and Project Atomic.</description></item><item><title>virt-manager: ‘NoneType’ object has no attribute ‘cpus’</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/06/virt-manager-nonetype-object-has-no-attribute-cpus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 18:44:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/06/virt-manager-nonetype-object-has-no-attribute-cpus/</guid><description>After upgrading my Fedora 20 Xen hypervisor to virt-manager 1.0.0, I noticed that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t open the console or VM details for any of my guests. Running virt-manager --debug gave me the following traceback:
Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;quot;/usr/share/virt-manager/virtManager/engine.py&amp;quot;, line 803, in _show_vm_helper details = self._get_details_dialog(uri, uuid) File &amp;quot;/usr/share/virt-manager/virtManager/engine.py&amp;quot;, line 760, in _get_details_dialog obj = vmmDetails(con.get_vm(uuid)) File &amp;quot;/usr/share/virt-manager/virtManager/details.py&amp;quot;, line 530, in __init__ self.init_details() File &amp;quot;/usr/share/virt-manager/virtManager/details.py&amp;quot;, line 990, in init_details for name in [c.</description></item><item><title>Keeping bwm-ng 0.6 functional on Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/19/keeping-bwm-ng-0-6-functional-on-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/19/keeping-bwm-ng-0-6-functional-on-fedora-19/</guid><description>If you run bwm-ng and you&amp;rsquo;ve run a yum upgrade lately on Fedora 19, you have probably seen this:
---&amp;gt; Package libstatgrab.x86_64 0:0.17-4.fc19 will be updated --&amp;gt; Processing Dependency: libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) for package: bwm-ng-0.6-10.fc19.x86_64 --&amp;gt; Finished Dependency Resolution Error: Package: bwm-ng-0.6-10.fc19.x86_64 (@fedora) Requires: libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) Removing: libstatgrab-0.17-4.fc19.x86_64 (@fedora) libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) Updated By: libstatgrab-0.90-1.fc19.x86_64 (updates) ~libstatgrab.so.9()(64bit) You could try using --skip-broken to work around the problem You could try running: rpm -Va --nofiles --nodigest The error message mentions that libstatgrab needs to be updated to version 0.</description></item><item><title>Moving from OS X to Linux: Day One</title><link>https://major.io/2013/08/26/moving-from-os-x-to-linux-day-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 03:05:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/08/26/moving-from-os-x-to-linux-day-one/</guid><description>The thought of using Linux as a manager in a highly Windows- and Mac-centric corporate environment isn&amp;rsquo;t something to be taken lightly. Integrating with Active Directory, wrangling email with Microsoft Exchange, and taming quirky Microsoft office documents can be a challenge even with a well-equipped Mac. I decided to make a change after using a Mac at Rackspace for six years.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get one thing straight: I&amp;rsquo;m not a Windows or Mac basher.</description></item><item><title>drbd 8.4.3 package on the way for Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/08/02/drbd-8-4-3-package-on-the-way-for-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/08/02/drbd-8-4-3-package-on-the-way-for-fedora-19/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a drbd-8.4.3-1 package waiting in the testing repository for Fedora 19. The DRBD kernel module for kernel 3.10 is up to 8.4.3 but the client tools within Fedora 19 (currently at 8.4.2) should work fine. The API versions are the same for both the kernel modules and user tools.
If you&amp;rsquo;re eager to see a changelog between 8.4.2 and 8.4.3, check DRBD&amp;rsquo;s git repository. The majority of the changes are within the kernel module itself.</description></item><item><title>A humble farewell to Seth Vidal</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</guid><description>I was shocked to see Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s email today about Seth Vidal&amp;rsquo;s passing. He was the victim of a hit and run accident while he was cycling last night. The suspect has turned himself in as of tonight.
I first met Seth at FUDCon Tempe back in 2011. We had talked off and on via email and IRC about cloud-related topics. He was interested in how we assembled our cloud offering at Rackspace and I was eager to talk to him about building cloud images and handling mirrors.</description></item><item><title>Automate CentOS 6 deployments with CIS Security Benchmarks already applied</title><link>https://major.io/2013/04/26/automate-centos-6-deployments-with-cis-security-benchmarks-already-applied/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 14:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/04/26/automate-centos-6-deployments-with-cis-security-benchmarks-already-applied/</guid><description>A coworker heard me grumbling about Linux system administration standards and recommended that I review the CIS Security Benchmarks. After downloading the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 security benchmark PDF, I quickly started to see the value of the document. Some of the standards were the installation defaults, some were often forgotten settings, and some were completely brand new to me.
Automating the standards can be a little treacherous simply due to the number of things to adjust and check.</description></item><item><title>New Fedora and EPEL package: httpry</title><link>https://major.io/2012/03/14/new-fedora-and-epel-package-httpry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/03/14/new-fedora-and-epel-package-httpry/</guid><description>A fellow Racker showed me httpry about five years ago and I&amp;rsquo;ve had in my toolbox as a handy way to watch HTTP traffic. I&amp;rsquo;d used some crazy tcpdump arguments and some bash one-liners to pull out the information I needed but I never could get the live look that I really wanted.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what httpry&amp;rsquo;s output looks like on a busy site like icanhazip.com:
GET icanhazip.</description></item><item><title>Looking back at the long road to becoming a Red Hat Certified Architect</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/13/looking-back-at-the-long-road-to-becoming-a-red-hat-certified-architect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/13/looking-back-at-the-long-road-to-becoming-a-red-hat-certified-architect/</guid><description>The grades came back last Friday and I&amp;rsquo;ve passed the last exam in the requirements to become a Red Hat Certified Architect (RHCA). I was fortunate enough to be part of Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s RHCA pilot program and we took our first exam back at the end of 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a good feeling to be finished and I&amp;rsquo;m definitely ready to give back some knowledge to the readers of this blog.</description></item><item><title>Locate RPM packages which contain a certain file</title><link>https://major.io/2010/12/08/locate-rpm-packages-which-contain-a-certain-file/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/12/08/locate-rpm-packages-which-contain-a-certain-file/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy remembering which RPM packages contain certain files. If I asked you which files you&amp;rsquo;d find in packages like postfix-2.7.1-1.fc14 and bash-4.1.7-3.fc14, you would be able to name some obvious executables. However, would you be able to do the same if I mentioned a package like util-linux-ng-2.18-4.6.fc14? If the RPM is already installed, you can quickly use rpm -ql to list the files within it.
However, what if the RPM isn&amp;rsquo;t installed already?</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Fedora 13 to Fedora 14 on Slicehost and Rackspace Cloud Servers</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/03/upgrading-fedora-13-to-fedora-14-on-slicehost-and-rackspace-cloud-servers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 20:02:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/03/upgrading-fedora-13-to-fedora-14-on-slicehost-and-rackspace-cloud-servers/</guid><description>On most systems, using Fedora&amp;rsquo;s preupgrade package is the most reliable way to update to the next Fedora release. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case with Slicehost and Rackspace Cloud Servers.
Here are the steps for an upgrade from Fedora 13 to Fedora 14 via yum:
yum -y upgrade wget http://mirror.rackspace.com/fedora/releases/14/Fedora/x86_64/os/Packages/fedora-release-14-1.noarch.rpm rpm -Uvh fedora-release-14-1.noarch.rpm yum -y install yum yum -y upgrade If you happen to be upgrading a 32-bit instance on Slicehost, simply replace x86_64 with i386 in the url shown above.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Fedora 11 to 12 using yum</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/07/upgrading-fedora-11-to-12-using-yum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 02:28:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/07/upgrading-fedora-11-to-12-using-yum/</guid><description>As with the Fedora 10 to 11 upgrade, you can upgrade Fedora 11 to Fedora 12 using yum. I find this to be the easiest and most reliable way to upgrade a Fedora installation whether you use it as a server or desktop.
To reduce the total data downloaded, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend installing the yum-presto package first. It downloads delta RPM&amp;rsquo;s and builds them on the fly, which allows you to upgrade packages without having to download the entire RPM&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading from Fedora 10 (Cambridge) to Fedora 11 (Leonidas)</title><link>https://major.io/2009/06/11/upgrading-from-fedora-10-cambridge-to-fedora-11-leonidas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 17:48:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/06/11/upgrading-from-fedora-10-cambridge-to-fedora-11-leonidas/</guid><description>There are two main ways to upgrade Fedora 10 (Cambridge) to Fedora 11 (Leonidas):
» What the Fedora developers suggest:
Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re doing this on a Fedora desktop, you can use preupgrade (rather than preupgrade-cli) to upgrade with a GUI.
» The method I prefer (and it works properly on Slicehost):
At this point, you would normally just start upgrading packages, but the Fedora developers threw us a curveball.</description></item><item><title>Compare the RPM packages installed on two different servers</title><link>https://major.io/2009/03/10/compare-the-rpm-packages-installed-on-two-different-servers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 23:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/03/10/compare-the-rpm-packages-installed-on-two-different-servers/</guid><description>Setting up new servers can be a pain if you&amp;rsquo;re not able to clone them from a server that is known to be working. Many VPS providers, like Slicehost, allow you to clone a system to a new system. Without that option, you can pull a list of RPM&amp;rsquo;s without their version number for a fairly quick and basic comparison.
First, pull a list of RPM package by name only:</description></item><item><title>Installing Microsoft’s TrueType fonts on Linux servers</title><link>https://major.io/2008/10/23/installing-microsofts-truetype-fonts-on-linux-servers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:31:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/10/23/installing-microsofts-truetype-fonts-on-linux-servers/</guid><description>Although the idea of putting something from Microsoft on a Linux box might sound awful at first, you may find a reason to use Microsoft TrueType fonts on a Linux server. If you&amp;rsquo;re using GD to render an image, these fonts may come in handy.
If you have an RPM-based linux distribution, you can use a spec file that is available on SourceForge. You can follow the instructions on the project&amp;rsquo;s page, or you can follow these abbreviated instructions here:</description></item><item><title>rpmdb: Lock table is out of available locker entries</title><link>https://major.io/2007/05/27/rpmdb-lock-table-is-out-of-available-locker-entries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 16:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/05/27/rpmdb-lock-table-is-out-of-available-locker-entries/</guid><description>If up2date throws some horrible Python errors and rpm says “rpmdb: Lock table is out of available locker entries”, you can restore your system to normality with the following:
The errors:
rpmdb: Lock table is out of available locker entries error: db4 error(22) from db-&amp;gt;close: Invalid argument error: cannot open Packages index using db3 - Cannot allocate memory (12) error: cannot open Packages database in /var/lib/rpm Make a backup of /var/lib/rpm in case you break something:</description></item></channel></rss>