<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>keyboard on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/keyboard/</link><description>Recent content in keyboard on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 05:33:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/keyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom keyboard shortcuts for Evolution in GNOME</title><link>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 05:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Thunderbird for years, but it lacks features in some critical areas. For example, I need Microsoft Exchange and Google Apps connectivity for my mail and contacts, but Thunderbird needs some extensions to make that connectivity easier. There are some great extensions available, but they lack polish since they&amp;rsquo;re not part of the core product.
My muscle memory for keyboard shortcuts in Thunderbird left me fumbling in Evolution.</description></item><item><title>Play/pause button stopped working in OS X Mavericks</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/30/playpause-button-stopped-working-in-os-x-mavericks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 14:31:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/30/playpause-button-stopped-working-in-os-x-mavericks/</guid><description>My play/pause button mysteriously stopped working in iTunes and VLC mysteriously this week on my laptop. It affected the previous track and next track buttons as well. It turns out that my Google Music extension in Chrome stole the keyboard bindings after the extension updated this week.
If your buttons stopped working as well, follow these steps to check your keyboard shortcuts in Chrome:
Choose Preferences in the Chrome menu in the menu bar Click Extensions in the left sidebar Scroll all the way to the bottom of the page Click Keyboard Shortcuts Look at the key bindings in the Google Play Music section Your shortcuts might look like the ones shown here in an Apple support forum.</description></item><item><title>Sticky shift key with synergy in Fedora 12</title><link>https://major.io/2010/03/03/sticky-shift-key-with-synergy-in-fedora-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 02:44:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/03/03/sticky-shift-key-with-synergy-in-fedora-12/</guid><description>My synergy setup at work is relatively simple. I have a MacBook Pro running Snow Leopard that acts as a synergy server and a desktop running Fedora 12 as a synergy client. On the Mac, I use SynergyKM to manage the synergy server. The Fedora box uses my gdm strategy for starting synergy at the login screen and in GNOME.
I kept having an issue where the shift key would become stuck regardless of the settings I set for the client or server.</description></item></channel></rss>