<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ftp on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/ftp/</link><description>Recent content in ftp on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 16:21:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/ftp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fix MacFusion on Snow Leopard</title><link>https://major.io/2009/08/28/fix-macfusion-on-snow-leopard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 16:21:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/08/28/fix-macfusion-on-snow-leopard/</guid><description>Running OS X 10.6.3? William Fennie found a fix on Google Groups.
First off, credit for this fix on OS X 10.6.2 goes to Geoff Watts from his two tweets.
If you&amp;rsquo;re using Snow Leopard, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that the current version of MacFusion refuses to complete a connection to a remote server. You can fix this in two steps:
First, quit MacFusion.
Second, open System Preferences and then open the MacFUSE pane.</description></item><item><title>Adding SSL encryption to vsftpd</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/26/adding-ssl-encryption-to-vsftpd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 18:21:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/26/adding-ssl-encryption-to-vsftpd/</guid><description>There may be some situations where you want to encrypt FTP traffic with SSL certificates rather than using SFTP with SSH. Using vsftpd with SSL encryption is quite easy, and here&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;s done:
First, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make a new self-signed SSL certificate (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a key and certificate available already):
Once you have the key and certificate made, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to concatenate them into a PEM file:</description></item><item><title>500 OOPS error from vsftpd</title><link>https://major.io/2007/06/14/500-oops-error-from-vsftpd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 23:14:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/06/14/500-oops-error-from-vsftpd/</guid><description>If you find yourself with the ever-so-peculiar 500 OOPS error from vsftpd when you attempt to login over SSH, there could be a few different things at play. Generally, this is the type of error you will get:
500 OOPS: cannot change directory:/home/someuser 500 OOPS: child died You can search for a solution in this order:
Home Directory
Does the user&amp;rsquo;s home directory even exist? Check /etc/passwd for the current home directory for the user and see what&amp;rsquo;s set:</description></item><item><title>Show hidden dot files in proftpd</title><link>https://major.io/2007/05/16/show-hidden-dot-files-in-proftpd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 01:46:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/05/16/show-hidden-dot-files-in-proftpd/</guid><description>If you can&amp;rsquo;t see hidden files in proftpd (the files beginning with a dot, like .htaccess), you can enable the option in your client. However, you can force the files to be displayed in almost all clients with a server wide variable in your proftpd.conf:
ListOptions -a
Make sure to restart proftpd afterwards and re-connect to the FTP server to see the changes.</description></item><item><title>Add SSL/TLS support to proftpd</title><link>https://major.io/2007/05/16/add-ssltls-support-to-proftpd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 01:45:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/05/16/add-ssltls-support-to-proftpd/</guid><description>To enable SSL/TLS support in proftpd, add the following to the proftpd.conf file:
&amp;lt;IfModule mod_tls.c&amp;gt; TLSEngine on TLSLog /var/ftpd/tls.log TLSRequired off TLSRSACertificateFile /usr/share/ssl/certs/server.crt TLSRSACertificateKeyFile /usr/share/ssl/private/server.key TLSCACertificateFile /usr/share/ssl/certs/cacert.crt TLSVerifyClient off TLSRenegotiate required off &amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt; To require SSL/TLS on all connections, change TLSRequired to on. Of course, replace the certificate, key, and CA certificate (if applicable) to the correct files on your system.
Once you&amp;rsquo;re all done, close your FTP connection and make a new one.</description></item><item><title>Adding chrooted FTP users outside of Plesk</title><link>https://major.io/2007/04/27/adding-chrooted-ftp-users-outside-of-plesk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 15:51:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/04/27/adding-chrooted-ftp-users-outside-of-plesk/</guid><description>To add a chrooted FTP user outside of Plesk properly, you need to:
Create the user with the home directory as the root of what they can access Give the user a password Make their primary group psacln Add them to the psaserv group as well # useradd username -d /var/www/html/website/slideshow/ # echo &amp;quot;password&amp;quot; | passwd username --stdin Changing password for user username. passwd: all authentication tokens updated successfully.</description></item><item><title>ProFTPD shows incorrect GMT time with Plesk</title><link>https://major.io/2007/02/21/gmt-ftp-timestamps-in-plesk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 19:13:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/02/21/gmt-ftp-timestamps-in-plesk/</guid><description>A really really strange issue randomly appears with ProFTPD and Plesk occasionally. On the filesystem, a file will have a correct creation/modification date, but then when you view it over FTP, it&amp;rsquo;s always off by the amount of hours you differ from GMT.
For example, if the server is on Central Time, all of the files will seem to be created 6 hours after they were really created. The filesystem will show something like 10AM, but the FTP client will say 4PM.</description></item><item><title>Enabling SSL in ProFTPD</title><link>https://major.io/2007/02/08/enabling-ssl-in-proftpd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 23:28:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/02/08/enabling-ssl-in-proftpd/</guid><description>If you need to enable SSL in ProFTPD, try this out:
&amp;lt;IfModule mod_tls.c&amp;gt; TLSEngine on TLSRequired off TLSRSACertificateFile /etc/httpd/conf/ssl.crt/server.crt TLSRSACertificateKeyFile /etc/httpd/conf/ssl.key/server.key TLSVerifyClient off &amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Group Editing With FTP</title><link>https://major.io/2006/12/26/group-editing-with-vsftpd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 03:44:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2006/12/26/group-editing-with-vsftpd/</guid><description>So you have multiple users that need to read and write to certain files on the filesystem? This can be done with vsftpd or proftpd quite easily. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have users called ann, bill and carl and they need to manage files in /var/www/html. Here&amp;rsquo;s the steps:
For vsftpd, change the umask for files created by FTP users. Open the vsftpd.conf file and edit the following:
local_umask = 077 &amp;lt;-- old local_umask = 022 &amp;lt;-- new For proftpd, change the umask for files created by FTP users.</description></item></channel></rss>