<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dell on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/dell/</link><description>Recent content in dell on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 20:53:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/dell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updating Dell PowerEdge BIOS from Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/18/updating-dell-poweredge-bios-from-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 20:53:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/18/updating-dell-poweredge-bios-from-linux/</guid><description>Updating Dell PowerEdge firmware from Linux is quite easy, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t documented very well. I ended up with a set of PowerEdge R710&amp;rsquo;s at work for a lab environment and the BIOS versions were different on each server.
Downloading the latest firmware Start by heading over to Dell&amp;rsquo;s support site and enter your system&amp;rsquo;s service tag. You can use lshw to find your service tag:
# lshw | head lab05 description: Rack Mount Chassis product: PowerEdge R710 () vendor: Dell Inc.</description></item><item><title>Linux support for the Dell XPS 13 9343 (2015 model)</title><link>https://major.io/2015/02/03/linux-support-dell-xps-13-9343-2015-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 15:23:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/02/03/linux-support-dell-xps-13-9343-2015-model/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;M ALL DONE:I&amp;rsquo;m not working on Linux compatibility for the XPS 13 any longer. I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a Lenovo X1 Carbon (3rd gen) and that&amp;rsquo;s my preferred laptop. More on this change later.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a good laptop to run Linux for a while now and my new Dell XPS 13 9343 has arrived. It was released at CES in 2015 and it received quite a lot of attention for packing a large amount of pixels into a very small laptop frame with excellent battery life.</description></item><item><title>Getting Dell’s racadm working in Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/20/getting-dells-racadm-working-in-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 14:39:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/20/getting-dells-racadm-working-in-fedora-20/</guid><description>Dell provides the racadm software on Linux that allows you to manage Dell hardware from a Linux system. Getting it installed on a very modern distribution like Fedora 20 isn&amp;rsquo;t supported, but here are some steps that might help you along the way:
First off, go to Dell&amp;rsquo;s site and review the racadm download instructions. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend following the Remote RACADM instructions so that you can manage multiple systems from your Fedora installation.</description></item></channel></rss>