<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gnome on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/gnome/</link><description>Recent content in gnome on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 18:42:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/gnome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ICC color profile for Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon 4th generation</title><link>https://major.io/2017/01/11/icc-color-profile-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon-4th-generation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 18:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/01/11/icc-color-profile-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon-4th-generation/</guid><description>My new ThinkPad arrived this week and it is working well! The Fedora 25 installation was easy and all of the hardware was recognized immediately.
However, there was a downside. The display looked washed out and had a strange tint. It seemed to be more pale than the previous ThinkPad. The default ICC profile in GNOME didn&amp;rsquo;t help much.
There&amp;rsquo;s a helpful review over at NotebookCheck that has a link to an ICC profile generated from a 4th generation ThinkPad X1 Carbon.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a telnet handler for OpenStack Zuul CI jobs in GNOME 3</title><link>https://major.io/2016/07/22/setting-up-a-telnet-handler-in-gnome-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 19:44:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/07/22/setting-up-a-telnet-handler-in-gnome-3/</guid><description>The OpenStack Zuul system has gone through some big changes recently, and one of those changes is around how you monitor a running CI job. I work on OpenStack-Ansible quite often, and the gate jobs can take almost an hour to complete at times. It can be helpful to watch the output of a Zuul job to catch a problem or follow a breakpoint.
New Zuul In the previous version of Zuul, you could access the Jenkins server that was running the CI job and monitor its progress right in your browser.</description></item><item><title>Bring back two and three finger taps in Fedora 24</title><link>https://major.io/2016/07/05/bring-back-two-three-finger-taps-fedora-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 04:54:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/07/05/bring-back-two-three-finger-taps-fedora-24/</guid><description>Most of the recent Fedora upgrades have been quite smooth. There were definitely some rough spots back in Fedora 15 and Fedora 17 with the /bin migration and the switch to systemd. The upgrade from Fedora 23 to Fedora 24 has been really easy except for one minor quirk: my two and three finger taps don&amp;rsquo;t seem to work on the touchpad.
I use a Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon (3rd gen) and it has a clickpad along with physical buttons across the top.</description></item><item><title>Mouse cursor disappears in GNOME 3</title><link>https://major.io/2016/03/11/mouse-cursor-disappears-gnome-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 15:36:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/03/11/mouse-cursor-disappears-gnome-3/</guid><description>UPDATE: The fixed version of mutter is now in the Fedora updates repository. You should be able to update the package with dnf:
dnf -y upgrade mutter GNOME 3 has been rock solid for the last few months but something cropped up this week that derailed me for a short while. Whenever I moved my mouse cursor to the top bar (where the clock and status icons reside), the mouse cursor disappeared.</description></item><item><title>Custom keyboard shortcuts for Evolution in GNOME</title><link>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 05:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Thunderbird for years, but it lacks features in some critical areas. For example, I need Microsoft Exchange and Google Apps connectivity for my mail and contacts, but Thunderbird needs some extensions to make that connectivity easier. There are some great extensions available, but they lack polish since they&amp;rsquo;re not part of the core product.
My muscle memory for keyboard shortcuts in Thunderbird left me fumbling in Evolution.</description></item><item><title>Allow new windows to steal focus in GNOME 3</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/06/allow-new-windows-to-steal-focus-in-gnome-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 12:36:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/06/allow-new-windows-to-steal-focus-in-gnome-3/</guid><description>GNOME 3 generally works well for me but it has some quirks. One of those quirks is that new windows don&amp;rsquo;t actually pop up on the screen with focus as they do in Windows and OS X. When opening a new window, you get a “[Windowname] is ready” notification:
My preference is for new windows to pop in front and steal focus. I can see why that&amp;rsquo;s not the default since it might cause you to type something in another window where you weren&amp;rsquo;t expecting to.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 22 and rotating GNOME wallpaper with systemd timers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/23/fedora-22-and-rotating-gnome-wallpaper-with-systemd-timers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 17:25:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/23/fedora-22-and-rotating-gnome-wallpaper-with-systemd-timers/</guid><description>My older post about rotating GNOME&amp;rsquo;s wallpaper with systemd timers doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work in Fedora 22. The DISPLAY=:0 environment variable isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient to allow systemd to use gsettings.
Instead, the script run by the systemd timer must know a little bit more about dbus. More specifically, the script needs to know the address of the dbus session so it can communicate on the bus. That&amp;rsquo;s normally kept within the DBUS_SESSION_BUS_ADDRESS environment variable.</description></item><item><title>Chrome 43 stuck in HiDPI mode</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/10/chrome-43-stuck-in-hidpi-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 12:36:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/10/chrome-43-stuck-in-hidpi-mode/</guid><description>I ran some package updates last night and ended up with a new version of Google Chrome from the stable branch. After restarting Chrome, everything in the interface was huge. The icons in the bookmark bar, the text, the padding - all of it looked enormous.
After a little searching, I found a helpful line in the ArchLinux HiDPI documentation:
Full HiDPI support in Chrome is now available in the main branch google-chromeAUR as of version 43.</description></item><item><title>Share a wireless connection via ethernet in GNOME 3.14</title><link>https://major.io/2015/03/29/share-a-wireless-connection-via-ethernet-in-gnome-3-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 02:31:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/03/29/share-a-wireless-connection-via-ethernet-in-gnome-3-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are some situations where you want to do the opposite of creating a wireless hotspot and you want to share a wireless connection to an ethernet connection. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re at a hotel that offers only WiFi internet access, you could share that connection to an ethernet switch and plug in more devices. Also, you could get online with your wireless connection and create a small NAT network to test a network device without mangling your home network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using play/pause buttons in Chrome with GNOME 3</title><link>https://major.io/2015/02/20/using-playpause-buttons-in-chrome-with-gnome-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 14:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/02/20/using-playpause-buttons-in-chrome-with-gnome-3/</guid><description>I wrote a post last summer about preventing Chrome from stealing the media buttons (like play, pause, previous track and next track) from OS X. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m using Linux regularly and I fell in love with Google Play Music All Access, I found that GNOME was stealing the media keys from Chrome.
The fix is quite simple. Press the SUPER key (Windows key or Mac Command key), type settings, and press enter.</description></item><item><title>Rotate GNOME 3’s wallpaper with systemd user units and timers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/02/11/rotate-gnome-3s-wallpaper-systemd-user-units-timers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 14:23:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/02/11/rotate-gnome-3s-wallpaper-systemd-user-units-timers/</guid><description>NOTE: This works in Fedora 21, but not in Fedora 22. Review this post for the fixes.
GNOME 3 has improved by leaps and bounds since its original release and it&amp;rsquo;s my daily driver window manager on my Linux laptop. Even with all of these improvements, there&amp;rsquo;s still no built-in way to rotate wallpaper (that I&amp;rsquo;ve found).
There are some extensions, like BackSlide, that enable background rotation on a time interval.</description></item></channel></rss>