<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog Posts on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/categories/blog-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/categories/blog-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitor a UPS with a Raspberry Pi Zero W</title><link>https://major.io/2021/03/15/monitor-ups-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/03/15/monitor-ups-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w/</guid><description>After the recent snow apocalypse that swept through Texas followed by widespread power crisis, I realized that my UPS monitoring strategy needed improvement. One had batteries that were near death and my other two had loads that were not well balanced.
I have a few CyberPower UPS units and an old APC UPS. Although CyberPower does offer relatively expensive monitoring cards that puts the UPS on the local network, none of them worked with my 1350/1500VA units.</description></item><item><title>Defending losing options trades</title><link>https://major.io/2021/02/10/defending-losing-options-trades/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/02/10/defending-losing-options-trades/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading. If you are new to options trading, you may want to start with some of my earlier posts.
You did your research. You waited for a good time to sell a put option. You received a decent premium for your option trade. Now your trade has turned into a loss. What can you do now?</description></item><item><title>Which stock broker should you use?</title><link>https://major.io/2021/01/24/which-stock-broker-should-you-use/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/01/24/which-stock-broker-should-you-use/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading. If you are new to options trading, you may want to start with some of my earlier posts.
One of my sports coaches in high school used to say: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the tool, it&amp;rsquo;s the fool.&amp;rdquo; This was his reminder that when something goes wrong in the game, it&amp;rsquo;s usually the fault of the person and not the equipment.</description></item><item><title>Choosing options to sell</title><link>https://major.io/2021/01/23/choosing-options-to-sell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/01/23/choosing-options-to-sell/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading. If you are new to options trading, you may want to start with some of my earlier posts.
You know your terminology, you know your max loss, and you are ready to start. Now you&amp;rsquo;re faced with the difficult question all new options traders face:
How do I choose which option to sell?
At first, you learn to look for the trades that are right for you.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from selling puts</title><link>https://major.io/2021/01/04/lessons-learned-from-selling-puts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/01/04/lessons-learned-from-selling-puts/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading on the blog. If you are confused on terminology, go back and start with the first post and the series and work your way to this one.
My options trading journey started back in September 2020 and I learned a lot in a short amount of time. This post covers some of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>Know your max loss</title><link>https://major.io/2020/12/09/know-your-max-loss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/12/09/know-your-max-loss/</guid><description>This is the third post in a series of posts on options trading. You can read this one out of order since it applies to almost everything you do in the stock market, including buying shares of stock.
What is &amp;ldquo;max loss&amp;rdquo; The maximum loss on a trade is the worst outcome possible. Knowing this number helps you protect your account from huge losses and avoids terrible situations such as margin calls.</description></item><item><title>The Dark Side: Selling Options</title><link>https://major.io/2020/12/07/the-dark-side-selling-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/12/07/the-dark-side-selling-options/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a series of posts on options trading and if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read yesterdays post, Options trading introduction, you should start there first.
Recap: Buying calls and puts Just to recap the introductory post:
Buying a call gives you the right to buy a stock at a certain strike price Buying a put gives you the right to sell a stock at a certain strike price Buying calls is a great way to capture gains from a stock that is trending upwards an buying puts provides an insurance policy in case your stock drops.</description></item><item><title>Options trading introduction</title><link>https://major.io/2020/12/06/options-trading-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/12/06/options-trading-introduction/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always on the hunt for new things to learn and one of my newer interests is around trading options on the stock market. Much like technology, it becomes much easier to understand when you peel back the layers of archaic terminology, snake oil salespeople, and debunked data.
Stay tuned for additional posts that go into greater detail. This post covers the basics about what an option is (and is not) and how you can compare it to other investment vehicles, like stocks.</description></item><item><title>Build AWS images with Image Builder</title><link>https://major.io/2020/06/19/build-aws-images-with-imagebuilder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/06/19/build-aws-images-with-imagebuilder/</guid><description>The AMIs provided by most Linux distributions in AWS work well for most use cases. However, there are those times when you need a customized image to support a certain configuration or to speed up CI processes.
You can get a customized image via a few methods:
Build from an existing AMI, customize it, and snapshot it. Use an automated tool, such as Packer, to automate #1. Build your own image locally in KVM, VMware, or Virtualbox and upload the image into S3, import it into an EC2, and create an AMI from the snapshot.</description></item><item><title>My experience with keto so far</title><link>https://major.io/2020/06/11/my-experience-with-keto-so-far/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/06/11/my-experience-with-keto-so-far/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about some of my experiences with altering my diet on Twitter and many people have asked about my experiences with keto so far. Note that I don&amp;rsquo;t call it &amp;ldquo;the keto diet&amp;rdquo; because it&amp;rsquo;s much more than a diet: it&amp;rsquo;s a lifestyle change. Sure, you alter what you eat, but you begin to think differently about how you fuel your body.
Before we start, I&amp;rsquo;d like to note that:</description></item><item><title>Make diacritics easy in Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2020/02/13/make-diacritics-easy-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/02/13/make-diacritics-easy-in-linux/</guid><description>Diacritics are all of the small things that are added on, above, or below certain characters in various languages. Some examples include tildes (ñ), accents (á), or other marks (š). These marks are little hints that help you know how to pronounce a word properly (and they sometimes change the definition of a word entirely).
They are often skipped by non-native language speakers, and sometimes even by native speakers, but I have done my best to make a habit of including them when I can.</description></item><item><title>My Travel Guide to Brno</title><link>https://major.io/2020/01/30/my-travel-guide-to-brno/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/01/30/my-travel-guide-to-brno/</guid><description>Come to the Czech Republic and discover the beautiful city of Brno. I just wrapped up my third visit to the city and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to come back! The city is full of history, culture, and delicious food.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my travel guide to Brno!
Getting to Brno Brno has an airport, but the flights are limited and sometimes expensive. Some coworkers have found good deals on these flights (especially via Ryanair from London&amp;rsquo;s Stansted Airport), but I prefer the train.</description></item><item><title>Disable Nvidia GPU on the Thinkpad T490</title><link>https://major.io/2020/01/24/disable-nvidia-gpu-thinkpad-t490/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/01/24/disable-nvidia-gpu-thinkpad-t490/</guid><description>I wrote about installing Linux on the Lenovo ThinkPad T490 last month and one of the biggest challenges was getting graphics working properly. The T490 comes with an option where you can get a discrete Nvidia MX250 GPU and it packs plenty of power in a small footprint.
It also brings along a few issues.
Awful battery life There are many times where it would be helpful to fully disable the Nvidia card to extend battery life when graphics processing is not needed.</description></item><item><title>Bring Back Fedora's Beefy Miracle boot splash</title><link>https://major.io/2019/12/16/bring-back-fedora-beefy-miracle-boot-splash.md/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/12/16/bring-back-fedora-beefy-miracle-boot-splash.md/</guid><description>Way back in 2012 when Fedora releases had names, there was one release that many of us in the Fedora community will never forget. Fedora 17&amp;rsquo;s code name was &amp;ldquo;Beefy Miracle&amp;rdquo; and it caused plenty of giggles and lots of consternation (especially in vegetarian and vegan circles).
No matter how you feel about the code name, the mascot was really good:
Major and the beefy miracle in 2012</description></item><item><title>Thinkpad T490 Fedora install tips</title><link>https://major.io/2019/12/12/thinkpad-t490-fedora-install-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/12/12/thinkpad-t490-fedora-install-tips/</guid><description>🔨 WORK IN PROGRESS! I&amp;rsquo;m still finding some additional issues and I&amp;rsquo;ll write those up here as soon as I find some solutions.
Thinkpad T490 With my 4th Gen X1 Carbon beginning to age (especially the battery), it was time for an upgrade. I now have a T490 with a 10th gen Intel CPU and a discrete NVIDIA MX250 GPU. This laptop spec was just released on Black Friday!</description></item><item><title>Monitoring OpenShift cron jobs</title><link>https://major.io/2019/11/18/monitoring-openshift-cron-jobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/11/18/monitoring-openshift-cron-jobs/</guid><description>Moving applications into an entirely containerized deployment, such as OpenShift or Kubernetes, requires care and attention. One aspect of both that is often overlooked is scheduled jobs, or cron jobs. ⏰
Cron jobs in OpenShift allow you to run certain containers on a regular basis and execute certain applications or scripts in those containers. You can use them to trigger GitLab CI pipelines, run certain housekeeping tasks in web applications, or run backups.</description></item><item><title>Monitor CyberPower UPS wattage</title><link>https://major.io/2019/11/08/monitor-cyberpower-ups-wattage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/11/08/monitor-cyberpower-ups-wattage/</guid><description>I have a CyberPower CP1350AVRLCD under my desk at home and I use it to run my computer, monitors, speakers, and a lamp. My new computer is a little more power hungry than my old one since I just moved to to a Ryzen 3700x and Nvidia GeForce 2060 and I like to keep tabs on how much energy it is consuming.
Some power supplies offer a monitoring interface where you can watch your power consumption in real time, but I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to spend that much money.</description></item><item><title>Install Chromium with VAAPI on Fedora 30</title><link>https://major.io/2019/10/20/install-chromium-with-vaapi-on-fedora-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/10/20/install-chromium-with-vaapi-on-fedora-30/</guid><description>UPDATE: The chromium-vaapi package is now chromium-freeworld. This post was updated on 2019-11-06 to include the change. See the end of the post for the update steps.
If you use a web browser to watch videos on a laptop, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably noticed that some videos play without much impact on the battery. Other videos cause the fans to spin wildly and your battery life plummets.
Intel designed a specification called VA API, often called VAAPI (without the space), and it offers up device drivers to applications running on your system.</description></item><item><title>Customize GNOME from i3</title><link>https://major.io/2019/09/22/customize-gnome-from-i3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/09/22/customize-gnome-from-i3/</guid><description>i3 has been my window manager of choice for a while and I really enjoy its simplicity and ease of use. I use plenty of gtk applications, such as Firefox and Evolution, and configuring them within i3 can be confusing.
This post covers a few methods to change configurations for GNOME and gtk applications from i3.
lxappearance Almost all of the gtk theming settings are available in lxappearance. You can change fonts, mouse cursors, icons, and colors.</description></item><item><title>Deploy monit in OpenShift</title><link>https://major.io/2019/09/11/deploy-monit-in-openshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/09/11/deploy-monit-in-openshift/</guid><description>Monit is a tried-and-true method for monitoring all kinds of systems, services, and network endpoints. Deploying monit is easy. There&amp;rsquo;s only one binary daemon to run and it reads monitoring configuration from files in a directory you specify.
Most Linux distributions have a package for monit and the package usually contains some basic configuration along with a systemd unit file to run the daemon reliably.
However, this post is all about how to deploy it inside OpenShift.</description></item><item><title>Get faster GitLab runners with a ramdisk</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/16/get-faster-gitlab-runners-with-a-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/16/get-faster-gitlab-runners-with-a-ramdisk/</guid><description>When you build tons of kernels every day like my team does, you look for speed improvements anywhere you can. Caching repositories, artifacts, and compiled objects makes kernel builds faster and it reduces infrastructure costs.
Need for speed We use GitLab CI in plenty of places, and that means we have a lot of gitlab-runner configurations for OpenShift (using the kubernetes executor) and AWS (using the docker-machine executor). The runner&amp;rsquo;s built-in caching makes it easy to upload and download cached items from object storage repositories like Google Cloud Storage or Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>buildah error: vfs driver does not support overlay.mountopt options</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/13/buildah-error-vfs-driver-does-not-support-overlay-mountopt-options/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/13/buildah-error-vfs-driver-does-not-support-overlay-mountopt-options/</guid><description>Buildah and podman make a great pair for building, managing and running containers on a Linux system. You can even use them with GitLab CI with a few small adjustments, namely the switch from the overlayfs to vfs storage driver.
I have some regularly scheduled GitLab CI jobs that attempt to build fresh containers each morning and I use these to get the latest packages and find out early when something is broken in the build process.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 30 on Google Compute Engine</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/07/fedora-30-on-google-compute-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/07/fedora-30-on-google-compute-engine/</guid><description>Fedora 30 is my primary operating system for desktops and servers, so I usually try to take it everywhere I go. I was recently doing some benchmarking for kernel compiles on different cloud plaforms and I noticed that Fedora isn&amp;rsquo;t included in Google Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s default list of operating system images.
(Note: Fedora does include links to quick start an Amazon EC2 instance with their pre-built AMI&amp;rsquo;s. They are superb!)</description></item><item><title>Ham Radio FAQ</title><link>https://major.io/ham-radio-faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/ham-radio-faq/</guid><description>Welcome! This page is a work in progress!
The world of amateur, or ham, radio is huge and it&amp;rsquo;s what you want to make of it. The itch struck me in the middle of 2017 and I learned a lot since then.
People often ask me questions about all kinds of amateur radio topics and I decided to compile all of the answers into a big page that I can update over time.</description></item><item><title>Texas Linux Fest 2019 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2019/06/02/texas-linux-fest-2019-recap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/06/02/texas-linux-fest-2019-recap/</guid><description>Another Texas Linux Fest has come and gone! The 2019 Texas Linux Fest was held in Irving at the Irving Convention Center. It was a great venue surrounded by lots of shops and restaurants.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t attended one of these events before, you really should! Attendees have varying levels of experience with Linux and the conference organizers (volunteers) work really hard to ensure everyone feels included.
The event usually falls on a Friday and Saturday.</description></item></channel></rss>