<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>qmail on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/qmail/</link><description>Recent content in qmail on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 18:54:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/qmail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting the maximum mail size in qmail</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/24/setting-the-maximum-mail-size-in-qmail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 18:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/24/setting-the-maximum-mail-size-in-qmail/</guid><description>On a Plesk server, the maximum size for an individual e-mail sent through qmail is unlimited. You can limit this size by adding a number to the /var/qmail/control/databytes file.
If you wanted to limit this to something like 10MB, you can just run the following command:
echo &amp;quot;10485760&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /var/qmail/control/databytes This will limit the size of messages (including attachments) to 10MB as a maximum.</description></item><item><title>Reduce iowait in Plesk: put qmail’s queue on a ramdisk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/14/reduce-iowait-in-plesk-put-qmails-queue-on-a-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 18:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/14/reduce-iowait-in-plesk-put-qmails-queue-on-a-ramdisk/</guid><description>I really dislike qmail. But, since I use Plesk, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck with it. However, I found a way to improve it&amp;rsquo;s awful mail queue performance by putting the mail queue onto a ramdisk. This is actually pretty darned easy to do.
First, toss a line like this into your /etc/fstab:
none /mailqueue tmpfs defaults,size=100m,nr_inodes=999k,mode=775 0 0 This will make a 100MB ramdisk on /mailqueue. Now, just symlink /var/qmail/mqueue to /mailqueue and move your e-mail over:</description></item><item><title>Can’t enable DNSBL/RBL in Plesk because it’s greyed out</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/25/cant-enable-dnsblrbl-in-plesk-because-its-greyed-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 17:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/25/cant-enable-dnsblrbl-in-plesk-because-its-greyed-out/</guid><description>If you have a new Plesk installation and the following option is greyed out in Server -&amp;gt; Mail:
Switch on spam protection based on DNS blackhole lists
Just install the following RPM from Plesk:
psa-qmail-rblsmtpd</description></item><item><title>qmail: This message is looping: it already has my Delivered-To line</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/23/qmail-this-message-is-looping-it-already-has-my-delivered-to-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/23/qmail-this-message-is-looping-it-already-has-my-delivered-to-line/</guid><description>I stumbled upon this peculiar bounce message recently while working on a server:
Hi. This is the qmail-send program at yourmailserver.com. I'm afraid I wasn't able to deliver your message to the following addresses. This is a permanent error; I've given up. Sorry it didn't work out. &amp;lt;user1@domain.com&amp;gt;: This message is looping: it already has my Delivered-To line. (#5.4.6) --- Below this line is a copy of the message.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; Return-Path: &amp;lt;remoteuser@otherdomain.</description></item><item><title>Plesk and qmail: 421 temporary envelope failure (#4.3.0)</title><link>https://major.io/2007/12/04/plesk-and-qmail-421-temporary-envelope-failure-430/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 18:21:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/12/04/plesk-and-qmail-421-temporary-envelope-failure-430/</guid><description>I stumbled upon a server running Plesk 8.2.1 where a certain user could not receive e-mail. I sent an e-mail to the user from my mail client, and I never saw it enter the user&amp;rsquo;s mailbox. It didn&amp;rsquo;t even appear in the logs.
After checking the usual suspects, like MX records, mail account configuration, and firewalls, I was unable to find out why it was occurring. Even after a run of mchk, the emails would not be delivered.</description></item><item><title>Sort e-mail in Plesk with procmail</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/27/sort-e-mail-in-plesk-with-procmail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 18:27:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/27/sort-e-mail-in-plesk-with-procmail/</guid><description>One of my biggest beefs with Plesk&amp;rsquo;s e-mail handling is the lack of server-side filtering. Plesk will only allow you to throw away e-mails marked as spam, but this won&amp;rsquo;t work for me since SpamAssassin marks some mails as spam that actually aren&amp;rsquo;t. If you set up filters in SquirrelMail or Horde, the filters will only work if you always log into the webmail interface to snag your e-mail.
Luckily, you can do some fancy work with procmail to have the filtering done server-side.</description></item></channel></rss>