<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ipv6 on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/ipv6/</link><description>Recent content in ipv6 on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/ipv6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get a /56 from Spectrum using wide-dhcpv6</title><link>https://major.io/2019/03/19/get-a-slash-56-from-spectrum-using-wide-dhcpv6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/03/19/get-a-slash-56-from-spectrum-using-wide-dhcpv6/</guid><description>After writing my last post on my IPv6 woes with my Pixel 3, some readers asked how I&amp;rsquo;m handling IPv6 on my router lately. I wrote about this previously when Spectrum was Time Warner Cable and I was using Mikrotik network devices.
There is a good post from 2015 on the blog and it still works today:
Time Warner Road Runner, Linux, and large IPv6 subnets I am still using that same setup today, but some readers found it difficult to find the post since Time Warner Cable has renamed to Spectrum.</description></item><item><title>Enable IPv6 privacy in NetworkManager</title><link>https://major.io/2016/04/17/enable-ipv6-privacy-networkmanager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 16:35:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/04/17/enable-ipv6-privacy-networkmanager/</guid><description>On most IPv6-enabled networks, network addresses are distributed via stateless address autoconfiguration (SLAAC). That is a fancy way to say that hosts on an IPv6 network will configure their own IP addresses.
The process usually works like this:
The host sends out a router solicitation request: Hey, who is the router around here? The router replies with a prefix: I am the router and your IPv6 address should start with this prefix.</description></item><item><title>Time Warner Road Runner, Linux, and large IPv6 subnets</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/11/time-warner-road-runner-linux-and-large-ipv6-subnets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 21:08:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/11/time-warner-road-runner-linux-and-large-ipv6-subnets/</guid><description>Although Time Warner Cable is now Spectrum and wide-dhcpv6 is quite old, this post is still what I&amp;rsquo;m using today (in 2019)!
I&amp;rsquo;ve written about how to get larger IPv6 subnets from Time Warner Cable&amp;rsquo;s Road Runner service on a Mikrotik router before, but I&amp;rsquo;ve converted to using a Linux server as my router for my home. Getting the larger /56 IPv6 subnet is a little tricky and it&amp;rsquo;s not terribly well documented.</description></item><item><title>HOWTO: Time Warner Cable and IPv6</title><link>https://major.io/2014/09/11/howto-time-warner-cable-ipv6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 14:43:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/09/11/howto-time-warner-cable-ipv6/</guid><description>Time Warner has gradually rolled out IPv6 connectivity to their Road Runner customers over the past couple of years and it started appearing on my home network earlier this year. I had some issues getting the leases to renew properly after they expired (TWC&amp;rsquo;s default lease length appears to be seven days) and there were some routing problems that cropped up occasionally. However, over the past month, things seem to have settled down on TWC&amp;rsquo;s San Antonio network.</description></item><item><title>X11 forwarding request failed on channel 0</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/24/x11-forwarding-request-failed-on-channel-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 19:24:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/24/x11-forwarding-request-failed-on-channel-0/</guid><description>Forwarding X over ssh is normally fairly straightforward when you have the correct packages installed. I have another post about the errors that appear when you&amp;rsquo;re missing the xorg-x11-xauth (CentOS, Fedora, RHEL) or xauth (Debian, Ubuntu) packages.
Today&amp;rsquo;s error was a bit different. Each time I accessed a particular Debian server via ssh with X forwarding requested, I saw this:
$ ssh -YC myserver.example.com X11 forwarding request failed on channel 0 The xauth package was installed and I found a .</description></item><item><title>OpenStack bleeding-edge Python packages are now available</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/01/openstack-bleeding-edge-python-packages-are-now-available/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 15:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/01/openstack-bleeding-edge-python-packages-are-now-available/</guid><description>I sometimes enjoy living on the edge occasionally and that sometimes means I keep up with OpenStack changes commit by commit. If you&amp;rsquo;re in the same boat as I am, you may save some time by using my repository of bleeding-edge Python packages from the OpenStack projects:
pypi.mhtx.net Python packages are updated moments after the commit is merged into the repositories under OpenStack&amp;rsquo;s github account.
Although the packages will contain the latest code available, rest assured that the code has passed an initial code review (by humans), unit tests, and varying levels of functional or integrated testing.</description></item><item><title>Native IPv6 connectivity in Mikrotik’s RouterOS</title><link>https://major.io/2012/01/11/native-ipv6-connectivity-in-mikrotiks-routeros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 13:30:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/01/11/native-ipv6-connectivity-in-mikrotiks-routeros/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Routerboard devices and the RouterOS software from Mikrotik that runs on them. The hardware is solid, the software is stable and feature-rich, and I found a great vendor that ships quickly.
I recently added a RB493G (~ $230 USD) to sit in front of a pair of colocated servers. The majority of the setup routine was the same as with my previous devices except for the IPv6 configuration.</description></item><item><title>icanhazip.com now supports both IPv4 and IPv6 addresses</title><link>https://major.io/2011/01/15/icanhazip-com-now-supports-both-ipv4-and-ipv6-addresses/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 14:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/01/15/icanhazip-com-now-supports-both-ipv4-and-ipv6-addresses/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of icanhazip.com, you&amp;rsquo;ll be excited to know that it now supports IPv4 and IPv6 addresses. The icanhazip.com domain now has A and AAAA records, so you should now be able to reach it on connections that are IPv6 only.
Should you find yourself in a situation in which you need to force it to display your IPv4 or IPv6 address (which is handy if you are running a dual stack), simply access ipv4.</description></item></channel></rss>