<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>screen on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/screen/</link><description>Recent content in screen on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 14:37:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/screen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching between audible and visual bells in screen</title><link>https://major.io/2010/01/21/switching-between-audible-and-visual-bells-in-screen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 14:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/01/21/switching-between-audible-and-visual-bells-in-screen/</guid><description>About a year ago, I was introduced to the joys of using irssi and screen to access irc servers. Before that time, I&amp;rsquo;d usually used graphical clients like Colloquy, and I always enjoyed getting Growl notifications when someone mentioned a word or string that I set up as a trigger.
Once I started using irssi in screen, I found that the visual bell in screen didn&amp;rsquo;t get my attention quickly. Luckily, someone in the #slicehost channel let me know about screen&amp;rsquo;s audible bell.</description></item><item><title>Change the escape keystrokes in screen</title><link>https://major.io/2010/01/07/change-the-escape-keystrokes-in-screen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 14:11:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/01/07/change-the-escape-keystrokes-in-screen/</guid><description>One of my favorite (and most used) applications on any Linux machine is screen. Once you fire up a screen session, you can start something and keep it running indefinitely. Even if your internet connection drops or you accidentally close your terminal window, the screen session will remain open on the remote server.
Detaching from a screen session is done by pressing CTRL-A and then d (for detach). However, when I&amp;rsquo;m on my Mac, CTRL-A and CTRL-E send my cursor to the beginning and end of lines, respectively.</description></item></channel></rss>