<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lxc on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/lxc/</link><description>Recent content in lxc on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 20:45:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/lxc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research Paper: Securing Linux Containers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/14/research-paper-securing-linux-containers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 20:45:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/14/research-paper-securing-linux-containers/</guid><description>It seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a new way to run containers every week. The advantages and drawbacks of each approach are argued about on mailing lists, in IRC channels, and in person, around the world. However, the largest amount of confusion seems to be around security.
Launching secure containers I&amp;rsquo;ve written about launching secure containers on this blog many times before:
Launch secure LXC containers on Fedora 20 using SELinux and sVirt Improving LXC template security Try out LXC with an Ansible playbook CoreOS vs.</description></item><item><title>Improving LXC template security</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/18/improving-lxc-template-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 19:52:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/18/improving-lxc-template-security/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting involved with the Fedora Security Team lately and we&amp;rsquo;re working as a group to crush security bugs that affect Fedora, CentOS (via EPEL) and Red Hat Enterprise Linux (via EPEL). During some of this work, I stumbled upon a group of Red Hat Bugzilla tickets talking about LXC template security.
The gist of the problem is that there&amp;rsquo;s a wide variance in how users and user credentials are handled by the different LXC templates.</description></item><item><title>Try out LXC with an Ansible playbook</title><link>https://major.io/2014/12/17/try-lxc-ansible-playbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 13:50:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/12/17/try-lxc-ansible-playbook/</guid><description>The world of containers is constantly evolving lately. The latest turn of events involves the CoreOS developers when they announced Rocket as an alternative to Docker. However, LXC still lingers as a very simple path to begin using containers.
When I talk to people about LXC, I often hear people talk about how difficult it is to get started with LXC. After all, Docker provides an easy-to-use image downloading function that allows you to spin up multiple different operating systems in Docker containers within a few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Launch secure LXC containers on Fedora 20 using SELinux and sVirt</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/21/launch-secure-lxc-containers-on-fedora-20-using-selinux-and-svirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 04:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/21/launch-secure-lxc-containers-on-fedora-20-using-selinux-and-svirt/</guid><description>Getting started with LXC is a bit awkward and I&amp;rsquo;ve assembled this guide for anyone who wants to begin experimenting with LXC containers in Fedora 20. As an added benefit, you can follow almost every step shown here when creating LXC containers on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Beta (which is based on Fedora 19).
You&amp;rsquo;ll need a physical machine or a VM running Fedora 20 to get started. (You could put a container in a container, but things get a little dicey with that setup.</description></item><item><title>Docker, trusted builds, and Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/26/docker-trusted-builds-and-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 05:17:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/26/docker-trusted-builds-and-fedora-20/</guid><description>Docker is a hot topic in the Linux world at the moment and I decided to try out the new trusted build process. Long story short, you put your Dockerfile along with any additional content into your GitHub repository, link your GitHub account with Docker, and then fire off a build. The Docker index labels it as &amp;ldquo;trusted&amp;rdquo; since it was build from source files in your repository.
I set off to build a Dockerfile to provision a container that would run all of the icanhazip services.</description></item></channel></rss>