<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 13:06:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Etsy reminds us that information security is an active process</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/22/etsy-reminds-us-that-information-security-is-an-active-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 13:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/22/etsy-reminds-us-that-information-security-is-an-active-process/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always impressed with the content published by folks at Etsy and Ben Hughes' presentation from DevOpsDays Minneapolis 2014 is no exception.
Ben adds some levity to the topic of information security with some hilarious (but relevant) images and reminds us that security is an active process that everyone must practice. Everyone plays a part - not just traditional corporate security employees.
I&amp;rsquo;ve embedded the presentation here for your convenience:</description></item><item><title>DevOps and enterprise inertia</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/17/devops-and-enterprise-inertia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 17:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/17/devops-and-enterprise-inertia/</guid><description>As I wait in the airport to fly back home from this year&amp;rsquo;s Red Hat Summit, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking back over the many conversations I had over breakfast, over lunch, and during the events. One common theme that kept cropping up was around bringing DevOps to the enterprise. I stumbled upon Mathias Meyer&amp;rsquo;s post, The Developer is Dead, Long Live the Developer, and I was inspired to write my own.
Before I go any further, here&amp;rsquo;s my definition of DevOps: it&amp;rsquo;s a mindset shift where everyone is responsible for the success of the customer experience.</description></item><item><title>Information security nuggets from DevOps Weekly #150</title><link>https://major.io/2013/11/17/information-security-nuggets-from-devops-weekly-150/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 21:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/11/17/information-security-nuggets-from-devops-weekly-150/</guid><description>Keeping an eye out for the DevOps Weekly email is something I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed since it started at the end of 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s usually chock full of tips for systems engineers, developers, managers, or anyone who is focused on environments that utilize continuous integration and deployment strategies. Quite a few of the tips are totally relevant for information security professionals who are looking for an edge at work.
This week, there are four links worth reviewing if you work in information security:</description></item></channel></rss>