<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>advice on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/advice/</link><description>Recent content in advice on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 15:53:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do professional certifications belong in your e-mail signature?</title><link>https://major.io/2010/10/16/do-professional-certifications-belong-in-your-e-mail-signature/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 15:53:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/10/16/do-professional-certifications-belong-in-your-e-mail-signature/</guid><description>After a discussion amongst coworkers about professional certifications in e-mail signatures yesterday, I decided to throw the question out to Twitter to gather some feedback:
rackerhacker: Quick Twitter poll for the nerds: How many certification abbreviations do you put in your e-mail signature? [Permalink]
The question must have struck a nerve with folks as I had over 50 replies in less than 10-15 minutes. I expected to hear a lot of people say &amp;ldquo;zero&amp;rdquo;, and there were quite a few responses that didn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me:</description></item><item><title>Securing your ssh server</title><link>https://major.io/2010/10/12/securing-your-ssh-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 22:39:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/10/12/securing-your-ssh-server/</guid><description>One of the most common questions that I see in my favorite IRC channel is: “How can I secure sshd on my server?” There&amp;rsquo;s no single right answer, but most systems administrators combine multiple techniques to provide as much security as possible with the least inconvenience to the end user.
Here are my favorite techniques listed from most effective to least effective:
SSH key pairs
By disabling password-based authentication and requiring ssh key pairs, you reduce the chances of compromise via a brute force attack.</description></item><item><title>A nerd’s perspective on cloud hosting</title><link>https://major.io/2010/08/25/a-nerds-perspective-on-cloud-hosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 13:03:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/08/25/a-nerds-perspective-on-cloud-hosting/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s go ahead and get this out of the way: The following post contains only my personal opinions. These are not the opinions of my employer and should not be considered as such. The term &amp;ldquo;cloud hosting&amp;rdquo; has become more popular over the past few years and it seems like everyone is talking about it. I&amp;rsquo;m often asked by customers and coworkers about what cloud hosting really is. Where does traditional dedicated hosting end and cloud begin?</description></item></channel></rss>