<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>icanhazip on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/icanhazip/</link><description>Recent content in icanhazip on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/icanhazip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>icanhazip.com FAQ</title><link>https://major.io/icanhazip-com-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/icanhazip-com-faq/</guid><description>icanhazip.com has a new owner! 🎉 Starting in June 2021, icanhazip.com is now owned and operated by Cloudflare! Read more about it in the blog post: A new future for icanhazip.
All of the remaining sites are unchanged.
Which sites are available? You have a few to choose from:
icanhazip.com - returns your IP address icanhazptr.com - returns the reverse DNS record (PTR) for your IP icanhaztrace.com - returns a traceroute from my servers to your IP address icanhaztraceroute.</description></item><item><title>A new future for icanhazip</title><link>https://major.io/2021/06/06/a-new-future-for-icanhazip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/06/06/a-new-future-for-icanhazip/</guid><description>In the summer of 2009, I had an idea. My workdays were spent deploying tons of cloud infrastructure as Rackspace acquired Slicehost and we rushed to keep up with the constant demands for new infrastructure from our customers. Working quickly led to challenges with hardware and networking.
That was a time where the I Can Has Cheeseburger meme was red hot just about everywhere. We needed a way to quickly check the public-facing IP address of lots of backend infrastructure and our customers sometimes needed that information, too.</description></item><item><title>Upatre and icanhazip</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/04/upatre-and-icanhazip/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 02:01:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/04/upatre-and-icanhazip/</guid><description>I recently updated the icanhazip FAQ about the resurgence of the Upatre malware and how it&amp;rsquo;s abusing icanhazip.com. The abuse reports keep coming into the ISP&amp;rsquo;s where I host the site and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming a challenge to defend each one.
From what I&amp;rsquo;ve read, Upatre is a piece of malware that has been around in one form or another since 2013. Somewhere along the way, it began making calls to icanhazip.</description></item><item><title>You have a problem and icanhazip.com isn’t one of them</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/20/you-have-a-problem-and-icanhazip-com-isnt-one-of-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 12:50:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/20/you-have-a-problem-and-icanhazip-com-isnt-one-of-them/</guid><description>I really enjoy operating icanhazip.com and the other domains. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to run some really busy services and find ways to reduce resource consumption and the overall cost of hosting.
My brain has a knack for optimization and improving the site is quite fun for me. So much so that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to host all of icanhazip.com out of my own pocket starting today.
However, something seriously needs to change.</description></item><item><title>icanhazip.com blocked by Websense</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/06/icanhazip-com-blocked-websense/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 01:16:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/06/icanhazip-com-blocked-websense/</guid><description>UPDATE 2014-08-07: Websense emailed me to say that the site has been reviewed and found to be safe. It may take some time for all of their products to receive the updated classification.
Quite a few emails and IRC messages hit my screen today about icanhazip.com being blocked by Websense products. The report on Websense&amp;rsquo;s site claims shows that the site is part of a bot network: The URL analyzed is currently compromised to serve malicious content to visitors.</description></item><item><title>icanhazip and CORS</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/21/icanhazip-and-cors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 14:31:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/21/icanhazip-and-cors/</guid><description>I received an email from an icanhazip.com user last week about enabling cross-origin resource sharing. He wanted to use AJAX calls on a different site to pull data from icanhazip.com and use it for his visitors.
Those headers are now available for all requests to the services provided by icanhazip.com! Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;ll see:
$ curl -i icanhazip.com --- Access-Control-Allow-Origin: * Access-Control-Allow-Methods: GET ---</description></item><item><title>Detect proxies with icanhazproxy</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/03/detect-proxies-with-icanhazproxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 15:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/03/detect-proxies-with-icanhazproxy/</guid><description>You can already detect proxy servers using icanhazip.com by accessing the service on port 80, 81, and 443. If you compare your results and you see different IP addresses, there&amp;rsquo;s most likely a proxy in the way.
To make things easier, I&amp;rsquo;ve launched icanhazproxy.com. It&amp;rsquo;s available on ports 80, 81 and 443 as well. If you choose to access it on port 443, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a certificate for icanhazip.com that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to ignore.</description></item><item><title>Docker, trusted builds, and Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/26/docker-trusted-builds-and-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 05:17:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/26/docker-trusted-builds-and-fedora-20/</guid><description>Docker is a hot topic in the Linux world at the moment and I decided to try out the new trusted build process. Long story short, you put your Dockerfile along with any additional content into your GitHub repository, link your GitHub account with Docker, and then fire off a build. The Docker index labels it as &amp;ldquo;trusted&amp;rdquo; since it was build from source files in your repository.
I set off to build a Dockerfile to provision a container that would run all of the icanhazip services.</description></item><item><title>icanhaz more domains: icanhazepoch.com</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/21/icanhaz-more-domains-icanhazepoch-com/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:41:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/21/icanhaz-more-domains-icanhazepoch-com/</guid><description>Sometimes I can&amp;rsquo;t help myself. I like to buy domains and use them for interesting activities. This tweet cropped up in my stream tonight:
You can give it a try now: icanhazepoch.com
$ curl icanhazepoch.com 1393036551 I&amp;rsquo;m doing my best to keep the server time in sync, so it should be relatively reliable. However, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend using it for launching satellites or timing anything where someone&amp;rsquo;s life is held in the balance.</description></item><item><title>Puppy Linux, icanhazip, and tin foil hats</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/09/puppy-linux-icanhazip-and-tin-foil-hats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 04:04:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/09/puppy-linux-icanhazip-and-tin-foil-hats/</guid><description>I figured that the Puppy Linux and icanhazip.com fiasco was over, but I was wrong:
After a quick visit to the forums, I found the debate stirred up again. Various users were wondering if their internet connections were somehow compromised or if a remote American network was somehow spying on their internet traffic. Others wondered if some secretive software was added to the Puppy Linux distribution that was calling out to the site.</description></item><item><title>This is why we can’t have nice things: malware callbacks to icanhazip.com</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/17/this-is-why-we-cant-have-nice-things-malware-callbacks-to-icanhazip-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 19:54:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/17/this-is-why-we-cant-have-nice-things-malware-callbacks-to-icanhazip-com/</guid><description>I figured it would only be a matter of time until people used icanhazip.com for evil deeds. Someone linked me to these Sophos analysis pages:
Detailed Analysis - Troj/Agent-ADRF
Detailed Analysis - Troj/Mdrop-FIM
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with a couple of these vendors to get my site removed from their products' blacklists but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long that will stay in place. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to hunt down user agents so that I can deny requests from certain malicious scripts and other malware but I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough intel on the malware to get started.</description></item><item><title>Privacy and icanhazip.com</title><link>https://major.io/2012/08/04/privacy-and-icanhazip-com/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 04:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/08/04/privacy-and-icanhazip-com/</guid><description>A forum thread cropped in my inbox today from the Puppy Linux forums titled &amp;ldquo;Major Hayden???&amp;rdquo;. After a little digging, I found a giant thread talking about icanhazip.com.
In these various threads, I was accused of:
being an expert on Linux (totally false!) running a site on behalf of the CIA being a direct descendent of General Michael Hayden (former director of CIA &amp;amp; NSA) recording MAC ID&amp;rsquo;s (which I assume means MAC addresses) on icanhazip.</description></item><item><title>Lifehacker effect on icanhazip.com</title><link>https://major.io/2011/03/30/lifehacker-effect-on-icanhazip-com/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 13:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/03/30/lifehacker-effect-on-icanhazip-com/</guid><description>I was surprised to see coverage about icanhazip.com on Lifehacker last Sunday and I was curious to know what effect the story would have on my site&amp;rsquo;s overall traffic. Dave Drager wrote a great summary of what the site offers and how people can use it in their daily work. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious that icanhazip.com really only serves a niche group of internet users, but even I was surprised at the level of interest.</description></item><item><title>icanhazip.com now supports both IPv4 and IPv6 addresses</title><link>https://major.io/2011/01/15/icanhazip-com-now-supports-both-ipv4-and-ipv6-addresses/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 14:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/01/15/icanhazip-com-now-supports-both-ipv4-and-ipv6-addresses/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of icanhazip.com, you&amp;rsquo;ll be excited to know that it now supports IPv4 and IPv6 addresses. The icanhazip.com domain now has A and AAAA records, so you should now be able to reach it on connections that are IPv6 only.
Should you find yourself in a situation in which you need to force it to display your IPv4 or IPv6 address (which is handy if you are running a dual stack), simply access ipv4.</description></item></channel></rss>