<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 18:42:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ICC color profile for Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon 4th generation</title><link>https://major.io/2017/01/11/icc-color-profile-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon-4th-generation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 18:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/01/11/icc-color-profile-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon-4th-generation/</guid><description>My new ThinkPad arrived this week and it is working well! The Fedora 25 installation was easy and all of the hardware was recognized immediately.
However, there was a downside. The display looked washed out and had a strange tint. It seemed to be more pale than the previous ThinkPad. The default ICC profile in GNOME didn&amp;rsquo;t help much.
There&amp;rsquo;s a helpful review over at NotebookCheck that has a link to an ICC profile generated from a 4th generation ThinkPad X1 Carbon.</description></item><item><title>OpenPOWER Summit Europe 2016 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2016/11/04/openpower-summit-europe-2016-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 14:07:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/11/04/openpower-summit-europe-2016-recap/</guid><description>I was in Barcelona last week for two big events: the OpenStack Summit and the OpenPOWER Summit. Luckily, the events were separated only by a five minute walk. Many of the slides from the OpenPOWER Summit are already available online.
One of my favorite talks was from Prof. Mateo Valero, the director of the Barcelona Supercomputer Center (Centro Nacional de Supercomputación). He was a great speaker and he talked a lot about how OpenPOWER has given them a new edge.</description></item><item><title>IBM Edge 2016: Day 1 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2016/09/20/ibm-edge-2016-day-1-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 20:19:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/09/20/ibm-edge-2016-day-1-recap/</guid><description>I am here in Las Vegas for IBM Edge 2016 to learn about the latest developments in POWER, machine learning, and OpenStack. It isn&amp;rsquo;t just about learning - I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some of our own use cases and challenges from my daily work at Rackspace.
I kicked off the day with a great run down the Las Vegas strip. There are many more staircases and escalators than I remember, but it was still a fun run.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned: Five years of colocation</title><link>https://major.io/2016/04/22/lessons-learned-four-years-colocation-hosting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/04/22/lessons-learned-four-years-colocation-hosting/</guid><description>Back in 2011, I decided to try out a new method for hosting my websites and other applications: colocation. Before that, I used shared hosting, VPS providers (&amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; wasn&amp;rsquo;t a popular thing back then), and dedicated servers. Each had their drawbacks in different areas. Some didn&amp;rsquo;t perform well, some couldn&amp;rsquo;t recover from failure well, and some were terribly time consuming to maintain.
This post will explain why I decided to try colocation and will hopefully help you avoid some of my mistakes.</description></item><item><title>Tinkering with systemd’s predictable network names</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/20/tinkering-with-systemds-predictable-network-names/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:46:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/20/tinkering-with-systemds-predictable-network-names/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about predictable network names (and seemingly unpredictable ones) on the blog before, but some readers asked me how they could alter the network naming to fit a particular situation. Oddly enough, my Supermicro 5028D-T4NT has a problem with predictable names and it&amp;rsquo;s a great example to use here.
The problem There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of detail in my post about the Supermicro 5028D-T4NT, but the basic gist is that something within the firmware is causing the all of the network cards in the server to show up as onboard.</description></item><item><title>Updating Dell PowerEdge BIOS from Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/18/updating-dell-poweredge-bios-from-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 20:53:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/18/updating-dell-poweredge-bios-from-linux/</guid><description>Updating Dell PowerEdge firmware from Linux is quite easy, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t documented very well. I ended up with a set of PowerEdge R710&amp;rsquo;s at work for a lab environment and the BIOS versions were different on each server.
Downloading the latest firmware Start by heading over to Dell&amp;rsquo;s support site and enter your system&amp;rsquo;s service tag. You can use lshw to find your service tag:
# lshw | head lab05 description: Rack Mount Chassis product: PowerEdge R710 () vendor: Dell Inc.</description></item><item><title>Asus Maximus VI Gene – Error 55</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/22/asus-maximus-vi-gene-error-55/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 14:20:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/22/asus-maximus-vi-gene-error-55/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since I built a computer but I decided to give it a try for a new hypervisor/NAS box at home. I picked up an Asus Maximus VI Gene motherboard since it had some good parts installed and it seems to work well with Linux. This was my first time doing water cooling for the CPU and I picked up a Seidon 240M after getting some recommendations.</description></item></channel></rss>