<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>supernova on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/supernova/</link><description>Recent content in supernova on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 15:04:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/supernova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>supernova 2.2.0 is available</title><link>https://major.io/2015/12/04/supernova-2-2-0-is-available/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 15:04:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/12/04/supernova-2-2-0-is-available/</guid><description>Thanks to all of the contributors that helped make a new release of supernova possible! Version 2.2.0 is available on GitHub or PyPi.
Changes There&amp;rsquo;s now a fix for some Pygi keyring errors that appeared on the console for some systems that use GnomeKeyring for credential storage. Thanks to dbolackrs for the fix and to gtmanfred for updating the tests.
Justin added some functionality to provide shorter listings of environment variables when you ask supernova to print all of the configurations from your .</description></item><item><title>supernova is coming to Fedora repositories</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/11/supernova-is-coming-to-fedora-repositories/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 13:13:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/11/supernova-is-coming-to-fedora-repositories/</guid><description>If you use Fedora, you will soon be able to install supernova via a Fedora package! The packages are currently in the testing repositories but they will soon be available in the stable repositories for Fedora 22, 23, and rawhide.
Want it right now? If you want to install supernova now, simply tell dnf to install it from the updates-testing repository:
dnf install --enablerepo=updates-testing supernova supernova in EPEL A few people have asked for supernova to be added to EPEL, but the version of the click module for python is too old.</description></item><item><title>Making things more super with supernova 2.0</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/18/making-things-more-super-with-supernova-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 17:42:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/18/making-things-more-super-with-supernova-2-0/</guid><description>I started supernova a little over three years ago with the idea of making it easier to use novaclient. Three years and a few downloads later, it manages multiple different OpenStack clients, like nova, glance, and trove along with some handy features for users who manage a large number of environments.
What&amp;rsquo;s new? With some help from some friends who are much better at writing Python than I am (thanks Paul, Matt and Jason), I restructured supernova to make it more testable.</description></item><item><title>Enjoy supernova 1.0.0</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/27/enjoy-supernova-1-0-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 13:19:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/27/enjoy-supernova-1-0-0/</guid><description>The first supernova commit to GitHub appeared just over two years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s been stable for quite some time, but it&amp;rsquo;s made it to version 1.0.0 today!
As always, you can get supernova from PyPi using pip:
pip install -U supernova All of the documentation has moved to ReadTheDocs and it looks much better than the giant README file in GitHub that served as the documentation for so long. Thanks to everyone that has committed code, found bugs, or called out my inability to write Python!</description></item><item><title>Testing grouped environment support for supernova</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/04/testing-grouped-environment-support-for-supernova/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 02:43:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/04/testing-grouped-environment-support-for-supernova/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added some grouped environment support for supernova tonight. This allows you to run the same action across a group of environments listed in your supernova configuration file. To give you an idea of how this works, I have two environments in my supernova file called prodord and prodiad. Both of them are my production environments at Rackspace:
[prodord] SUPERNOVA_GROUP=prodrax OS_AUTH_URL=https://identity.api.rackspacecloud.com/v2.0/ OS_AUTH_SYSTEM=rackspace OS_REGION_NAME=ORD OS_TENANT_NAME=USE_KEYRING[&amp;#39;prodcloudauthuser&amp;#39;] OS_PROJECT_ID=USE_KEYRING[&amp;#39;prodcloudauthuser&amp;#39;] OS_PASSWORD=USE_KEYRING[&amp;#39;prodcloudauthpass&amp;#39;] OS_PROJECT_ID=[my account number] [prodiad] SUPERNOVA_GROUP=prodrax OS_AUTH_URL=https://identity.</description></item><item><title>Small update for supernova 0.9.6</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/01/small-update-for-supernova-0-9-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 14:32:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/01/small-update-for-supernova-0-9-6/</guid><description>A supernova user ran into a tough problem where supernova didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to obey a configuration within the supernova configuration file. After checking python module versions and re-checking the configuration file a multitude of times, we discovered that there were variables defined in the user&amp;rsquo;s ~/.bash_profile that were not overwritten. It&amp;rsquo;s key to remember how supernova works:
supernova copies your current environment variables into a dictionary any configuration options from the supernova configuration are applied to the dictionary the dictionary is used to set environment variables only for the subprocess that runs nova (or the executable of your choice) your original environment variables are left unaltered.</description></item><item><title>supernova 0.9.5 is available</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/29/supernova-0-9-5-is-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 13:14:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/29/supernova-0-9-5-is-available/</guid><description>I just pushed supernova 0.9.5 to pypi and it&amp;rsquo;s now available for installation using pip. You can get the latest version by running:
pip install --upgrade supernova Some of the new features include the ability to use suprernova with other executables, like glance. Place a configuration option within your ~/.supernova file that looks like this:
OS_EXECUTABLE=/usr/bin/glance Once you do that, supernova will package up all of your environment variables as it normally would, but it will call glance instead of nova.</description></item><item><title>supernova 0.9.0 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2014/01/13/supernova-0-9-0-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 20:28:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/01/13/supernova-0-9-0-is-now-available/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll find version 0.9.0 of supernova on GitHub.
Here are the big changes:
A fix for supernova with python 2.6 (thanks to Sandy Walsh)
You can now use supernova with executables other than nova (thanks to Dan Krause)
Bash completion support (thanks to Cory Wright)
Version 0.9.0 is already on PyPi as well. Enjoy!</description></item><item><title>Reaching a new milestone and making some big changes</title><link>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</guid><description>This is my 500th post on this blog! I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful for the constant comments, questions, and even the complaints (really!) that I receive about the topics discussed here throughout the years. The sole reason I keep this blog going is for the readers and I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to get value out of it over time. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t, be sure to let me know so I can make some changes.</description></item></channel></rss>