<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dns on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/dns/</link><description>Recent content in dns on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 19:39:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automated Let’s Encrypt DNS challenges with Rackspace Cloud DNS</title><link>https://major.io/2016/03/31/automated-lets-encrypt-dns-challenges-with-rackspace-cloud-dns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 19:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/03/31/automated-lets-encrypt-dns-challenges-with-rackspace-cloud-dns/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt has taken the world by storm by providing free SSL certificates that can be renewed via automated methods. They have issued over 1.4 million certificates since launch in the fall of 2015.
If you are not familiar with how Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt operates, here is an extremely simple explanation:
Create a private key Make a request for a new certificate Complete the challenge process You have a certificate! That is highly simplified, but there is plenty of detail available on how the whole system works.</description></item><item><title>cups.service start operation timed out in Fedora 22</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/09/cups-service-start-operation-timed-out-in-fedora-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 14:35:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/09/cups-service-start-operation-timed-out-in-fedora-22/</guid><description>Applications on my Fedora 22 system kept stalling when I attempted to print. My system journal was full of these log messages:
systemd[1]: cups.service start operation timed out. Terminating. systemd[1]: Failed to start CUPS Scheduler. systemd[1]: Unit cups.service entered failed state. systemd[1]: cups.service failed. audit[1]: &amp;lt;audit-1130&amp;gt; pid=1 uid=0 auid=4294967295 ses=4294967295 subj=system_u:system_r:init_t:s0 msg='unit=cups comm=&amp;quot;systemd&amp;quot; exe=&amp;quot;/usr/lib/systemd/systemd&amp;quot; hostname=? addr=? terminal=? res=failed' If I tried to run systemctl start cups, the command would hang for quite a while and then fail.</description></item><item><title>Fixing broken DNS lookups in spamassassin</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/20/fixing-broken-dns-lookups-in-spamassassin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 13:20:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/20/fixing-broken-dns-lookups-in-spamassassin/</guid><description>I talked about the joys of running my own mail server last week only to find that my mail server was broken yesterday. Spamassassin stopped doing DNS lookups for RBL and SPF checks.
I had one of these moments:
My logs looked like this:
plugin: eval failed: available_nameservers: No DNS servers available! plugin: eval failed: available_nameservers: No DNS servers available! rules: failed to run NO_DNS_FOR_FROM RBL test, skipping: (available_nameservers: [.</description></item><item><title>DNS Service Review: Luadns</title><link>https://major.io/2012/07/22/dns-service-review-luadns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 20:31:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/07/22/dns-service-review-luadns/</guid><description>Vitalie Cherpec contacted me back in May about his new hosted DNS offering, Luadns. I gave it a try and I offered to write a review about the service.
DISCLAIMER: I don&amp;rsquo;t write many reviews on this blog, but I want to make sure a few things are clear. Vitalie was kind enough to set up an account for me to test with which would have normally cost me $9/month. However, he didn&amp;rsquo;t give me any compensation of any kind for the review itself and there was nothing done for me outside of what a customer would receive at a paid service level at Luadns.</description></item><item><title>WordPress + W3 Total Cache + MaxCDN How-To</title><link>https://major.io/2010/02/13/wordpress-w3-total-cache-maxcdn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 03:56:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/02/13/wordpress-w3-total-cache-maxcdn/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of WordPress as a blog and CMS platform. While it does have its problems, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple to set up, it&amp;rsquo;s extensible, and - when properly configured - it has great performance. The WP Super Cache plugin has been a staple on my WordPress blogs for quite some time and it has solved almost all of my performance problems.
However, when you load up quite a few plugins or a heavy theme, the performance will dip due to the increased number of stylesheets, javascript files, and images.</description></item></channel></rss>