<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rhel on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/rhel/</link><description>Recent content in rhel on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 19:01:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/rhel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>augenrules fails with “rule exists” when loading rules into auditd</title><link>https://major.io/2017/01/03/augenrules-fails-with-rule-exists-when-loading-rules-into-auditd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 19:01:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/01/03/augenrules-fails-with-rule-exists-when-loading-rules-into-auditd/</guid><description>When I came back from the holiday break, I found that the openstack-ansible-security role wasn&amp;rsquo;t passing tests any longer. The Ansible playbook stopped when augenrules ran to load the new audit rules. The error wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly helpful:
/usr/sbin/augenrules: No change Error sending add rule data request (Rule exists) There was an error in line 5 of /etc/audit/audit.rules A duplicated rule? I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on lots of changes to implement the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG) and I assumed I put in the same rule twice with an errant copy and paste.</description></item><item><title>Chronicles of SELinux: Dealing with web content in unusual directories</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/10/chronicles-of-selinux-dealing-with-web-content-in-unusual-directories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:40:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/10/chronicles-of-selinux-dealing-with-web-content-in-unusual-directories/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start a series of posts called &amp;ldquo;Chronicles of SELinux&amp;rdquo; where I hope to educate more users on how to handle SELinux denials with finesse rather than simply disabling it entirely. To kick things off, I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about dealing with web content in the first post.
First steps If you&amp;rsquo;d like to follow along, simply hop onto a system running Fedora 21 (or later), CentOS 7 or Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.</description></item><item><title>Automated testing for Ansible CIS playbook on RHEL/CentOS 6</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/05/automated-testing-for-ansible-cis-playbook-on-rhelcentos-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 13:13:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/05/automated-testing-for-ansible-cis-playbook-on-rhelcentos-6/</guid><description>I started working on the Ansible CIS playbook for CentOS and RHEL 6 back in 2014 and I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes to increase quality and make it easier to use.
First off, the role itself is no longer a submodule. You can now just clone the repository and get rolling. This should reduce the time it takes to get started.
Also, all pull requests to the repository now go through integration testing at Rackspace.</description></item><item><title>Launch secure LXC containers on Fedora 20 using SELinux and sVirt</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/21/launch-secure-lxc-containers-on-fedora-20-using-selinux-and-svirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 04:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/21/launch-secure-lxc-containers-on-fedora-20-using-selinux-and-svirt/</guid><description>Getting started with LXC is a bit awkward and I&amp;rsquo;ve assembled this guide for anyone who wants to begin experimenting with LXC containers in Fedora 20. As an added benefit, you can follow almost every step shown here when creating LXC containers on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Beta (which is based on Fedora 19).
You&amp;rsquo;ll need a physical machine or a VM running Fedora 20 to get started. (You could put a container in a container, but things get a little dicey with that setup.</description></item></channel></rss>