<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 02:17:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I’m on the hunt for experienced security analysts!</title><link>https://major.io/2013/10/14/im-on-the-hunt-for-experienced-security-analysts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 02:17:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/10/14/im-on-the-hunt-for-experienced-security-analysts/</guid><description>Want to work for a company that finds new approaches to traditional IT problems? Do you want to work with a team that provides Fanatical Support through keeping customer data safe?
Our Global Security Services team is looking for experienced security analysts who can take network analysis and malware defense to the next level.
The responsibilities of the role include:
Monitor global NIDS, Firewall, and log correlation tools for potential threats Initiate escalation procedure to counteract potential threats/vulnerabilities Provide Incident remediation and prevention documentation Document and conform to processes related to security monitoring Provide performance metrics as necessary Provide customer service that exceeds our customers expectations Experience with tools such as Wireshark, Hex Rays, IDA Pro or Hex workshop.</description></item><item><title>Block Flash and Java in your browser today</title><link>https://major.io/2013/02/22/block-flash-and-java-in-your-browser-today/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 16:56:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/02/22/block-flash-and-java-in-your-browser-today/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about the wave of security issues caused by Java and Flash in recent months, you must be living under a rock. Attackers are getting smarter by delivering more 0-day exploits that fly under the radar of traditional A/V products and patches from the vendors are lagging behind. How can you attack the problem in the meantime?
Be smart and only enable Flash and Java for the sites you explicitly trust.</description></item><item><title>Highlight IP addresses with a double click in Firefox</title><link>https://major.io/2011/08/16/highlight-ip-addresses-with-a-double-click-in-firefox/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 12:46:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/08/16/highlight-ip-addresses-with-a-double-click-in-firefox/</guid><description>My daily work involves working with a large number of servers and one of my frustrations with Firefox is that it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to select an entire IP address with a double click with the default settings. Although it works right out of the box with Safari, you have to make a configuration adjustment in Firefox to get the same behavior.
To change the setting in Firefox, open up a new Firefox tab and go to about:config in the browser.</description></item></channel></rss>