<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>redhat on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/redhat/</link><description>Recent content in redhat on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/redhat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Travel Guide to Brno</title><link>https://major.io/2020/01/30/my-travel-guide-to-brno/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/01/30/my-travel-guide-to-brno/</guid><description>Come to the Czech Republic and discover the beautiful city of Brno. I just wrapped up my third visit to the city and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to come back! The city is full of history, culture, and delicious food.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my travel guide to Brno!
Getting to Brno Brno has an airport, but the flights are limited and sometimes expensive. Some coworkers have found good deals on these flights (especially via Ryanair from London&amp;rsquo;s Stansted Airport), but I prefer the train.</description></item><item><title>Updating Dell PowerEdge BIOS from Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/18/updating-dell-poweredge-bios-from-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 20:53:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/18/updating-dell-poweredge-bios-from-linux/</guid><description>Updating Dell PowerEdge firmware from Linux is quite easy, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t documented very well. I ended up with a set of PowerEdge R710&amp;rsquo;s at work for a lab environment and the BIOS versions were different on each server.
Downloading the latest firmware Start by heading over to Dell&amp;rsquo;s support site and enter your system&amp;rsquo;s service tag. You can use lshw to find your service tag:
# lshw | head lab05 description: Rack Mount Chassis product: PowerEdge R710 () vendor: Dell Inc.</description></item><item><title>Audit RHEL/CentOS 6 security benchmarks with ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/19/audit-rhelcentos-6-security-benchmarks-ansible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/19/audit-rhelcentos-6-security-benchmarks-ansible/</guid><description>Securing critical systems isn&amp;rsquo;t easy and that&amp;rsquo;s why security benchmarks exist. Many groups and communities distribute recommendations for securing servers, including NIST, the US Department of Defense (DoD), and the Center for Internet Security (CIS).
Although NIST and DoD are catching up quickly with newer OS releases, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the CIS benchmarks are updated very regularly. CIS distributes auditing tools (with paid memberships) that require Java and they&amp;rsquo;re cumbersome to use, especially on servers where Java isn&amp;rsquo;t normally installed.</description></item><item><title>Start Jenkins on Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/13/get-jenkins-start-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 14:39:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/13/get-jenkins-start-fedora-20/</guid><description>Installing Jenkins on Fedora 20 is quite easy thanks to the available Red Hat packages, but I ran into problems when I tried to start Jenkins. Here are the installation steps I followed:
wget -O /etc/yum.repos.d/jenkins.repo http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/redhat/jenkins.repo rpm --import http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/redhat/jenkins-ci.org.key yum -y install jenkins systemctl enable jenkins systemctl start jenkins Your first error will show up if Java isn&amp;rsquo;t installed. You can fix that by installing Java:
yum -y install java-1.</description></item><item><title>httpry 0.1.8 available for RHEL and CentOS 7</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/13/httpry-rhel-centos-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 13:20:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/13/httpry-rhel-centos-7/</guid><description>Red Hat Enterprise Linux and CentOS 7 users can now install httpry 0.1.8 in EPEL 7 Beta. The new httpry version is also available for RHEL/CentOS 6 and supported Fedora versions (19, 20, 21 branched, and rawhide).
Configuring EPEL on a RHEL/CentOS server is easy. Follow the instructions on EPEL&amp;rsquo;s site and install the epel-release RPM that matches your OS release version.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t used httpry before, check the output on Jason Bittel&amp;rsquo;s site.</description></item><item><title>Unexpected predictable network naming with systemd</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/06/unexpected-predictable-network-naming-systemd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 21:09:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/06/unexpected-predictable-network-naming-systemd/</guid><description>While using a Dell R720 at work today, we stumbled upon a problem where the predictable network device naming with systemd gave us some unpredictable results. The server has four onboard network ports (two 10GbE and two 1GbE) and an add-on 10GbE card with two additional ports.
Running lspci gives this output:
# lspci | grep Eth 01:00.0 Ethernet controller: Intel Corporation Ethernet Controller 10-Gigabit X540-AT2 (rev 01) 01:00.1 Ethernet controller: Intel Corporation Ethernet Controller 10-Gigabit X540-AT2 (rev 01) 08:00.</description></item><item><title>Adventures in live booting Linux distributions</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/29/adventures-in-live-booting-linux-distributions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 13:05:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/29/adventures-in-live-booting-linux-distributions/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with live booting Linux distributions. Almost every Linux distribution under the sun has a method for making live CD&amp;rsquo;s, writing live USB sticks, or booting live images over the network. The primary use case for some distributions is on a live medium (like KNOPPIX).
However, I embarked on an adventure to look at live booting Linux for a different use case. Sure, many live environments are used for demonstrations or installations - temporary activities for a desktop or a laptop.</description></item><item><title>PXE boot Fedora 19 using a Mikrotik firewall</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/23/pxe-boot-fedora-19-using-a-mikrotik-firewall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 21:47:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/23/pxe-boot-fedora-19-using-a-mikrotik-firewall/</guid><description>Outside of the RHCA exams, I haven&amp;rsquo;t configured a PXE system for my personal needs. A colleague demoed his PXE setup for me and I was hooked. Once I realized how much time I could save when I&amp;rsquo;m building and tearing down virtual machines, it made complete sense. This post will show you how to configure PXE and tftpd in Mikrotik&amp;rsquo;s RouterOS to boot and install Fedora 19 (as well as provide rescue environments).</description></item><item><title>Come and get your SELinux shirts!</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/18/come-and-get-your-selinux-shirts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 12:14:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/18/come-and-get-your-selinux-shirts/</guid><description>After my podcast interview at the 2013 Red Hat Summit, Dan Walsh posted a photo of himself in the SELinux shirt that I gave him at the Summit:
Needless to say, I was flooded with requests for shirts after that. Someone suggested using the Overpass font and I have new shirts ready for purchase on Spreadshirt.
I set all the prices as low as the vendor will allow and I&amp;rsquo;m not making any profit for each purchase.</description></item><item><title>A humble farewell to Seth Vidal</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</guid><description>I was shocked to see Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s email today about Seth Vidal&amp;rsquo;s passing. He was the victim of a hit and run accident while he was cycling last night. The suspect has turned himself in as of tonight.
I first met Seth at FUDCon Tempe back in 2011. We had talked off and on via email and IRC about cloud-related topics. He was interested in how we assembled our cloud offering at Rackspace and I was eager to talk to him about building cloud images and handling mirrors.</description></item><item><title>Boot VM’s with virt-manager and libvirt with ISO’s stored remotely via samba/cifs</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/06/boot-vms-with-virt-manager-and-libvirt-with-isos-stored-remotely-via-sambacifs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 01:51:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/06/boot-vms-with-virt-manager-and-libvirt-with-isos-stored-remotely-via-sambacifs/</guid><description>Pairing virt-manager with KVM makes booting new VM&amp;rsquo;s pretty darned easy. I have a QNAP NAS at home with a bunch of ISO&amp;rsquo;s stored in share available to guests and I wanted to use that with libvirt to boot new VM&amp;rsquo;s. (By the way, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an off-the-shelf NAS that is built with solid hardware and pretty reliable software, try one of the QNAP devices. You still get access to many of the usual commands that you would normally find on a Linux box for emergencies.</description></item><item><title>Confine untrusted users (including your children) with SELinux</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/05/confine-untrusted-users-including-your-children-with-selinux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 18:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/05/confine-untrusted-users-including-your-children-with-selinux/</guid><description>The confined user support in SELinux is handy for ensuring that users aren&amp;rsquo;t able to do something that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. It seems more effective and easier to use than most of the other methods I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. Thanks to Dan for reminding me about this during his SELinux in the Enterprise talk from this year&amp;rsquo;s Red Hat Summit.
There are five main SELinux user types (and a handy chart in the Fedora documentation):</description></item><item><title>My interview on the Dave and Gunnar Show</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/19/my-interview-on-the-dave-and-gunnar-show/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 12:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/19/my-interview-on-the-dave-and-gunnar-show/</guid><description>David Egts and Gunnar Hellekson were kind enough to invite me to participate in their Dave and Gunnar Show podcast during the 2013 Red Hat Summit. We talked about Red Hat Enterprise Linux and my takeaways from the Summit.
The podcast episode [32MB] is about 34 minutes long and my interview starts after the 21 minute mark. I&amp;rsquo;m always nervous when I do these things so you&amp;rsquo;re certainly not allowed to poke fun at my accent.</description></item><item><title>Red Hat Summit 2013 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/14/red-hat-summit-2013-recap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:25:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/14/red-hat-summit-2013-recap/</guid><description>The 2013 Red Hat Summit was my second one and I enjoyed it more than last year. Quite a few people asked for a recap and some takeaways from the Summit and that&amp;rsquo;s what I hope to do in this post.
Keynotes
It&amp;rsquo;s quite apparent that Red Hat is taking a more assertive - and sometimes aggressive - stance against closed source, overpriced solutions that prevent consumers from getting things done.</description></item><item><title>Seriously, stop disabling SELinux</title><link>https://major.io/2013/04/15/seriously-stop-disabling-selinux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 04:40:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/04/15/seriously-stop-disabling-selinux/</guid><description>After many discussions with fellow Linux users, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize that most seem to disable SELinux rather than understand why it&amp;rsquo;s denying access. In an effort to turn the tide, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a new site as a public service to SELinux cowards everywhere: stopdisablingselinux.com.
Here are some relatively useful SELinux posts from the blog:
Getting started with SELinux Receive email reports for SELinux AVC denials Edit: The goal of the post was to poke some fun at system administrators who disable SELinux immediately without learning how it works or why they&amp;rsquo;re seeing certain operations being denied.</description></item><item><title>Remove sensitive information from email headers with postfix</title><link>https://major.io/2013/04/14/remove-sensitive-information-from-email-headers-with-postfix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 02:59:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/04/14/remove-sensitive-information-from-email-headers-with-postfix/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of moving back to a postfix/dovecot setup for hosting my own mail and I wanted a way to remove the more sensitive email headers that are normally generated when I send mail. My goal is to hide the originating IP address of my mail as well as my mail client type and version.
To get started, make a small file with regular expressions in /etc/postfix/header_checks:
/^Received:.*with ESMTPSA/ IGNORE /^X-Originating-IP:/ IGNORE /^X-Mailer:/ IGNORE /^Mime-Version:/ IGNORE The &amp;ldquo;ESMTPSA&amp;rdquo; match works for me because I only send email via port 465.</description></item><item><title>X forwarding over ssh woes: DISPLAY is not set</title><link>https://major.io/2012/07/14/x-forwarding-over-ssh-woes-display-is-not-set/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 19:56:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/07/14/x-forwarding-over-ssh-woes-display-is-not-set/</guid><description>This problem came up in conversation earlier this week and I realized that I&amp;rsquo;d never written a post about it. Has this ever happened to you before?
$ ssh -YC remotebox [major@remotebox ~]$ xterm xterm: Xt error: Can't open display: xterm: DISPLAY is not set I&amp;rsquo;ve scratched my head on this error message when the remote server is a minimally-installed CentOS, Fedora, or Red Hat system. It turns out that the xorg-x11-xauth package wasn&amp;rsquo;t installed with the minimal package set and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any authentication credentials ready to hand off to the X server on the remote machine.</description></item><item><title>SELinux and .forward files</title><link>https://major.io/2012/01/02/selinux-and-forward-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 22:44:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/01/02/selinux-and-forward-files/</guid><description>If you want to forward e-mail from root to another user, you can usually place a .forward file in root&amp;rsquo;s home directory and your mail server will take care of the rest:
/root/.forward With SELinux, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up getting an AVC denial each time your mail server tries to read the contents of the .forward file:
type=AVC msg=audit(1325543823.787:7416): avc: denied { open } for pid=9850 comm=&amp;quot;local&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;.forward&amp;quot; dev=md0 ino=17694734 scontext=system_u:system_r:postfix_local_t:s0 tcontext=unconfined_u:object_r:admin_home_t:s0 tclass=file The reason is that your .</description></item></channel></rss>