<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>irc on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/irc/</link><description>Recent content in irc on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 03:43:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/irc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Make alt-arrow keys work with terminator and weechat</title><link>https://major.io/2018/09/05/make-alt-arrow-keys-work-with-terminator-and-weechat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 03:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/09/05/make-alt-arrow-keys-work-with-terminator-and-weechat/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I make the move from the world of GNOME to i3, I found myself digging deeper into the &lt;a href="https://terminator-gtk3.readthedocs.io/en/latest/">terminator&lt;/a> preferences to make it work more like &lt;a href="https://help.gnome.org/users/gnome-terminal/stable/">gnome-terminal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Send weechat notifications via Pushover</title><link>https://major.io/2014/12/05/send-weechat-notifications-via-pushover/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 16:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/12/05/send-weechat-notifications-via-pushover/</guid><description>IRC is my main communication mechanism and I&amp;rsquo;ve gradually moved from graphical clients, to irssi and then to weechat. Text-based IRC removes quite a few distractions for me and it allows me to get access to my IRC communications from anything that can act as an ssh client.
I wanted a better way to get notifications when people send me messages and I&amp;rsquo;m away from my desk. Pushover is a great service that will take notification data via an API and blast it out to various devices.</description></item><item><title>Installing irssi via MacPorts on OS X Lion 10.7.1</title><link>https://major.io/2011/09/30/installing-irssi-via-macports-on-os-x-lion-10-7-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 13:24:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/09/30/installing-irssi-via-macports-on-os-x-lion-10-7-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve floated back and forth between graphical IRC clients and terminal-based clients for a long time. However, I was sad to see that irssi wouldn&amp;rsquo;t build via MacPorts on OS X Lion. During the build, I saw quite a few errors from the compiler:
-E, -S, -save-temps and -M options are not allowed with multiple -arch flags Sure enough, when I looked at the lines in the output, both x86_64 and i386 were passed to the compiler:</description></item><item><title>Switching between audible and visual bells in screen</title><link>https://major.io/2010/01/21/switching-between-audible-and-visual-bells-in-screen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 14:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/01/21/switching-between-audible-and-visual-bells-in-screen/</guid><description>About a year ago, I was introduced to the joys of using irssi and screen to access irc servers. Before that time, I&amp;rsquo;d usually used graphical clients like Colloquy, and I always enjoyed getting Growl notifications when someone mentioned a word or string that I set up as a trigger.
Once I started using irssi in screen, I found that the visual bell in screen didn&amp;rsquo;t get my attention quickly. Luckily, someone in the #slicehost channel let me know about screen&amp;rsquo;s audible bell.</description></item><item><title>Changing the time zone in irssi</title><link>https://major.io/2009/11/03/changing-the-time-zone-in-irssi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 14:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/11/03/changing-the-time-zone-in-irssi/</guid><description>I usually set the time zone on my servers to UTC, but that makes it a bit confusing for me when I use irssi. If you have perl support built into irssi, you can run these commands to alter your time zone within irssi only:
For example, I&amp;rsquo;m in Central Time, so I&amp;rsquo;d use:
To update the time in your status bar, simply /whois yourself and you should see the updated time zone.</description></item></channel></rss>