<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sysadmin on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/sysadmin/</link><description>Recent content in sysadmin on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 15:30:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fight cynicism with curiosity</title><link>https://major.io/2016/02/17/fight-cynicism-curiosity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 15:30:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/02/17/fight-cynicism-curiosity/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always interested to talk to college students about technology and business in general. They have amazing ideas and they don&amp;rsquo;t place any limits on themselves. In particular, their curiosity is limitless.
A great question I joined several other local employers at the University of Texas at San Antonio last week for mock interviews with computer science students. We went through plenty of sample questions and gave feedback to the students on their content and delivery during the mock interviews.</description></item><item><title>Helpful, low-FUD information security sites, mailing lists, and blogs</title><link>https://major.io/2015/01/08/helpful-low-fud-information-security-sites-mailing-lists-blogs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/01/08/helpful-low-fud-information-security-sites-mailing-lists-blogs/</guid><description>Keeping current with the latest trends and technologies in the realm of information security is critical and there are many options to choose from. However, as with any content on the internet, it takes some effort to find sites with a good signal-to-noise ratio. Information security is a heavily FUD-laden industry and I&amp;rsquo;ve taken some time to compile a list of helpful sites.
General sites Cryptanalys.is: https://cryptanalys.is/ Linux Weekly News (subscription optional but highly recommended): http://lwn.</description></item><item><title>Install sysstat on Fedora 21</title><link>https://major.io/2014/12/12/install-sysstat-fedora-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 17:55:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/12/12/install-sysstat-fedora-21/</guid><description>One of the first tools I learned about after working with Red Hat was sysstat. It can write down historical records about your server at regular intervals. This can help you diagnose CPU usage, RAM usage, or network usage problems. In addition, sysstat also provides some handy command line utilities like vmstat, iostat, and pidstat that give you a live view of what your system is doing.
On Debian-based systems (including Ubuntu), you install the sysstat package and enable it with a quick edit to /etc/default/sysstat and the cron job takes it from there.</description></item><item><title>Adventures in live booting Linux distributions</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/29/adventures-in-live-booting-linux-distributions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 13:05:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/29/adventures-in-live-booting-linux-distributions/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with live booting Linux distributions. Almost every Linux distribution under the sun has a method for making live CD&amp;rsquo;s, writing live USB sticks, or booting live images over the network. The primary use case for some distributions is on a live medium (like KNOPPIX).
However, I embarked on an adventure to look at live booting Linux for a different use case. Sure, many live environments are used for demonstrations or installations - temporary activities for a desktop or a laptop.</description></item><item><title>Configure remote syslog for XenServer via the command line</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/03/configure-remote-syslog-for-xenserver-via-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/03/configure-remote-syslog-for-xenserver-via-the-command-line/</guid><description>Citrix has some helpful documentation online about configuring remote syslog support for XenServer using the XenCenter GUI. However, if you need to do this via configuration management or scripts, using a GUI isn&amp;rsquo;t an option.
Getting it done via the command line is relatively easy:
HOSTUUID=`xe host-list --minimal` SYSLOGHOST=syslog.example.com xe host-param-set uuid=${HOSTUUID} logging:syslog_destination=${SYSLOGHOST} xe host-syslog-reconfigure host-uuid=${HOSTUUID} Removing the configuration and going back to only local logging is easy as well:</description></item><item><title>Switching to systemd on Debian jessie</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/20/switching-to-systemd-on-debian-jessie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 13:47:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/20/switching-to-systemd-on-debian-jessie/</guid><description>It seems like everyone is embracing systemd these days. It&amp;rsquo;s been in Fedora since 2011 and it&amp;rsquo;s already in the RHEL 7 release candidate. Arch Linux and Gentoo have it as well. Debian got on board with the jessie release (which is currently in testing).
Switching from old SysVinit to systemd in Debian jessie is quite simple. For the extremely cautious system administrators, you can follow Debian&amp;rsquo;s guide and test systemd before you make the full cutover.</description></item><item><title>Helpful Linux I/O stack diagram</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/30/helpful-linux-io-stack-diagram/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 15:03:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/30/helpful-linux-io-stack-diagram/</guid><description>During one of my regular trips to reddit, I stumbled upon an amazingly helpful Linux I/O stack diagram:
It&amp;rsquo;s quite comprehensive and it can really help if you&amp;rsquo;re digging through a bottleneck and you&amp;rsquo;re not quite sure where to look. The original diagram is available in multiple formats from Thomas Krenn&amp;rsquo;s website.
If you combine that with this slide from Brendan Gregg&amp;rsquo;s Linux Performance Analysis and Tools presentation from Scale 11x, you can attack performance problems with precision:</description></item><item><title>Configure static IP addresses for Project Atomic’s KVM image</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/23/configure-static-ip-addresses-for-project-atomics-kvm-image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 15:14:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/23/configure-static-ip-addresses-for-project-atomics-kvm-image/</guid><description>Amid all of the Docker buzz at the Red Hat Summit, Project Atomic was launched. It&amp;rsquo;s a minimalistic Fedora 20 image with a few tweaks, including rpm-ostree and geard.
There are great instructions on the site for firing up a test instance under KVM but my test server doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a DHCP server on its network. You can use Project Atomic with static IP addresses fairly easily:
Create a one-line /etc/sysconfig/network:</description></item><item><title>openssl heartbleed updates for Fedora 19 and 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/07/openssl-heartbleed-updates-for-fedora-19-and-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 01:18:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/07/openssl-heartbleed-updates-for-fedora-19-and-20/</guid><description>The openssl heartbleed bug has made the rounds today and there are two new testing builds or openssl out for Fedora 19 and 20:
Fedora 19 Fedora 20 Both builds are making their way over into the updates-testingstable repository thanks to some quick testing and karma from the Fedora community.
If the stable updates haven&amp;rsquo;t made it into your favorite mirror yet, you can live on the edge and grab the koji builds:</description></item><item><title>Installing Xen on Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/27/installing-xen-on-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 03:43:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/27/installing-xen-on-fedora-20/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about installing Xen on Fedora 19 and earlier versions on this blog before. Let&amp;rsquo;s tackle it on Fedora 20.
Start with the Xen hypervisor and the basic toolset first:
yum -y install xen xen-hypervisor xen-libs xen-runtime systemctl enable xend.service systemctl enable xendomains.service Get GRUB2 in order:
# grep ^menuentry /boot/grub2/grub.cfg | cut -d &amp;quot;'&amp;quot; -f2 Fedora, with Linux 3.13.4-200.fc20.x86_64 Fedora, with Linux 0-rescue-c9dcecb251df472fbc8b4e620a749f6d Fedora, with Xen hypervisor # grub2-set-default 'Fedora, with Xen hypervisor' # grub2-editenv list saved_entry=Fedora, with Xen hypervisor # grub2-mkconfig -o /boot/grub2/grub.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v1.3.0</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/21/mysqltuner-v1-3-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/21/mysqltuner-v1-3-0/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been three long years since the last MySQLTuner release but you&amp;rsquo;ll now find version 1.3.0 available on GitHub. You can get it from the git repository or via these extremely simple methods:
wget -O mysqltuner.pl mysqltuner.pl wget --trust-server-names mysqltuner.pl There are a bunch of new features and fixes that you can find in the list of commits from today (2014-02-21). Some of the bigger adjustments include:
Basic support for MariaDB 10.</description></item><item><title>Puppy Linux, icanhazip, and tin foil hats</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/09/puppy-linux-icanhazip-and-tin-foil-hats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 04:04:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/09/puppy-linux-icanhazip-and-tin-foil-hats/</guid><description>I figured that the Puppy Linux and icanhazip.com fiasco was over, but I was wrong:
After a quick visit to the forums, I found the debate stirred up again. Various users were wondering if their internet connections were somehow compromised or if a remote American network was somehow spying on their internet traffic. Others wondered if some secretive software was added to the Puppy Linux distribution that was calling out to the site.</description></item><item><title>Be an inspiration, not an impostor</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/04/be-an-inspiration-not-an-impostor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 03:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/04/be-an-inspiration-not-an-impostor/</guid><description>Many of the non-technical posts on the blog are inspired by the comments of others. I stumbled upon this tweet after it was retweeted by someone I follow:
The link in the tweet takes you to a blog post from Erika Owens about impostor syndrome. Erika touches on that uncomfortable feeling that some of us feel when we&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by other people from our field of study or work. These three sentences hit home for me:</description></item><item><title>Hierarchy of DevOps Needs from DevOps Weekly</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/02/hierarchy-of-devops-needs-from-devops-weekly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 02:30:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/02/hierarchy-of-devops-needs-from-devops-weekly/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made posts about the DevOps Weekly mailing list before. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t signed up yet, do so now. You&amp;rsquo;ll thank me later.
Aaron Suggs' Hierarchy of DevOps Needs gives a great summary of the building blocks of a solid development culture and how they relate to one another. I laughed a bit when I saw his pyramid because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many development groups build the pyramid upside down in the past.</description></item><item><title>Learn octal file permissions easily with stat</title><link>https://major.io/2013/12/10/learn-octal-file-permissions-easily-with-stat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 13:41:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/12/10/learn-octal-file-permissions-easily-with-stat/</guid><description>My SANS classmates were learning how to set and recognize file permissions on a Linux server and we realized it would be helpful to display the octal value of the permissions next to the normal rwx display. Fortunately, a quick search revealed that stat could deliver this information:
# stat -c &amp;quot;%a %A %n&amp;quot; /usr/sbin/* | head 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/accessdb 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/acpid 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/addgnupghome 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/addpart 777 lrwxrwxrwx /usr/sbin/adduser 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/agetty 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/alternatives 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/anacron 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/apachectl 755 -rwxr-xr-x /usr/sbin/applygnupgdefaults The first octal digit (for setuid, setgid, and sticky) is left off for any files without those bits set.</description></item><item><title>Speed up your Fedora PXE installations by hosting the stage2 installer locally</title><link>https://major.io/2013/11/03/speed-up-your-fedora-pxe-installations-by-hosting-the-stage2-installer-locally/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 17:04:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/11/03/speed-up-your-fedora-pxe-installations-by-hosting-the-stage2-installer-locally/</guid><description>In my previous post about installing Fedora via PXE, I forgot to mention a big time saver for the installation. A Fedora PXE installation requires a few different things:
initial ramdisk (initrd.img) kernel (vmlinuz) installation repository If you only specify an installation repository, then Anaconda tries to drag down a 214MB squashfs.img file in each installation. You can host this file locally by recreating a portion of a Fedora repo&amp;rsquo;s structure and dropping two files into it.</description></item><item><title>One month using a Linux laptop at work: Back to the Mac</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/22/one-month-using-a-linux-laptop-at-work-back-to-the-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 02:38:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/22/one-month-using-a-linux-laptop-at-work-back-to-the-mac/</guid><description>This post has been a bit delayed, but I want to follow up on the post I wrote last month about moving from OS X to Linux at work. I started out with a Lenovo Thinkpad X1 Carbon along with Fedora 19 and KDE. Although most things went really well, there were a few deal-breakers that sent me back to the Mac.
Just to give you an idea of my daily workflow, much of my day revolved around my calendar and email.</description></item><item><title>Keeping bwm-ng 0.6 functional on Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/19/keeping-bwm-ng-0-6-functional-on-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/19/keeping-bwm-ng-0-6-functional-on-fedora-19/</guid><description>If you run bwm-ng and you&amp;rsquo;ve run a yum upgrade lately on Fedora 19, you have probably seen this:
---&amp;gt; Package libstatgrab.x86_64 0:0.17-4.fc19 will be updated --&amp;gt; Processing Dependency: libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) for package: bwm-ng-0.6-10.fc19.x86_64 --&amp;gt; Finished Dependency Resolution Error: Package: bwm-ng-0.6-10.fc19.x86_64 (@fedora) Requires: libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) Removing: libstatgrab-0.17-4.fc19.x86_64 (@fedora) libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) Updated By: libstatgrab-0.90-1.fc19.x86_64 (updates) ~libstatgrab.so.9()(64bit) You could try using --skip-broken to work around the problem You could try running: rpm -Va --nofiles --nodigest The error message mentions that libstatgrab needs to be updated to version 0.</description></item><item><title>Moving from OS X to Linux: Day One</title><link>https://major.io/2013/08/26/moving-from-os-x-to-linux-day-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 03:05:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/08/26/moving-from-os-x-to-linux-day-one/</guid><description>The thought of using Linux as a manager in a highly Windows- and Mac-centric corporate environment isn&amp;rsquo;t something to be taken lightly. Integrating with Active Directory, wrangling email with Microsoft Exchange, and taming quirky Microsoft office documents can be a challenge even with a well-equipped Mac. I decided to make a change after using a Mac at Rackspace for six years.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get one thing straight: I&amp;rsquo;m not a Windows or Mac basher.</description></item><item><title>PXE boot Fedora 19 using a Mikrotik firewall</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/23/pxe-boot-fedora-19-using-a-mikrotik-firewall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 21:47:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/23/pxe-boot-fedora-19-using-a-mikrotik-firewall/</guid><description>Outside of the RHCA exams, I haven&amp;rsquo;t configured a PXE system for my personal needs. A colleague demoed his PXE setup for me and I was hooked. Once I realized how much time I could save when I&amp;rsquo;m building and tearing down virtual machines, it made complete sense. This post will show you how to configure PXE and tftpd in Mikrotik&amp;rsquo;s RouterOS to boot and install Fedora 19 (as well as provide rescue environments).</description></item><item><title>Come and get your SELinux shirts!</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/18/come-and-get-your-selinux-shirts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 12:14:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/18/come-and-get-your-selinux-shirts/</guid><description>After my podcast interview at the 2013 Red Hat Summit, Dan Walsh posted a photo of himself in the SELinux shirt that I gave him at the Summit:
Needless to say, I was flooded with requests for shirts after that. Someone suggested using the Overpass font and I have new shirts ready for purchase on Spreadshirt.
I set all the prices as low as the vendor will allow and I&amp;rsquo;m not making any profit for each purchase.</description></item><item><title>Confine untrusted users (including your children) with SELinux</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/05/confine-untrusted-users-including-your-children-with-selinux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 18:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/05/confine-untrusted-users-including-your-children-with-selinux/</guid><description>The confined user support in SELinux is handy for ensuring that users aren&amp;rsquo;t able to do something that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. It seems more effective and easier to use than most of the other methods I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. Thanks to Dan for reminding me about this during his SELinux in the Enterprise talk from this year&amp;rsquo;s Red Hat Summit.
There are five main SELinux user types (and a handy chart in the Fedora documentation):</description></item><item><title>My interview on the Dave and Gunnar Show</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/19/my-interview-on-the-dave-and-gunnar-show/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 12:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/19/my-interview-on-the-dave-and-gunnar-show/</guid><description>David Egts and Gunnar Hellekson were kind enough to invite me to participate in their Dave and Gunnar Show podcast during the 2013 Red Hat Summit. We talked about Red Hat Enterprise Linux and my takeaways from the Summit.
The podcast episode [32MB] is about 34 minutes long and my interview starts after the 21 minute mark. I&amp;rsquo;m always nervous when I do these things so you&amp;rsquo;re certainly not allowed to poke fun at my accent.</description></item><item><title>Supermicro X9SCI/X9SCA server does a shutdown rather than a reboot</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/03/supermicro-x9scix9sca-server-does-a-shutdown-rather-than-a-reboot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 14:45:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/03/supermicro-x9scix9sca-server-does-a-shutdown-rather-than-a-reboot/</guid><description>Most of my websites run on a pair of Supermicro servers that I purchased from Silicon Mechanics (and I can&amp;rsquo;t say enough good things about them and their servers). One problem that kept cropping up was that the servers would become unresponsive during a reboot. If I issued the reboot command in Linux, the machine would begin the reboot process, power off, and remain powered off.
Needless to say, this is highly annoying.</description></item><item><title>Installing the Xen hypervisor on Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/02/installing-the-xen-hypervisor-on-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 04:27:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/02/installing-the-xen-hypervisor-on-fedora-19/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while since I last posted about installing Xen on Fedora, so I figured that Fedora 19&amp;rsquo;s beta release was as good a time as any to write a new post. To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get Fedora 19 installed on your favorite hardware (or virtual machine).
Install the Xen hypervisor and tools. Also, ensure that both of the necessary daemons are running on each boot:</description></item></channel></rss>