<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mysqltuner on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/mysqltuner/</link><description>Recent content in mysqltuner on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:30:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/mysqltuner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MySQLTuner v1.3.0</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/21/mysqltuner-v1-3-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/21/mysqltuner-v1-3-0/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been three long years since the last MySQLTuner release but you&amp;rsquo;ll now find version 1.3.0 available on GitHub. You can get it from the git repository or via these extremely simple methods:
wget -O mysqltuner.pl mysqltuner.pl wget --trust-server-names mysqltuner.pl There are a bunch of new features and fixes that you can find in the list of commits from today (2014-02-21). Some of the bigger adjustments include:
Basic support for MariaDB 10.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner mentioned at the O’Reilly MySQL Conference</title><link>https://major.io/2011/04/15/mysqltuner-mentioned-at-the-oreilly-mysql-conference/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 01:56:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/04/15/mysqltuner-mentioned-at-the-oreilly-mysql-conference/</guid><description>If you push play, the video should scoot out to about the 14m40s mark where MySQLTuner appears on one of the slides. Thanks to Trent Hornibrook for letting me know!</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner 1.0.0 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/12/01/mysqltuner-100-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 00:31:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/12/01/mysqltuner-100-is-now-available/</guid><description>It has finally arrived. MySQLTuner 1.0.0 is now available for download. Major improvements include full support for MySQL 5.1 and Solaris. You can review other changes in the changelog.
As always, I&amp;rsquo;d like to personally thank everyone who has made this release possible. Your efforts have provided benefits from MySQL users worldwide, and they have shown me how rewarding it is to maintain open source software.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner 0.9.9 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/07/mysqltuner-099-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 02:05:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/07/mysqltuner-099-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner 0.9.9 is now available for download. There&amp;rsquo;s a new wiki for the script at wiki.mysqltuner.com. The new wiki contains links to downloads, changelogs, and other details.
If you want to know when the latest releases are available, there are multiple options:
Follow RackerHacker on Twitter Sign up for the MySQLTuner mailing list Use the --checkversion option when you run the script</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner 0.9.8 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/07/21/mysqltuner-098-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 17:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/07/21/mysqltuner-098-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner 0.9.8 is now available for download and it is full of new changes! So far, MySQLTuner has been downloaded almost 24,000 times. Thanks for making it so popular.
Easy download!
You can download it simply by running wget mysqltuner.pl. You will automatically be redirected to the script.
Access servers remotely
If you have multiple servers that you need to tune and monitor, simply download MySQLTuner onto one machine. You can run it against other servers by specifying a hostname, port, and login credentials.</description></item><item><title>Calling all creative types: I need a slogan</title><link>https://major.io/2008/07/15/calling-all-creative-types-i-need-a-slogan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/07/15/calling-all-creative-types-i-need-a-slogan/</guid><description>As some of you may know, MySQLTuner is one of my favorite projects. It&amp;rsquo;s approaching the 1.0 release and I feel like celebrating. I thought about putting together some T-shirts (because as a nerd, I enjoy the occasional techy T-shirt), but I can&amp;rsquo;t come up with a good slogan.
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of some pretty hilarious slogans for database-related activities, like &amp;ldquo;DBA&amp;rsquo;s know how to take dumps&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t overflow my buffer&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to come up with some good ones for MySQLTuner.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner is now a Fedora 9 package!</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/27/mysqltuner-is-now-a-fedora-9-package/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 17:16:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/27/mysqltuner-is-now-a-fedora-9-package/</guid><description>Thanks to some work started by Ville Skyttä, MySQLTuner is now included in Fedora 9 repositories:
# cat /etc/fedora-release Fedora release 9 (Sulphur) # yum info mysqltuner Loaded plugins: fastestmirror, priorities, refresh-packagekit Loading mirror speeds from cached hostfile * updates: mirrors.usc.edu * fedora: mirror.unl.edu * livna: mirrors.tummy.com Available Packages Name : mysqltuner Arch : noarch Version : 0.9.1 Release : 4 Size : 11 k Repo : updates Summary : MySQL high performance tuning script URL : http://mysqltuner.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner 0.9.1 available for Mandriva users</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/21/mysqltuner-091-available-for-mandriva-users/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2008 02:54:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/21/mysqltuner-091-available-for-mandriva-users/</guid><description>Thanks to some hard work from Oden Eriksson and Frederik Himpe, MySQLTuner 0.9.1 is available in a Mandriva package.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v0.9.1 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/18/mysqltuner-v091-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 02:53:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/18/mysqltuner-v091-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner v0.9.1 is now available! This long-awaited update includes bug fixes, feature enhancements, and compatibility improvements.
MySQLTuner now checks for fragmented tables
When deletes or updates are made on tables, MySQL will often leave holes behind that it hopes to fill in later. If the size and quantity keep climbing, the holes can cause performance degradation for writes and reads. Fragmentation can be corrected with OPTIMIZE TABLE, and the script recommends it if needed.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v0.9.0 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/04/06/mysqltuner-v090-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/04/06/mysqltuner-v090-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner v0.9.0 is now available. There is a bug fix and also a new feature!
Fixed a bug in the enumeration/sizing of tables in MySQL 5
In MySQL 5 on some distributions, a NULL is returned for the storage engine and data length. Luuk Vosslamber quickly e-mailed me about the bug yesterday and it has been fixed.
MySQLTuner version checking
MySQLTuner will now check to see if a new version is available when the script runs.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v0.8.9 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/04/05/mysqltuner-v089-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/04/05/mysqltuner-v089-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner v0.8.9 is now available. There are a few bug fixes, performance improvements, and readability adjustments.
Table enumeration and sizing can now be skipped
I&amp;rsquo;ve received reports that MySQLTuner will stall while enumerating tables on servers that contain a lot of tables or a lot of large tables. You can now use the --skipsize option to skip over the table enumeration process and let the script finish. However, you will not be able to receive some recommendations since the script was unable to determine which storage engines are enabled.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v0.8.6 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/02/26/mysqltuner-v086-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 03:24:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/02/26/mysqltuner-v086-is-now-available/</guid><description>Version 0.8.6 of MySQLTuner is now available. It contains a few bug fixes and readability improvements:
Newlines are placed between the sections for increased readability
Each section now contains extra lines to set the sections apart. It makes the output a little longer, but easier to read as well.
Storage engine status color bug
Even if the -nocolor option was passed, the storage engine statuses were being shown in color.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner now has a mailing list</title><link>https://major.io/2008/02/19/mysqltuner-now-has-a-mailing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 02:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/02/19/mysqltuner-now-has-a-mailing-list/</guid><description>Due to popular demand, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a mailing list for MySQLTuner. It will be a low-traffic list consisting of new version announcements and bug fixes.
If you want to subscribe, simply send an e-mail with SUBSCRIBE in the subject line to mysqltuner-announce-request@mysqltuner.com. Be sure to add mysqltuner-announce@mysqltuner.com to your mail provider&amp;rsquo;s whitelist.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v0.8.5 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/02/11/mysqltuner-v085-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 18:02:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/02/11/mysqltuner-v085-is-now-available/</guid><description>To get the latest copy, head over to the download page! Here&amp;rsquo;s the changes from 0.8.0 to 0.8.5 for MySQLTuner:
Fixed a copy/paste bug
There was a bug in 0.8.0 that displayed &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; in red rather than showing &amp;ldquo;!!&amp;rdquo;. It affected the informational &amp;ldquo;-&amp;rdquo; outputs as well. Thanks to Nils Breunese for pointing out that confusing bug!
Fixed a data length calculation bug with MySQL 4.0
If the script was run against MySQL 4.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v0.8.0 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/31/mysqltuner-v080-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 01:01:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/31/mysqltuner-v080-is-now-available/</guid><description>Thanks to an e-mail from Joe Calderon, I&amp;rsquo;ve corrected a MySQLTuner bug where indexes were not being calculated properly when symbolic links are used. It was a quick fix, and the new version is now available for download.
Also, MySQLTuner now has a standardized versioning scheme. I&amp;rsquo;m starting at 0.8.0 since I&amp;rsquo;m close to a completely stable release. There&amp;rsquo;s still a few kinks when working with MySQL cluster nodes, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to work that out soon.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner reaches 5,000 downloads!</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/25/mysqltuner-reaches-5000-downloads/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 17:01:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/25/mysqltuner-reaches-5000-downloads/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just reviewed the stats for MySQLTuner, and it crossed the 5,000 download mark last week! Thanks to all of you who have helped me make it a successful tool for MySQL server optimization.
With that said - how can MySQLTuner be improved to help you? Please let me know, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get started on those features!</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner Revision 29 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/15/mysqltuner-revision-29-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 04:13:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/15/mysqltuner-revision-29-is-now-available/</guid><description>A new version of MySQLTuner was released tonight to correct some bugs found within revision 26. As usual, you can get a new copy from the MySQLTuner site.
Here are the new features:
» Storage engine counts are shown
In addition to the actual size of the tables stored under each storage engine, there is a table count as well. The table count reflects the number of tables that exist on the server which use the specified storage engine.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner Revision 26 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/15/mysqltuner-revision-26-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/15/mysqltuner-revision-26-is-now-available/</guid><description>As some subversion users may have noticed, revision 23 of MySQLTuner was released quietly on Sunday. Thanks to Mike Jackson, a few bugs from revision 23 were smashed today and revision 26 was released this morning.
To pick up the new script, visit the MySQLTuner site.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the new features:
» Shows banner of enabled and disabled storage engines
Near the top of the MySQLTuner output, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a line like this:</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner is now a Debian package</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/08/mysqltuner-is-now-a-debian-package/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 16:37:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/08/mysqltuner-is-now-a-debian-package/</guid><description>I just received a note yesterday that MySQLTuner was added to Debian&amp;rsquo;s package list for the sid release. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank Marcela Tiznado for putting the package together and submitting it!
You can read more about the package.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner Revision 22 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2007/12/03/mysqltuner-revision-22-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 18:09:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/12/03/mysqltuner-revision-22-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner revision 22 is available today. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the notable fixes and changes:
» Changed how indexes are calculated on MySQL 5
Thanks to Jon Hinds, I found that when running the tuning script against MySQL 5, the following SQL statement caused MySQL to open all of the tables on the server, which of course caused the table cache hit rate to plummet each time the script is run:</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner is now a Mandriva Linux package!</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/30/mysqltuner-is-now-a-mandriva-linux-package/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 18:49:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/30/mysqltuner-is-now-a-mandriva-linux-package/</guid><description>Thanks to Oden Eriksson at Mandriva, MySQLTuner is now packaged into an RPM for easier installations on Mandriva Linux.
More data can be found in the Mandriva Linux Archives.
As an aside, I find it quite interesting that the first package for my script popped up on Mandriva. My first adventure into Linux was with Mandrake many years ago.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner Revision 20 is available</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/06/mysqltuner-revision-20-is-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 23:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/06/mysqltuner-revision-20-is-available/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve updated MySQLTuner to revision 20 tonight, and it has the following improvements:
Added NetBSD support (thanks to Dave Burgess)
Switched username/password prompts to STDERR so they won&amp;rsquo;t appear in printouts
Downloads are available, or you can do a new subversion checkout.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner Revision 19 is available</title><link>https://major.io/2007/10/15/mysqltuner-revision-19-is-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 01:54:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/10/15/mysqltuner-revision-19-is-available/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve revamped a few of the recommendations in MySQLTuner, and revision 19 is now available tonight! Here&amp;rsquo;s the main changes:
Adjusted infoprint to use asterisks (cosmetic)
Per-thread/global buffer counts are now displayed
Key buffer increases are only recommended if the buffer is smaller than total indexes and hit rate is &amp;lt; 95% * Dropped max_seeks_for_key checks * Temporary table size increases are not recommended over 256M * Aborted connection calculation and recommendation adjustments You can download the latest copy on the MySQLTuner page, and you can get diffs for the new version as well.</description></item></channel></rss>