<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chrome on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/chrome/</link><description>Recent content in chrome on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:31:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/chrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recovering deleted Chrome bookmarks on Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2016/02/26/recovering-deleted-chrome-bookmarks-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:31:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/02/26/recovering-deleted-chrome-bookmarks-on-linux/</guid><description>After getting a bit overzealous with cleaning up bookmarks in Chrome, I discovered that I deleted a helpful Gerrit filter for OpenStack reviews. I worked hard to create the filter and I definitely needed it back.
Chrome keeps a file called Bookmarks.bak inside its configuration directory. You can find this file here:
/home/[username]/.config/google-chrome/Default/Bookmarks.bak # If using Chrome stable /home/[username]/.config/google-chrome-beta/Default/Bookmarks.bak # If using Chrome beta The file is stored in JSON format.</description></item><item><title>Chrome 43 stuck in HiDPI mode</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/10/chrome-43-stuck-in-hidpi-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 12:36:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/10/chrome-43-stuck-in-hidpi-mode/</guid><description>I ran some package updates last night and ended up with a new version of Google Chrome from the stable branch. After restarting Chrome, everything in the interface was huge. The icons in the bookmark bar, the text, the padding - all of it looked enormous.
After a little searching, I found a helpful line in the ArchLinux HiDPI documentation:
Full HiDPI support in Chrome is now available in the main branch google-chromeAUR as of version 43.</description></item><item><title>Tweetdeck’s Chrome notifications stopped working</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/08/tweetdecks-chrome-notifications-stopped-working/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 13:55:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/08/tweetdecks-chrome-notifications-stopped-working/</guid><description>With the last few weeks, I noticed that Tweetdeck&amp;rsquo;s notifications weren&amp;rsquo;t showing up in Chrome any longer. I double-checked all of the Tweetdeck settings and notifications were indeed enabled. However, I found that Tweetdeck wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed to send notifications when I checked in my Chrome settings.
Check your settings To check these for yourself, hop into Chrome&amp;rsquo;s content settings. Scroll down to Notifications and click Manage Exceptions. In my case, https://tweetdeck.</description></item><item><title>Using play/pause buttons in Chrome with GNOME 3</title><link>https://major.io/2015/02/20/using-playpause-buttons-in-chrome-with-gnome-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 14:21:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/02/20/using-playpause-buttons-in-chrome-with-gnome-3/</guid><description>I wrote a post last summer about preventing Chrome from stealing the media buttons (like play, pause, previous track and next track) from OS X. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m using Linux regularly and I fell in love with Google Play Music All Access, I found that GNOME was stealing the media keys from Chrome.
The fix is quite simple. Press the SUPER key (Windows key or Mac Command key), type settings, and press enter.</description></item><item><title>Play/pause button stopped working in OS X Mavericks</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/30/playpause-button-stopped-working-in-os-x-mavericks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 14:31:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/30/playpause-button-stopped-working-in-os-x-mavericks/</guid><description>My play/pause button mysteriously stopped working in iTunes and VLC mysteriously this week on my laptop. It affected the previous track and next track buttons as well. It turns out that my Google Music extension in Chrome stole the keyboard bindings after the extension updated this week.
If your buttons stopped working as well, follow these steps to check your keyboard shortcuts in Chrome:
Choose Preferences in the Chrome menu in the menu bar Click Extensions in the left sidebar Scroll all the way to the bottom of the page Click Keyboard Shortcuts Look at the key bindings in the Google Play Music section Your shortcuts might look like the ones shown here in an Apple support forum.</description></item></channel></rss>