<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>supermicro on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/supermicro/</link><description>Recent content in supermicro on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:46:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/supermicro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tinkering with systemd’s predictable network names</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/20/tinkering-with-systemds-predictable-network-names/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:46:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/20/tinkering-with-systemds-predictable-network-names/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about predictable network names (and seemingly unpredictable ones) on the blog before, but some readers asked me how they could alter the network naming to fit a particular situation. Oddly enough, my Supermicro 5028D-T4NT has a problem with predictable names and it&amp;rsquo;s a great example to use here.
The problem There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of detail in my post about the Supermicro 5028D-T4NT, but the basic gist is that something within the firmware is causing the all of the network cards in the server to show up as onboard.</description></item><item><title>Customizing systemd’s network device names</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/28/customizing-systemds-network-device-names/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 02:08:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/28/customizing-systemds-network-device-names/</guid><description>Earlier today, I wrote a post about my first thoughts on the Supermicro 5028D-T4NT server. The 10Gb interfaces on the server came up with the names eth0 and eth1. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I expected. There&amp;rsquo;s tons of detail on the problem in the blog post as well as the Github issue.
Kay Sievers gave a hint about how to adjust the interfacing naming in a more granular way than simply disabling the predictable network names.</description></item><item><title>First thoughts: Linux on the Supermicro 5028D-TN4T</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/28/first-thoughts-linux-on-the-supermicro-5028d-t4nt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 12:55:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/28/first-thoughts-linux-on-the-supermicro-5028d-t4nt/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently moved over to Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s OpenStack Private Cloud team and the role is full of some great challenges. One of those challenges was figuring out a home lab for testing.
The search My first idea was to pick up some lower-power machines that would give me some infrastructure at a low price with a low power bill as well. I found some Dell Optiplex 3020&amp;rsquo;s on Newegg with Haswell i3&amp;rsquo;s that came in at a good price point.</description></item></channel></rss>