<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wireless on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/wireless/</link><description>Recent content in wireless on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:14:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/wireless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Restoring wireless and Bluetooth state after reboot in Fedora 22</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/19/restoring-wireless-and-bluetooth-state-after-reboot-in-fedora-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/19/restoring-wireless-and-bluetooth-state-after-reboot-in-fedora-22/</guid><description>My upgrade to Fedora 22 on the ThinkPad X1 Carbon was fairly uneventful and the hiccups were minor. One of the more annoying items that I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with for quite some time is how to boot up with the wireless LAN and Bluetooth disabled by default. Restoring wireless and Bluetooth state between reboots is normally handled quite well in Fedora.
In Fedora 21, NetworkManager saved my settings between reboots. For example, if I shut down with wifi off and Bluetooth on, the laptop would boot up later with wifi off and Bluetooth on.</description></item><item><title>Getting online with a CradlePoint PHS-300 and an AT&amp;T USBConnect Mercury</title><link>https://major.io/2011/12/16/getting-online-with-a-cradlepoint-phs-300-and-an-att-usbconnect-mercury/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 07:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/12/16/getting-online-with-a-cradlepoint-phs-300-and-an-att-usbconnect-mercury/</guid><description>Anyone who has used a 3G ExpressCard or USB stick knows how handy they can be when you need internet access away from home (and away from Wi-Fi). I&amp;rsquo;ve run into some situations recently where I needed to share my 3G connection with more than one device without using internet sharing on my MacBook Pro.
That led me to pick up a CradlePoint PHS-300 (discontinued by the manufacturer, but available from Amazon for about $35).</description></item></channel></rss>