<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mail on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/mail/</link><description>Recent content in mail on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 12:54:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/mail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thunderbird changes fonts in some messages, not all</title><link>https://major.io/2017/08/02/thunderbird-changes-fonts-messages-not/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 12:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/08/02/thunderbird-changes-fonts-messages-not/</guid><description>Thunderbird is a great choice for a mail client on Linux systems if you prefer a GUI, but I had some problems with fonts in the most recent releases. The monospace font used for plain text messages was difficult to read.
I opened Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Display and clicked Advanced to the right of Fonts &amp;amp; Colors. The default font for monospace text was &amp;ldquo;Monospace&amp;rdquo;, and that one isn&amp;rsquo;t terribly attractive.</description></item><item><title>Thunderbird opens multiple windows</title><link>https://major.io/2016/04/20/thunderbird-opens-multiple-windows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 13:31:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/04/20/thunderbird-opens-multiple-windows/</guid><description>When I started Thunderbird today, it opened three windows. Each window was identical. I closed two of them and then quit Thunderbird.
As soon as I started Thunderbird, I had three windows again.
I found a Mozilla bug report from 2015 that had some tips for getting the additional windows closed.
Choose one of the open Thunderbird windows and select Close from the File menu. Do not use ALT-F4 or CTRL-W to close the window.</description></item><item><title>Custom keyboard shortcuts for Evolution in GNOME</title><link>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 05:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Thunderbird for years, but it lacks features in some critical areas. For example, I need Microsoft Exchange and Google Apps connectivity for my mail and contacts, but Thunderbird needs some extensions to make that connectivity easier. There are some great extensions available, but they lack polish since they&amp;rsquo;re not part of the core product.
My muscle memory for keyboard shortcuts in Thunderbird left me fumbling in Evolution.</description></item><item><title>Fixing broken DNS lookups in spamassassin</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/20/fixing-broken-dns-lookups-in-spamassassin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 13:20:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/20/fixing-broken-dns-lookups-in-spamassassin/</guid><description>I talked about the joys of running my own mail server last week only to find that my mail server was broken yesterday. Spamassassin stopped doing DNS lookups for RBL and SPF checks.
I had one of these moments:
My logs looked like this:
plugin: eval failed: available_nameservers: No DNS servers available! plugin: eval failed: available_nameservers: No DNS servers available! rules: failed to run NO_DNS_FOR_FROM RBL test, skipping: (available_nameservers: [.</description></item><item><title>Show originating IP address in Apple Mail</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/18/show-originating-ip-address-in-apple-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 14:20:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/18/show-originating-ip-address-in-apple-mail/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received some very sophisticated phishing emails lately and I was showing some of them to my coworkers. One of my coworkers noticed that my Apple Mail client displays the X-Originating-IP header for all of the emails I receive.
You can enter that IP into a whois search and get a better idea of who sent you the message without diving into the headers. If someone that regularly exchanges email with me suddenly has an originating IP in another country that would be unusual for them to travel to, I can approach the message with more caution.</description></item><item><title>Remove sensitive information from email headers with postfix</title><link>https://major.io/2013/04/14/remove-sensitive-information-from-email-headers-with-postfix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 02:59:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/04/14/remove-sensitive-information-from-email-headers-with-postfix/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of moving back to a postfix/dovecot setup for hosting my own mail and I wanted a way to remove the more sensitive email headers that are normally generated when I send mail. My goal is to hide the originating IP address of my mail as well as my mail client type and version.
To get started, make a small file with regular expressions in /etc/postfix/header_checks:
/^Received:.*with ESMTPSA/ IGNORE /^X-Originating-IP:/ IGNORE /^X-Mailer:/ IGNORE /^Mime-Version:/ IGNORE The &amp;ldquo;ESMTPSA&amp;rdquo; match works for me because I only send email via port 465.</description></item><item><title>SELinux and .forward files</title><link>https://major.io/2012/01/02/selinux-and-forward-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 22:44:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/01/02/selinux-and-forward-files/</guid><description>If you want to forward e-mail from root to another user, you can usually place a .forward file in root&amp;rsquo;s home directory and your mail server will take care of the rest:
/root/.forward With SELinux, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up getting an AVC denial each time your mail server tries to read the contents of the .forward file:
type=AVC msg=audit(1325543823.787:7416): avc: denied { open } for pid=9850 comm=&amp;quot;local&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;.forward&amp;quot; dev=md0 ino=17694734 scontext=system_u:system_r:postfix_local_t:s0 tcontext=unconfined_u:object_r:admin_home_t:s0 tclass=file The reason is that your .</description></item><item><title>Deleting all e-mail messages in your inbox with mutt</title><link>https://major.io/2009/06/19/deleting-all-e-mail-messages-in-your-inbox-with-mutt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 17:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/06/19/deleting-all-e-mail-messages-in-your-inbox-with-mutt/</guid><description>Occasionally, I&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a mailbox full of random data, alerts, or other useless things. If you have SSH access to the server, you can always clear out your mail spool, but if you connect to an IMAP server, you can use mutt to do the same thing.
First, use mutt to connect to your server remotely (via IMAP over SSL in this example):
mutt -f imaps://mail.yourdomain.com/ Once you&amp;rsquo;ve connected and logged in, press SHIFT-D (uppercase d).</description></item><item><title>Plesk: Upgrade to 8.4 causes “no such user” error in maillog</title><link>https://major.io/2008/11/06/plesk-upgrade-to-84-causes-no-such-user-error-in-maillog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:04:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/11/06/plesk-upgrade-to-84-causes-no-such-user-error-in-maillog/</guid><description>If you have a Plesk server where short mail names are enabled, upgrading to Plesk 8.4 can cause some issues. Valid logins may be rejected, and they&amp;rsquo;ll appear in your /usr/local/psa/var/log/maillog as &amp;ldquo;no such user&amp;rdquo;. You can correct the issue by switching to long mail names (click Server -&amp;gt; Mail in Plesk), or you can run a shell script provided by Parallels.
For further details, refer to the Plesk KB article &amp;ldquo;Mail users cannot get or send mail after upgrade to Plesk 8.</description></item><item><title>Forcing qmail to process e-mail in the queue</title><link>https://major.io/2008/05/02/forcing-qmail-to-process-e-mail-in-the-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 17:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/05/02/forcing-qmail-to-process-e-mail-in-the-queue/</guid><description>Normally, qmail will be able to process the mail queue without any interaction from the system administrator, however, if you want to force it to process everything that is in the queue right now, you can do so:
kill -ALRM `pgrep qmail-send` If for some peculiar reason you don&amp;rsquo;t have pgrep on your server, you can go about it a slightly different way:
kill -ALRM `ps ax | grep qmail-send | grep -v grep | awk '{print $1}'` Your logs should begin filling up with data about e-mails rolling through the queue.</description></item><item><title>mchk: Unable to initialize quota settings for someuser@somedomain.com</title><link>https://major.io/2008/04/14/mchk-unable-to-initialize-quota-settings-for-someusersomedomaincom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/04/14/mchk-unable-to-initialize-quota-settings-for-someusersomedomaincom/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working in Plesk and you receive this error:
mchk: Unable to initialize quota settings for someuser@somedomain.com
Run this command to fix the issue, but be patient:
find /var/qmail/mailnames -type d -name '.*' ! -name '.spamassassin' -ls -exec touch '{}'/maildirfolder \; -exec chown popuser:popuser '{}'/maildirfolder \; Thanks to Mike Jackson for this one.</description></item><item><title>Setting the maximum mail size in qmail</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/24/setting-the-maximum-mail-size-in-qmail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 18:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/24/setting-the-maximum-mail-size-in-qmail/</guid><description>On a Plesk server, the maximum size for an individual e-mail sent through qmail is unlimited. You can limit this size by adding a number to the /var/qmail/control/databytes file.
If you wanted to limit this to something like 10MB, you can just run the following command:
echo &amp;quot;10485760&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /var/qmail/control/databytes This will limit the size of messages (including attachments) to 10MB as a maximum.</description></item><item><title>Reduce iowait in Plesk: put qmail’s queue on a ramdisk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/14/reduce-iowait-in-plesk-put-qmails-queue-on-a-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 18:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/14/reduce-iowait-in-plesk-put-qmails-queue-on-a-ramdisk/</guid><description>I really dislike qmail. But, since I use Plesk, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck with it. However, I found a way to improve it&amp;rsquo;s awful mail queue performance by putting the mail queue onto a ramdisk. This is actually pretty darned easy to do.
First, toss a line like this into your /etc/fstab:
none /mailqueue tmpfs defaults,size=100m,nr_inodes=999k,mode=775 0 0 This will make a 100MB ramdisk on /mailqueue. Now, just symlink /var/qmail/mqueue to /mailqueue and move your e-mail over:</description></item><item><title>sendmail: savemail panic</title><link>https://major.io/2008/02/18/sendmail-savemail-panic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 18:56:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/02/18/sendmail-savemail-panic/</guid><description>If you see a large mail queue and your system&amp;rsquo;s I/O is increasing, you may find messages like these in your syslog:
Losing q5/qfg9N5EwE3004499: savemail panic&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; SYSERR(root): savemail: cannot save rejected email anywhere
In this situation, there&amp;rsquo;s some reason why sendmail cannot deliver e-mail to the postmaster address. There&amp;rsquo;s a few issues that can create this problem:
Missing postmaster alias in /etc/aliases Hard disk is full The mail spool for the postmaster has the wrong ownership The mbox file for the postmaster is over 2GB and procmail can&amp;rsquo;t deliver the e-mail First, correct the situation that is preventing sendmail from delivering the e-mail to the postmaster user.</description></item><item><title>High iowait on RHEL 4 with Plesk and SpamAssassin</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/31/high-iowait-on-rhel-4-with-plesk-and-spamassassin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 18:38:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/31/high-iowait-on-rhel-4-with-plesk-and-spamassassin/</guid><description>One of my biggest complaints on RHEL 4 is the large resource usage by the version of SpamAssassin that is installed. When it runs, it uses a ton of CPU time and causes a lot of disk I/O as well. When running top, you may see multiple spamd processes. For a high-volume e-mail server (like the one I administer), this is simply unacceptable.
I decided to do something about it, and here are the steps:</description></item><item><title>Can’t enable DNSBL/RBL in Plesk because it’s greyed out</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/25/cant-enable-dnsblrbl-in-plesk-because-its-greyed-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 17:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/25/cant-enable-dnsblrbl-in-plesk-because-its-greyed-out/</guid><description>If you have a new Plesk installation and the following option is greyed out in Server -&amp;gt; Mail:
Switch on spam protection based on DNS blackhole lists
Just install the following RPM from Plesk:
psa-qmail-rblsmtpd</description></item><item><title>qmail: This message is looping: it already has my Delivered-To line</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/23/qmail-this-message-is-looping-it-already-has-my-delivered-to-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/23/qmail-this-message-is-looping-it-already-has-my-delivered-to-line/</guid><description>I stumbled upon this peculiar bounce message recently while working on a server:
Hi. This is the qmail-send program at yourmailserver.com. I'm afraid I wasn't able to deliver your message to the following addresses. This is a permanent error; I've given up. Sorry it didn't work out. &amp;lt;user1@domain.com&amp;gt;: This message is looping: it already has my Delivered-To line. (#5.4.6) --- Below this line is a copy of the message.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; Return-Path: &amp;lt;remoteuser@otherdomain.</description></item><item><title>Dovecot: libsepol.so.1: failed to map segment from shared object: Cannot allocate memory</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/22/dovecot-libsepolso1-failed-to-map-segment-from-shared-object-cannot-allocate-memory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 18:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/22/dovecot-libsepolso1-failed-to-map-segment-from-shared-object-cannot-allocate-memory/</guid><description>You may catch this error when you attempt to start dovecot on a Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.1 system with the 64-bit architecture:
dovecot: imap-login: imap-login: error while loading shared libraries: libsepol.so.1: failed to map segment from shared object: Cannot allocate memory dovecot: pop3-login: pop3-login: error while loading shared libraries: libsepol.so.1: failed to map segment from shared object: Cannot allocate memory If you start dovecot, the main dovecot daemon will run with one auth child process, but there will be no POP/IMAP processes started.</description></item><item><title>Removing news feeds in Horde</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/21/removing-news-feeds-in-horde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 18:36:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/21/removing-news-feeds-in-horde/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve used newer versions of Horde with Plesk, you have probably noticed the news feed that runs down the left side of the screen. Depending on the types of e-mails you receive, you may get some pretty odd news popping up on the screen.
Luckily, you can remove the news feeds pretty easily. Open the following file in your favorite text editor:
/usr/share/psa-horde/templates/portal/sidebar.inc
Once the file is open, drop down to line 102 and comment out the entire if() statement (lines 102-117).</description></item><item><title>Plesk and qmail: 421 temporary envelope failure (#4.3.0)</title><link>https://major.io/2007/12/04/plesk-and-qmail-421-temporary-envelope-failure-430/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 18:21:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/12/04/plesk-and-qmail-421-temporary-envelope-failure-430/</guid><description>I stumbled upon a server running Plesk 8.2.1 where a certain user could not receive e-mail. I sent an e-mail to the user from my mail client, and I never saw it enter the user&amp;rsquo;s mailbox. It didn&amp;rsquo;t even appear in the logs.
After checking the usual suspects, like MX records, mail account configuration, and firewalls, I was unable to find out why it was occurring. Even after a run of mchk, the emails would not be delivered.</description></item><item><title>Sort e-mail in Plesk with procmail</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/27/sort-e-mail-in-plesk-with-procmail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 18:27:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/27/sort-e-mail-in-plesk-with-procmail/</guid><description>One of my biggest beefs with Plesk&amp;rsquo;s e-mail handling is the lack of server-side filtering. Plesk will only allow you to throw away e-mails marked as spam, but this won&amp;rsquo;t work for me since SpamAssassin marks some mails as spam that actually aren&amp;rsquo;t. If you set up filters in SquirrelMail or Horde, the filters will only work if you always log into the webmail interface to snag your e-mail.
Luckily, you can do some fancy work with procmail to have the filtering done server-side.</description></item><item><title>clamdscan: corrupt or unknown clamd scanner error or memory/resource/perms problem</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/16/clamdscan-corrupt-or-unknown-clamd-scanner-error-or-memoryresourceperms-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 18:11:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/16/clamdscan-corrupt-or-unknown-clamd-scanner-error-or-memoryresourceperms-problem/</guid><description>A few days ago, I stumbled upon a server running qmail with qmail-scanner. The server was throwing out this error when a user on the server attempted to send an e-mail to someone else:
451 qq temporary problem (#4.3.0)
The one thing I love about qmail is its extremely descriptive error messages. Did I say descriptive? I meant cryptic.
Luckily, clamdscan was a bit more chatty in the general system logs:</description></item><item><title>Enabling Dr. Web virus scanning for new accounts</title><link>https://major.io/2007/10/12/enabling-dr-web-virus-scanning-for-new-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/10/12/enabling-dr-web-virus-scanning-for-new-accounts/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re using Plesk 8.0 or later, you can set up Dr. Web to be enabled for all new mail accounts. To do this, you have to create an event handler.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the steps you will need:
» Log into Plesk
» Click &amp;ldquo;Server&amp;rdquo;
» Click &amp;ldquo;Event Manager&amp;rdquo;
» Choose &amp;ldquo;Mail Name Created&amp;rdquo; next to &amp;ldquo;Event&amp;rdquo;
» In the command area, enter /usr/local/psa/bin/mail.sh --update $NEW_MAILNAME -antivirus inout
» Click &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Dovecot: mbox: Can’t create root IMAP folder</title><link>https://major.io/2007/10/09/dovecot-mbox-cant-create-root-imap-folder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 01:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/10/09/dovecot-mbox-cant-create-root-imap-folder/</guid><description>In some situations with dovecot running on your server, you may receive a message from your e-mail client stating that the &amp;ldquo;connection was interrupted with your mail server&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;login process failed&amp;rdquo;. This may happen even if you&amp;rsquo;ve created the e-mail account, created the mail spool, and set a password for the user.
If you check your /var/log/maillog, you will generally find errors like these:
Oct 7 09:37:45 mailserver pop3-login: Login: newuser [111.</description></item><item><title>Plesk: Error opening /var/lib/squirrelmail/prefs/default_pref</title><link>https://major.io/2007/10/08/plesk-error-opening-varlibsquirrelmailprefsdefault_pref/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 00:44:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/10/08/plesk-error-opening-varlibsquirrelmailprefsdefault_pref/</guid><description>On brand new Plesk 8.2.x installations or on servers that have been upgraded to Plesk 8.2.x, you might run into this error when you attempt to log into squirrelmail after it was installed via RPM:
Error opening /var/lib/squirrelmail/prefs/default_pref Could not create initial preference file! /var/lib/squirrelmail/prefs/ should be writable by user apache Please contact your system administrator and report this error. No matter what you do to the /var/lib/squirrelmail/prefs/default_pref file, even if you chmod 777 the file, you will still get the error.</description></item></channel></rss>