<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fun on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/fun/</link><description>Recent content in fun on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 03:13:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New icanhaz features: reverse DNS and traceroutes</title><link>https://major.io/2013/03/16/new-icanhaz-features-reverse-dns-and-traceroutes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 03:13:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/03/16/new-icanhaz-features-reverse-dns-and-traceroutes/</guid><description>After adding some upgrades for icanhazip.com, I wanted to go a bit further. Adding reverse DNS (PTR) lookups and traceroutes seemed like a decent idea!
Want to beta test some new features on icanhazptr.com and icanhaztrace.com? Give them a try!
Getting your reverse DNS entry is easy:
$ curl -4 icanhazptr.com ord.icanhazip.com $ curl -6 icanhazptr.com ord.icanhazip.com Traceroutes are straightforward as well:
$ curl -4 icanhaztrace.com traceroute to 166.78.118.193 (166.78.118.193), 30 hops max, 60 byte packets 1 212.</description></item><item><title>Five years of rackerhacker.com</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</guid><description>Today marks the fifth year that this blog has existed on the internet. I bought the domain on February 14th, 2007 and tossed together a quick WordPress installation (I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember the version now!) to hold my notes that I was gathering at work.
Rackspace as an entry-level Linux system administrator. The abrupt change from &amp;ldquo;top dog at the startup&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;wow, I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Linux&amp;rdquo; caught me by surprise and I was trying to stuff as much knowledge into my brain as quickly as I could.</description></item><item><title>You might see me on CNN Money soon</title><link>https://major.io/2011/09/02/you-might-see-me-on-cnn-money-soon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 15:40:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/09/02/you-might-see-me-on-cnn-money-soon/</guid><description>A videographer from CNN Money stopped by the office today to ask about what makes Rackspace a unique place to work. As soon as we got started, everyone started to make as many distractions as they could to crack me up. Very few succeeded. ;-)
Thanks to @pinojo for snapping the photo.</description></item><item><title>Xen Summit 2011: My Takeways</title><link>https://major.io/2011/08/08/xen-summit-2011-my-takeways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/08/08/xen-summit-2011-my-takeways/</guid><description>Quite a few people who couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to Xen Summit 2011 this year asked me to write a post summarizing my takeaways from the event. I&amp;rsquo;m not generally one to back down from peer pressure, so read on if you&amp;rsquo;re interested about the discussions at this year&amp;rsquo;s Summit.
The feeling I had at last year&amp;rsquo;s summit is that Xen was on the verge of losing traction in the market. Very few distributions still had Xen support going forward and much of the discussion was around the lack of dom0 support in upstream Linux kernels.</description></item><item><title>Taking a short posting break</title><link>https://major.io/2008/05/08/taking-a-short-posting-break/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 23:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/05/08/taking-a-short-posting-break/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a short break from posting, but I should be back underway within week! Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m working on during the break:
MySQLTuner - Thank you for all of the e-mails with suggestions, patches and complaints. The 1.0 version of MySQLTuner is in the works and I hope that it helps you get more done with your MySQL server. Boxcheck - A new version of boxcheck.com is coming and it will include more tests for you to use.</description></item><item><title>Hosting the politicians</title><link>https://major.io/2008/04/24/hosting-the-politicians/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 17:12:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/04/24/hosting-the-politicians/</guid><description>Call me weird - but I like to know where people host their sites. When I get a link to a nice-looking site, I&amp;rsquo;ll get there and think, &amp;ldquo;Hmm, I wonder where they host.&amp;rdquo;
Part of this curiosity probably stems from being a server administrator. I&amp;rsquo;ve used seven different dedicated server providers before along with 5 different VPS providers. There&amp;rsquo;s quite a few shared hosters thrown into the mix as well.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner reaches 5,000 downloads!</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/25/mysqltuner-reaches-5000-downloads/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 17:01:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/25/mysqltuner-reaches-5000-downloads/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just reviewed the stats for MySQLTuner, and it crossed the 5,000 download mark last week! Thanks to all of you who have helped me make it a successful tool for MySQL server optimization.
With that said - how can MySQLTuner be improved to help you? Please let me know, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get started on those features!</description></item><item><title>Have a great 2008</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/01/have-a-great-2008/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 18:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/01/have-a-great-2008/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to wish everyone a Happy New Year and I hope it is a great 2008 for you all!</description></item><item><title>Taking a little time off</title><link>https://major.io/2007/12/18/taking-a-little-time-off/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/12/18/taking-a-little-time-off/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m taking a little bit of time off for Christmas, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding new posts on December 31st. I wish all of you a happy holiday season, and if you celebrate Christmas, a Merry Christmas as well!</description></item><item><title>Happy Thanksgiving</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/22/happy-thanksgiving/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 04:20:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/22/happy-thanksgiving/</guid><description>In the US, we celebrate Thanksgiving today. I&amp;rsquo;m taking off the rest of this week, but you can expect updates to begin again on Monday!</description></item><item><title>A short vacation</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/02/a-short-vacation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2007 05:21:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/02/a-short-vacation/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a bit of a vacation lately, and that&amp;rsquo;s why there&amp;rsquo;s been a lack of updates. On October 20th, I married the best woman on the planet, and we we&amp;rsquo;ve been on our honeymoon since then.
New updates should start again this Monday!</description></item><item><title>A week’s vacation</title><link>https://major.io/2007/09/25/weeks-vacation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 03:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/09/25/weeks-vacation/</guid><description>So, you might be saying: &amp;ldquo;where the heck are the updates for RackerHacker lately?&amp;rdquo;
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;m still alive! Some work and personal obligations kept me away from the blogging for a week, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be hard at work finding new things for you as soon as I can!</description></item><item><title>Happy Labor Day</title><link>https://major.io/2007/09/03/happy-labor-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 03:49:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/09/03/happy-labor-day/</guid><description>In the spirit of Labor Day, there will be no new items today. Plus, I worked today, and I&amp;rsquo;m tired. :-)</description></item></channel></rss>