<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dovecot on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/dovecot/</link><description>Recent content in dovecot on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 18:47:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/dovecot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dovecot: libsepol.so.1: failed to map segment from shared object: Cannot allocate memory</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/22/dovecot-libsepolso1-failed-to-map-segment-from-shared-object-cannot-allocate-memory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 18:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/22/dovecot-libsepolso1-failed-to-map-segment-from-shared-object-cannot-allocate-memory/</guid><description>You may catch this error when you attempt to start dovecot on a Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.1 system with the 64-bit architecture:
dovecot: imap-login: imap-login: error while loading shared libraries: libsepol.so.1: failed to map segment from shared object: Cannot allocate memory dovecot: pop3-login: pop3-login: error while loading shared libraries: libsepol.so.1: failed to map segment from shared object: Cannot allocate memory If you start dovecot, the main dovecot daemon will run with one auth child process, but there will be no POP/IMAP processes started.</description></item><item><title>Dovecot: mbox: Can’t create root IMAP folder</title><link>https://major.io/2007/10/09/dovecot-mbox-cant-create-root-imap-folder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 01:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/10/09/dovecot-mbox-cant-create-root-imap-folder/</guid><description>In some situations with dovecot running on your server, you may receive a message from your e-mail client stating that the &amp;ldquo;connection was interrupted with your mail server&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;login process failed&amp;rdquo;. This may happen even if you&amp;rsquo;ve created the e-mail account, created the mail spool, and set a password for the user.
If you check your /var/log/maillog, you will generally find errors like these:
Oct 7 09:37:45 mailserver pop3-login: Login: newuser [111.</description></item></channel></rss>