<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rackspace on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/rackspace/</link><description>Recent content in rackspace on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:18:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/rackspace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reaching the fork in the road</title><link>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:18:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</guid><description>Walt Disney said it best:
We keep moving forward, opening new doors, and doing new things, because we&amp;rsquo;re curious and curiosity keeps leading us down new paths.
The world of technology is all about change. We tear down the old things that get in our way and we build new technology that takes us to new heights. Tearing down these old things can often be difficult and that forces us to make difficult choices.</description></item><item><title>OpenStack Summit Boston 2017 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2017/05/11/openstack-summit-boston-2017-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:25:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/05/11/openstack-summit-boston-2017-recap/</guid><description>The OpenStack Summit wrapped up today in Boston and it was a great week! There were plenty of informative breakouts and some interesting keynotes.
Keynotes Beth Cohen shared some of the work that Verizon has done with software-defined WAN on customer-premises equipment (CPE). She showed a demo of how customers could easily provision virtual network hardware, such as firewalls or intrusion detection systems, without waiting for hardware or cabling changes. I&amp;rsquo;m less familiar with the world of telcos, so I found this really interesting.</description></item><item><title>Five reasons why I’m excited about POWER9</title><link>https://major.io/2017/03/21/five-reasons-why-im-excited-about-power9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 18:38:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/03/21/five-reasons-why-im-excited-about-power9/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s plenty to like about the POWER8 architecture: high speed interconnections, large (and flexible) core counts, and support for lots of memory. POWER9 provides improvements in all of these areas and it has learned some entirely new tricks as well.
Here are my top five reasons for getting excited about POWER9:
NVLink 2.0 In the simplext terms, NVLink provides a very high speed interface between CPUs and GPUs with very low latency.</description></item><item><title>Reflecting on 10 years of (mostly) technical blogging</title><link>https://major.io/2017/03/10/reflecting-on-10-years-of-mostly-technical-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:11:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/03/10/reflecting-on-10-years-of-mostly-technical-blogging/</guid><description>It all started shortly after I joined Rackspace in December of 2006. I needed a place to dump the huge amounts of information I was learning as an entry-level Linux support technician and I wanted to store everything in a place where it could be easily shared. The blog was born!
The blog now has over 700 posts on topics ranging from Linux system administration to job interview preparation. I&amp;rsquo;ll get an email or a tweet once every few weeks from someone saying: &amp;ldquo;I ran into a problem, Googled for it, and found your blog!</description></item><item><title>Join me on Thursday to talk about OpenStack LBaaS and security hardening</title><link>https://major.io/2016/07/19/join-me-on-thursday-to-talk-about-openstack-lbaas-and-security/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 14:09:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/07/19/join-me-on-thursday-to-talk-about-openstack-lbaas-and-security/</guid><description>If you want to learn more about load balancers and security hardening in OpenStack clouds, join me on Thursday for the Rackspace Office Hours podcast! Walter Bentley, Kenneth Hui and I will be talking about some of the new features available in the 12.2 release of Rackspace Private Cloud powered by OpenStack.
The release has a tech preview of OpenStack&amp;rsquo;s Load Balancer as a Service project. The new LBaaSv2 API is stable and makes it easy to create load balancers, add pools, and add members.</description></item><item><title>Talk recap: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2016/06/28/talk-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 03:43:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/06/28/talk-recap/</guid><description>The 2016 Red Hat Summit is underway in San Francisco this week and I delivered a talk with Robyn Bergeron earlier today. Our talk, When flexibility met simplicity: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible, explained how Ansible can reduce the complexity of OpenStack environments without sacrificing the flexibility that private clouds offer.
The talk started at the same time as lunch began and the Partner Pavilion first opened, so we had some stiff competition for attendees' attention.</description></item><item><title>My list of must-see sessions at Red Hat Summit 2016</title><link>https://major.io/2016/06/26/almost-time-red-hat-summit-2016/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 10:52:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/06/26/almost-time-red-hat-summit-2016/</guid><description>The Red Hat Summit starts this week in San Francisco, and a few folks asked me about the sessions that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss. The schedule can be overwhelming for first timers and it can be difficult at times to discern the technical sessions from the ones that are more sales-oriented.
If you&amp;rsquo;re in San Francisco, and you want to learn a bit more about using Ansible to manage OpenStack environments, come to the session that I am co-presenting with Robyn Bergeron: When flexibility met simplicity: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible.</description></item><item><title>OpenStack Summit in Austin is almost here!</title><link>https://major.io/2016/04/21/brace-openstack-summit-austin-coming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 13:16:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/04/21/brace-openstack-summit-austin-coming/</guid><description>OpenStack comes home to Austin on Monday for the OpenStack Summit! I will be there with plenty of other Rackers to learn, collaborate, and share our story.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in applying automated security hardening to an OpenStack cloud, be sure to drop by my talk on Tuesday from 11:15 to 11:55 AM. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Rackspace uses the openstack-ansible-security Ansible role to automatically apply hardening standards to servers in an OpenStack private cloud.</description></item><item><title>Build a high performance KVM hypervisor on Rackspace’s OnMetal servers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/28/build-a-high-performance-kvm-hypervisor-on-rackspaces-onmetal-servers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/28/build-a-high-performance-kvm-hypervisor-on-rackspaces-onmetal-servers/</guid><description>I received some good feedback about my post on systemd-networkd and bonded interfaces on Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s OnMetal servers, and I decided to write about another use case. Recent product updates allow you to attach a Cloud Block Storage volume, and this opens up quite a few new possibilities for deployments.
So why not create a high-performance KVM hypervisor on an OnMetal server? Let&amp;rsquo;s do this.
Disclaimer WHOA THERE. These are amazing servers and because of that, they&amp;rsquo;re priced much differently than Cloud Servers are.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 23 Alpha in boot.rackspace.com</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/27/fedora-23-alpha-in-boot-rackspace-com/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 13:03:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/27/fedora-23-alpha-in-boot-rackspace-com/</guid><description>Fedora 23&amp;rsquo;s Alpha release was announced earlier this month and work is underway for the beta release. The full list of dates for the Fedora 23 release is in the Fedora wiki.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to try Fedora 23 Alpha a little sooner, check out boot.rackspace.com. I added support for Fedora 23 in the menus last night.
Quick start If you want to get underway quickly, simply download the boot.rackspace.com ISO and attach it to a virtual machine:</description></item><item><title>Using systemd-networkd with bonding on Rackspace’s OnMetal servers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/21/using-systemd-networkd-with-bonding-on-rackspaces-onmetal-servers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/21/using-systemd-networkd-with-bonding-on-rackspaces-onmetal-servers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about systemd-networkd in the past and how easy it can be to set up new network devices and tunnels. However, the documentation on systemd-networkd with bonding is a bit lacking (but I have a pull request pending for that).
Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s OnMetal Servers are a good place to test since they have bonded networks configured by default. They&amp;rsquo;re also quite fast and always fun for experiments.
To get started, head on over to the Rackspace Cloud control panel and build a compute-1 OnMetal server and choose Fedora 22 as your operating system.</description></item><item><title>Woot! Eight years of my blog</title><link>https://major.io/2015/04/14/woot-eight-years-of-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:53:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/04/14/woot-eight-years-of-my-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>The spring of 2015 marks eight years of this blog! I&amp;rsquo;ve learned plenty of tough lessons along the way and I&amp;rsquo;ve made some changes recently that might be handy for other people. After watching &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sashalaund">Sasha Laundy&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> video from her &lt;a href="http://blog.sashalaundy.com/talks/asking-helping/">awesome talk at Pycon 2015&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m even more energized to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with other people. &lt;em>(Seriously: Go watch that video or review the slides whether you work in IT or not. It&amp;rsquo;s worth your time.)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Test Fedora 22 at Rackspace with Ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2015/03/24/test-fedora-22-at-rackspace-with-ansible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/03/24/test-fedora-22-at-rackspace-with-ansible/</guid><description>Fedora 22 will be arriving soon and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to test on Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s cloud with my Ansible playbook:
https://github.com/major/ansible-rax-fedora22 As with the previous playbook I created for Fedora 21, this playbook will ensure your Fedora 21 instance is fully up to date and then perform the upgrade to Fedora 22.
WARNING: It&amp;rsquo;s best to use this playbook against a non-production system. Fedora 22 is an alpha release at the time of this post&amp;rsquo;s writing.</description></item><item><title>Eight years at Rackspace</title><link>https://major.io/2014/12/18/eight-years-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/12/18/eight-years-rackspace/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Test Fedora 21 at Rackspace with Ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2014/10/03/easily-test-fedora-21-rackspace-cloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 20:24:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/10/03/easily-test-fedora-21-rackspace-cloud/</guid><description>Fedora 21 reached Alpha status last month and will reach beta status at the end of October. There are plenty of new features planned for the final release.
You can test Fedora 21 now using Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Servers. I&amp;rsquo;ve assembled a small Ansible playbook that will automate the upgrade process from Fedora 20 to 21 and it takes around 7-9 minutes to complete.
The Ansible playbook is on GitHub along with instructions: ansible-rax-fedora21</description></item><item><title>Xen hackathon coming up in London</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/27/xen-hackathon-coming-up-in-london/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 13:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/27/xen-hackathon-coming-up-in-london/</guid><description>If you enjoy using Xen, join members of the Xen Project community and Rackspace at the Xen Hackathon in London. The two day event starts on May 29th.
Use these links to get more information:
Hackathon announcement and travel/venue/registration information Discussion topics You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a developer to join the event. It&amp;rsquo;s a great networking opportunity and you can take time to learn more about virtualization and how Xen works under the hood.</description></item><item><title>A humble farewell to Seth Vidal</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</guid><description>I was shocked to see Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s email today about Seth Vidal&amp;rsquo;s passing. He was the victim of a hit and run accident while he was cycling last night. The suspect has turned himself in as of tonight.
I first met Seth at FUDCon Tempe back in 2011. We had talked off and on via email and IRC about cloud-related topics. He was interested in how we assembled our cloud offering at Rackspace and I was eager to talk to him about building cloud images and handling mirrors.</description></item><item><title>Reaching a new milestone and making some big changes</title><link>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</guid><description>This is my 500th post on this blog! I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful for the constant comments, questions, and even the complaints (really!) that I receive about the topics discussed here throughout the years. The sole reason I keep this blog going is for the readers and I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to get value out of it over time. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t, be sure to let me know so I can make some changes.</description></item><item><title>Proud to be a part of OpenStack at Rackspace</title><link>https://major.io/2012/10/17/proud-to-be-a-part-of-openstack-at-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 03:34:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/10/17/proud-to-be-a-part-of-openstack-at-rackspace/</guid><description>Troy Toman delivered a great keynote this morning about OpenStack and how Rackspace uses it:
I&amp;rsquo;m extremely glad to be a tiny part of the OpenStack story and I&amp;rsquo;m proud to see where it&amp;rsquo;s going today. My goals are to make OpenStack environments easier to deploy, maintain and administer. Along with other Rackers, we&amp;rsquo;re making this happen each day and we plan to share our successes and hardships with the community.</description></item><item><title>Red Hat Summit 2012: Thursday</title><link>https://major.io/2012/06/28/red-hat-summit-2012-thursday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 04:54:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/06/28/red-hat-summit-2012-thursday/</guid><description>Thursday has felt like the busiest, most jam-packed day of the week. The morning started off with three keynotes from HP, Intel, and Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s CTO, Brian Stevens.
HP&amp;rsquo;s message centered around converged cloud and that customers don&amp;rsquo;t need an all or nothing solution. They can pull the best pieces from every type of hosting to do what&amp;rsquo;s best for their business. The presentation from Intel was extremely heavy on the marketing side and didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to do with Red Hat.</description></item><item><title>supernova: Manage multiple OpenStack nova environments with ease</title><link>https://major.io/2012/06/05/supernova-manage-multiple-openstack-nova-environments-with-ease/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 13:12:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/06/05/supernova-manage-multiple-openstack-nova-environments-with-ease/</guid><description>While working on multiple nova (OpenStack Compute) environments at Rackspace, I found myself thrashing between multiple terminal windows where I had exported environment variables for python-novaclient to use. I ended up requesting some image and instance deletions in a terminal window only to find that I&amp;rsquo;d done the deletions in the wrong nova environment. Once I realized what I&amp;rsquo;d done (and after a small bit of cursing), I knew there had to be a better way to work with multiple environments.</description></item><item><title>Getting a Technical Job at Rackspace</title><link>https://major.io/2012/04/09/getting-a-technical-job-at-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/04/09/getting-a-technical-job-at-rackspace/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably noticed that the blog has slowed down a bit recently. Part of the slowdown is due to an uptick in work required to get OpenStack Nova and its related software up and running at Rackspace for Cloud Servers and another part of it is a severe case of writer&amp;rsquo;s block. I threw out some questions on Twitter about the topics people would like to see covered in some new posts and a commonly requested topic was employment at Rackspace.</description></item><item><title>mysql-json-bridge: a simple JSON API for MySQL</title><link>https://major.io/2012/03/28/mysql-json-bridge-a-simple-json-api-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 02:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/03/28/mysql-json-bridge-a-simple-json-api-for-mysql/</guid><description>My quest to get better at Python led me to create a new project on GitHub. It&amp;rsquo;s called mysql-json-bridge and it&amp;rsquo;s ready for you to use.
Why do we need a JSON API for MySQL?
The real need sprang from a situation I was facing daily at Rackspace. We have a lot of production and pre-production environments which are in flux but we need a way to query data from various MySQL servers for multiple purposes.</description></item><item><title>Five years of rackerhacker.com</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</guid><description>Today marks the fifth year that this blog has existed on the internet. I bought the domain on February 14th, 2007 and tossed together a quick WordPress installation (I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember the version now!) to hold my notes that I was gathering at work.
Rackspace as an entry-level Linux system administrator. The abrupt change from &amp;ldquo;top dog at the startup&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;wow, I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Linux&amp;rdquo; caught me by surprise and I was trying to stuff as much knowledge into my brain as quickly as I could.</description></item><item><title>Looking back at the long road to becoming a Red Hat Certified Architect</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/13/looking-back-at-the-long-road-to-becoming-a-red-hat-certified-architect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/13/looking-back-at-the-long-road-to-becoming-a-red-hat-certified-architect/</guid><description>The grades came back last Friday and I&amp;rsquo;ve passed the last exam in the requirements to become a Red Hat Certified Architect (RHCA). I was fortunate enough to be part of Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s RHCA pilot program and we took our first exam back at the end of 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a good feeling to be finished and I&amp;rsquo;m definitely ready to give back some knowledge to the readers of this blog.</description></item></channel></rss>