<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mod_rewrite on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/mod_rewrite/</link><description>Recent content in mod_rewrite on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 04:02:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/mod_rewrite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a local PyPi repository using only mod_rewrite</title><link>https://major.io/2012/01/31/create-a-local-pypi-repository-using-only-mod_rewrite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 04:02:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/01/31/create-a-local-pypi-repository-using-only-mod_rewrite/</guid><description>Regular users of Python&amp;rsquo;s package tools like pip or easy_install are probably familiar with the PyPi repository. It&amp;rsquo;s a one-stop-shop to learn more about available Python packages and get them installed on your server.
However, certain folks may find the need to host a local PyPi repository for their own packages. You may need it to store Python code which you don&amp;rsquo;t plan to release publicly or you may need to add proprietary patches to upstream Python packages.</description></item><item><title>Throwing thoughtful “403 Forbidden” responses with apache</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/17/throwing-thoughtful-403-forbidden-responses-with-apache/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 13:47:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/17/throwing-thoughtful-403-forbidden-responses-with-apache/</guid><description>If you offer a web service that users query via scripts or other applications, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably find that some people will begin to abuse the service. My icanhazip.com site is no exception.
While many of the users have reasonable usage patterns, there are some users that query the site more than once per second from the same IP address. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t used the site before, all it does is return your public IP address in plain text.</description></item><item><title>Apache 2.2: internal dummy connection</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/23/apache-22-internal-dummy-connection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 01:42:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/23/apache-22-internal-dummy-connection/</guid><description>After working with some RHEL 5 servers fairly regularly, I noticed a reduction in Apache 2.2 performance when many connections were made to the server. There were messages like these streaming into the access_log as well:
127.0.0.1 - - [21/Aug/2008:12:00:10 -0400] &amp;quot;GET / HTTP/1.0&amp;quot; 200 2269 &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Apache/2.2.3 (Red Hat) (internal dummy connection)&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; 127.0.0.1 - - [21/Aug/2008:12:00:11 -0400] &amp;quot;GET / HTTP/1.0&amp;quot; 200 2269 &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Apache/2.2.3 (Red Hat) (internal dummy connection)&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; 127.</description></item><item><title>Enabling Ruby on Rails support for a domain in Plesk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/08/11/enabling-ruby-on-rails-support-for-a-domain-in-plesk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 01:16:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/08/11/enabling-ruby-on-rails-support-for-a-domain-in-plesk/</guid><description>If you have Plesk 8.1 or later, you have support available for Ruby on Rails. Unfortunately, clicking the FastCGI checkbox in Plesk won&amp;rsquo;t get you all of the support you need (and expect). The folks over at Parallels created a relatively simple process to get Ruby on Rails working properly on your site:
Go to your domain that you want to adjust, and click Setup. Make sure the CGI and FastCGI options are enabled.</description></item></channel></rss>