<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>twitter on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/twitter/</link><description>Recent content in twitter on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 13:55:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tweetdeck’s Chrome notifications stopped working</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/08/tweetdecks-chrome-notifications-stopped-working/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 13:55:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/08/tweetdecks-chrome-notifications-stopped-working/</guid><description>With the last few weeks, I noticed that Tweetdeck&amp;rsquo;s notifications weren&amp;rsquo;t showing up in Chrome any longer. I double-checked all of the Tweetdeck settings and notifications were indeed enabled. However, I found that Tweetdeck wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed to send notifications when I checked in my Chrome settings.
Check your settings To check these for yourself, hop into Chrome&amp;rsquo;s content settings. Scroll down to Notifications and click Manage Exceptions. In my case, https://tweetdeck.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo ThinkPad T430s review</title><link>https://major.io/2012/10/21/lenovo-thinkpad-t430s-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 21:15:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/10/21/lenovo-thinkpad-t430s-review/</guid><description>This post covers the second half of my experience moving back to a Linux desktop but I figured it was a good opportunity to focus on the ThinkPad T430s itself as well as the Lenovo ordering experience. If you follow me on Twitter, you know about my service experience. I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for the end of this post.
This post is a little on the long side, so here&amp;rsquo;s a TL;DR for you if you&amp;rsquo;re in a big hurry:</description></item><item><title>See you at LinuxCon North America 2012!</title><link>https://major.io/2012/08/15/see-you-at-linuxcon-north-america-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 14:02:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/08/15/see-you-at-linuxcon-north-america-2012/</guid><description>I was sitting at my desk yesterday when I saw a tweet from @LinuxFoundation:
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to attend LinuxCon, so I fired back with a reply: &amp;ldquo;@linuxfoundation Fedora! #linuxcon #cloudopen&amp;rdquo;. This popped into my Twitter timeline yesterday evening:
Wow! This sure was a surprise since I rarely ever win a contest of any sort.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a big thanks to the Linux Foundation for making this possible and to Rackspace for letting me travel on such short notice.</description></item><item><title>Off to the 2012 Red Hat Summit</title><link>https://major.io/2012/06/26/off-to-the-2012-red-hat-summit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 10:11:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/06/26/off-to-the-2012-red-hat-summit/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m on my way to my first Red Hat Summit and I&amp;rsquo;m really eager to learn some new things, meet new people, and share my experiences with others. This is my first time attending the summit and my first time in Boston.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not attending, but you&amp;rsquo;d like to follow along with some of the keynotes, you can register online to live stream those events to your desktop. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share some of the best parts of the keynotes and the sessions here on the blog if TL;DR is a little more your style.</description></item><item><title>Keep tabs on OpenStack development with OpenStack Watch on Twitter</title><link>https://major.io/2012/06/08/keep-tabs-on-openstack-development-with-openstack-watch-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 12:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/06/08/keep-tabs-on-openstack-development-with-openstack-watch-on-twitter/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Twitter and OpenStack. I found myself needing a better way to follow the rapid pace of OpenStack development and I figured that a Twitter bot would be a pretty good method for staying up to date.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to invite you to check out @openstackwatch.
First things first, it&amp;rsquo;s a completely unofficial project that I worked on during my spare time and it&amp;rsquo;s not affiliated with OpenStack in any way.</description></item><item><title>Do professional certifications belong in your e-mail signature?</title><link>https://major.io/2010/10/16/do-professional-certifications-belong-in-your-e-mail-signature/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 15:53:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/10/16/do-professional-certifications-belong-in-your-e-mail-signature/</guid><description>After a discussion amongst coworkers about professional certifications in e-mail signatures yesterday, I decided to throw the question out to Twitter to gather some feedback:
rackerhacker: Quick Twitter poll for the nerds: How many certification abbreviations do you put in your e-mail signature? [Permalink]
The question must have struck a nerve with folks as I had over 50 replies in less than 10-15 minutes. I expected to hear a lot of people say &amp;ldquo;zero&amp;rdquo;, and there were quite a few responses that didn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me:</description></item><item><title>Reincarnation of Twitter’s realtime XMPP search term tracking with ruby</title><link>https://major.io/2010/06/17/reincarnation-of-twitters-realtime-xmpp-search-term-tracking-with-ruby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 18:40:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/06/17/reincarnation-of-twitters-realtime-xmpp-search-term-tracking-with-ruby/</guid><description>When Twitter was still in its early stages, you could track certain search terms in near-realtime via Jabber. It was quite popular and its performance degraded over time as more users signed up and began posting updates. Eventually, Twitter killed the jabber bot altogether. Many users have asked when it will return.
Well, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t returned, but you can build your own replacement with ruby, a jabber account, and a few gems.</description></item><item><title>Idiot’s guide to OAuth logins for Twitter</title><link>https://major.io/2010/05/19/idiots-guide-to-oauth-logins-for-twitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 01:26:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/05/19/idiots-guide-to-oauth-logins-for-twitter/</guid><description>It certainly shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be difficult, but I always have a tough time with OAuth. Twitter is dropping support for basic authentication on June 30th, 2010. I have some automated Twitter bots that need an upgrade, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a quick solution to generate tokens for my scripts.
I formulated a pretty simple script using John Nunemaker&amp;rsquo;s twitter gem that will get it done manually for any scripts you have that read from or update Twitter:</description></item><item><title>New Linux security advisory Twitter bots</title><link>https://major.io/2009/02/05/new-linux-security-advisory-twitter-bots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/02/05/new-linux-security-advisory-twitter-bots/</guid><description>Thanks to the simplicity of ruby as well as the twitter and httparty gems, I&amp;rsquo;ve whipped up some Twitter bots today. The three bots will alert you when there are Red Hat, Ubuntu, or Debian security advisories. I&amp;rsquo;d set one up for Fedora, but their feed is broken today.
@redhaterrata - Red Hat Errata Updates
@ubuntusecurity - Ubuntu Security Notifications
@debiansecurity - Debian Security Advisories
As always, you can let me know if you have any suggestions for improvements, or other bots you&amp;rsquo;d like to see.</description></item></channel></rss>