<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>networkmanager on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/networkmanager/</link><description>Recent content in networkmanager on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:14:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/networkmanager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Restoring wireless and Bluetooth state after reboot in Fedora 22</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/19/restoring-wireless-and-bluetooth-state-after-reboot-in-fedora-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/19/restoring-wireless-and-bluetooth-state-after-reboot-in-fedora-22/</guid><description>My upgrade to Fedora 22 on the ThinkPad X1 Carbon was fairly uneventful and the hiccups were minor. One of the more annoying items that I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with for quite some time is how to boot up with the wireless LAN and Bluetooth disabled by default. Restoring wireless and Bluetooth state between reboots is normally handled quite well in Fedora.
In Fedora 21, NetworkManager saved my settings between reboots. For example, if I shut down with wifi off and Bluetooth on, the laptop would boot up later with wifi off and Bluetooth on.</description></item><item><title>Share a wireless connection via ethernet in GNOME 3.14</title><link>https://major.io/2015/03/29/share-a-wireless-connection-via-ethernet-in-gnome-3-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 02:31:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/03/29/share-a-wireless-connection-via-ethernet-in-gnome-3-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are some situations where you want to do the opposite of creating a wireless hotspot and you want to share a wireless connection to an ethernet connection. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re at a hotel that offers only WiFi internet access, you could share that connection to an ethernet switch and plug in more devices. Also, you could get online with your wireless connection and create a small NAT network to test a network device without mangling your home network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accessing Rackspace Cloud Servers and Slicehost slices privately via OpenVPN</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/16/accessing-rackspace-cloud-servers-and-slicehost-slices-privately-via-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/16/accessing-rackspace-cloud-servers-and-slicehost-slices-privately-via-openvpn/</guid><description>Diagram: OpenVPN to Rackspace Cloud Servers and Slicehost
A recent blog post from Mixpanel inspired me to write a quick how-to for Fedora users on using OpenVPN to talk to instances privately in the Rackspace Cloud.
The diagram at the right gives an idea of what this guide will allow you to accomplish. Consider a situation where you want to talk to the MySQL installation on db1 directly without requiring extra ssh tunnels or MySQL over SSL via the public network.</description></item><item><title>Prevent gnome-keyring from asking for a password when NetworkManager starts</title><link>https://major.io/2009/02/26/prevent-gnome-keyring-from-asking-for-a-password-when-networkmanager-starts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 00:21:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/02/26/prevent-gnome-keyring-from-asking-for-a-password-when-networkmanager-starts/</guid><description>I recently tossed Ubuntu 8.10 on my Mac Mini at home to use it as a home theater PC (with Boxee). When I connected to my wireless network via NetworkManager, I entered my WPA2 passphrase, and then I was prompted to enter a password for gnome-keyring. I went back to the couch, SSH&amp;rsquo;ed in, and continued configuring it remotely. When it rebooted, it never came back online.
Once I switched the TV back over to the Mini, I saw that gnome-keyring had popped up and it was asking for my password.</description></item></channel></rss>