<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:11:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflecting on 10 years of (mostly) technical blogging</title><link>https://major.io/2017/03/10/reflecting-on-10-years-of-mostly-technical-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:11:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/03/10/reflecting-on-10-years-of-mostly-technical-blogging/</guid><description>It all started shortly after I joined Rackspace in December of 2006. I needed a place to dump the huge amounts of information I was learning as an entry-level Linux support technician and I wanted to store everything in a place where it could be easily shared. The blog was born!
The blog now has over 700 posts on topics ranging from Linux system administration to job interview preparation. I&amp;rsquo;ll get an email or a tweet once every few weeks from someone saying: &amp;ldquo;I ran into a problem, Googled for it, and found your blog!</description></item><item><title>HTTP/2 for the blog and icanhazip.com</title><link>https://major.io/2016/09/13/http2-for-the-blog-and-icanhazip-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 13:47:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/09/13/http2-for-the-blog-and-icanhazip-com/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated this blog and icanhazip.com to enable HTTP/2! This probably won&amp;rsquo;t have much of an effect on users who query icanhazip.com with automated tools, but it should deliver the content on this blog a little faster. If you&amp;rsquo;re using an older, non-HTTP/2 client - don&amp;rsquo;t worry. All of the sites will continue working for you as they always have.
Head on over to Wikipedia to learn more about HTTP/2 and its benefits.</description></item><item><title>Helpful, low-FUD information security sites, mailing lists, and blogs</title><link>https://major.io/2015/01/08/helpful-low-fud-information-security-sites-mailing-lists-blogs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/01/08/helpful-low-fud-information-security-sites-mailing-lists-blogs/</guid><description>Keeping current with the latest trends and technologies in the realm of information security is critical and there are many options to choose from. However, as with any content on the internet, it takes some effort to find sites with a good signal-to-noise ratio. Information security is a heavily FUD-laden industry and I&amp;rsquo;ve taken some time to compile a list of helpful sites.
General sites Cryptanalys.is: https://cryptanalys.is/ Linux Weekly News (subscription optional but highly recommended): http://lwn.</description></item><item><title>Reaching a new milestone and making some big changes</title><link>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</guid><description>This is my 500th post on this blog! I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful for the constant comments, questions, and even the complaints (really!) that I receive about the topics discussed here throughout the years. The sole reason I keep this blog going is for the readers and I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to get value out of it over time. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t, be sure to let me know so I can make some changes.</description></item><item><title>Why technical people should blog (but don’t)</title><link>https://major.io/2012/03/30/why-technical-people-should-blog-but-dont/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 14:30:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/03/30/why-technical-people-should-blog-but-dont/</guid><description>I originally wrote this post for the Rackspace Blogbut I decided to post it here in case some of my readers might have missed it. Please feel free to leave your comments at the end of the post. Sometimes people talk to me about posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written on my blog, or posts they wish I would write. At some point during the discussion, I&amp;rsquo;ll almost always ask the person why they don&amp;rsquo;t start up their own blog or contribute to someone else&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Five years of rackerhacker.com</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</guid><description>Today marks the fifth year that this blog has existed on the internet. I bought the domain on February 14th, 2007 and tossed together a quick WordPress installation (I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember the version now!) to hold my notes that I was gathering at work.
Rackspace as an entry-level Linux system administrator. The abrupt change from &amp;ldquo;top dog at the startup&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;wow, I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Linux&amp;rdquo; caught me by surprise and I was trying to stuff as much knowledge into my brain as quickly as I could.</description></item><item><title>400th post: Looking back at where this blog started</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/13/400th-post-looking-back-at-where-this-blog-started/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 02:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/13/400th-post-looking-back-at-where-this-blog-started/</guid><description>Last night&amp;rsquo;s post about my charity drive for the Movember Foundation was the 400th post on my blog! I started posting on rackerhacker.com way back in the spring of 2007 shortly after I was hired by Rackspace in December of 2006.
My main purpose for the blog at the beginning was to create a place where I could write quick articles about problems I found and how to fix them. Most of the people around me were using their own handy systems to store notes (Stickies on the Mac, Tomboy notes on Linux, or just simple text files), but they weren&amp;rsquo;t able to share them easily.</description></item><item><title>Raising money for prostate cancer research and survivor support</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/12/raising-money-for-prostate-cancer-research-and-survivor-support/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 03:19:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/12/raising-money-for-prostate-cancer-research-and-survivor-support/</guid><description>Movember 2010
This is a bit of an unusual post for my blog, but I wanted to reach out to you for charitable reasons. I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying to grow some facial hair (which is a feat in itself) with some folks from work for the Movember Foundation. I look a bit sillier than usual, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s for a good cause.
The Movember Foundation currently passes along the proceeds to the Prostate Cancer Foundation and LIVESTRONG.</description></item><item><title>Why I’m a Racker</title><link>https://major.io/2010/03/26/why-im-a-racker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 13:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/03/26/why-im-a-racker/</guid><description>I normally try to keep my work-related items separate from this blog, but I felt that I needed to break tradition for a moment. The new Rackspace Talent site was released a few weeks ago and Michael Long asked me to write a blog post about what it means to be a Racker (that&amp;rsquo;s the term we use for employees of Rackspace).
After the post went up, I received as much feedback from people outside of Rackspace as I received from Rackers.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.7</title><link>https://major.io/2008/12/25/upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 03:45:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/12/25/upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded the blog successfully to WordPress 2.7 (with a bit of frustration). When I attempted the upgrade, I received this error:
Call to undefined method wpdb::has_cap() in schema.php on line 22
Even though I followed the instructions on the WordPress site, and I disabled all of my plugins, the error kept appearing. The only parts of the site that remained unchanged after the upgrade were the wp-config.php page and the wp-content directory.</description></item><item><title>New look</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/20/new-look/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 20:19:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/20/new-look/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to adjust the look of this blog to make it easier to read and faster to download. My old Mandigo theme was great, but it required each user to download about 200kb worth of content to see the blog. The new theme is about 30-40kb per download and it renders faster in all the browsers I&amp;rsquo;ve tested.
Leave a comment and let me know what you think of the changes.</description></item><item><title>Thanks for making RackerHacker so popular!</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/14/thanks-for-making-rackerhacker-so-popular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 03:31:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/14/thanks-for-making-rackerhacker-so-popular/</guid><description>After a quick review of the stats this evening, I found that this blog has made it to 500,000 sessions so far this year. Page views are just past 2.5 million! In 2007, there were over 65,000 sessions and over 427,000 million page views in 2007 as a final count.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the exact numbers as of tonight:
2008 Year to Date:
Sessions: 501,166 Pageviews: 2,506,011 Hits: 7,414,333 Bytes Transferred: 65.</description></item></channel></rss>