<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>php on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/php/</link><description>Recent content in php on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:53:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Woot! Eight years of my blog</title><link>https://major.io/2015/04/14/woot-eight-years-of-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:53:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/04/14/woot-eight-years-of-my-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>The spring of 2015 marks eight years of this blog! I&amp;rsquo;ve learned plenty of tough lessons along the way and I&amp;rsquo;ve made some changes recently that might be handy for other people. After watching &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sashalaund">Sasha Laundy&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> video from her &lt;a href="http://blog.sashalaundy.com/talks/asking-helping/">awesome talk at Pycon 2015&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m even more energized to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with other people. &lt;em>(Seriously: Go watch that video or review the slides whether you work in IT or not. It&amp;rsquo;s worth your time.)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survive the Google Reader exodus with Tiny Tiny RSS</title><link>https://major.io/2013/03/17/survive-the-google-reader-exodus-with-tiny-tiny-rss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 21:27:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/03/17/survive-the-google-reader-exodus-with-tiny-tiny-rss/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that Google Reader is a popular way to keep up with your RSS feeds, but it&amp;rsquo;s getting shelved later this year. Most folks suggested Feedly as a replacement but I found the UI quite clunky in a browser and on Android devices.
Then someone suggested Tiny Tiny RSS. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t learn more about it on the day Google Reader&amp;rsquo;s shutdown was announced because the site was slammed. In a nutshell, Tiny Tiny RSS is a well-written web UI for managing feeds and a handy API for using it with mobile applications.</description></item><item><title>Getting apache, PHP, and memcached working with SELinux</title><link>https://major.io/2011/09/07/getting-apache-php-and-memcached-working-with-selinux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 03:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/09/07/getting-apache-php-and-memcached-working-with-selinux/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m using SELinux more often now on my Fedora 15 installations and I came up against a peculiar issue today on a new server. My PHP installation is configured to store its sessions in memcached and I brought over some working configurations from another server. However, each time I accessed a page which tried to initiate a session, the page load would hang for about a minute and I&amp;rsquo;d find this in my apache error logs:</description></item><item><title>WordPress and PHP 5.3.x: update_comment_type_cache() expected to be a reference</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/21/wordpress-and-php-5-3-x-update_comment_type_cache-expected-to-be-a-reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/21/wordpress-and-php-5-3-x-update_comment_type_cache-expected-to-be-a-reference/</guid><description>I upgraded a Fedora 11 instance to Fedora 12 and found the following error at the top of one of my WordPress blogs:
Parameter 1 to update_comment_type_cache() expected to be a reference, value given in wp-includes/plugin.php on line 166 The problem wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a plugin, actually. It was within my theme&amp;rsquo;s (R755-light) functions.php:
function update_comment_type_cache(&amp;amp;$queried_posts) { The temporary fix is to remove the &amp;amp; from that line so it looks like this:</description></item><item><title>Requiring SSL encryption for WordPress administration</title><link>https://major.io/2009/07/31/requiring-ssl-encryption-for-wordpress-administration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 13:13:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/07/31/requiring-ssl-encryption-for-wordpress-administration/</guid><description>I was digging around for WordPress plugins last night that would allow me to secure the administrative login page for my WordPress installations. Most of the plugins are only compatible with WordPress 2.7.x or earlier, so I was a little concerned about them working with WordPress 2.8.2.
Then I stumbled upon the WordPress documentation that shows you how to require SSL with no plugins at all. If you&amp;rsquo;re using WordPress 2.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded WordPress to 2.8.2</title><link>https://major.io/2009/07/29/upgraded-wordpress-to-2-8-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 22:22:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/07/29/upgraded-wordpress-to-2-8-2/</guid><description>I finally made it around to upgrading WordPress to 2.8.2 and it seems to be working like a charm. It looks like there were some bug fixes and a XSS vulnerability was patched.</description></item><item><title>Ugly upgrade path from WordPress 2.7.1 to 2.8</title><link>https://major.io/2009/06/13/ugly-upgrade-path-from-wordpress-2-7-1-to-2-8/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 17:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/06/13/ugly-upgrade-path-from-wordpress-2-7-1-to-2-8/</guid><description>When I tried to do an automatic upgrade from WordPress 2.7.1 to 2.8 yesterday, it failed miserably. The files were all put in place, but when I tried to load /wp-admin/upgrade.php, this error popped up:
I was perplexed at the error, so I restored from a backup and began upgrading manually. The manual upgrades have always worked well for me in the past, so I figured this would probably fix the problem.</description></item><item><title>Boxcheck v2.0 is on the way</title><link>https://major.io/2009/02/24/boxcheck-v20-is-on-the-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 13:20:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/02/24/boxcheck-v20-is-on-the-way/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit slow on new posts lately for two main reasons. First, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard with my new position at Slicehost, (I&amp;rsquo;m still with Rackspace). Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown out the old code for Boxcheck.com and I&amp;rsquo;m re-writing it from scratch.
Most of you probably know that the first version of Boxcheck threw out some odd errors for some tests and caused confusion for those that depended on the results.</description></item><item><title>Importing Excel files into MySQL with PHP</title><link>https://major.io/2008/11/07/importing-excel-files-into-mysql-with-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 19:42:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/11/07/importing-excel-files-into-mysql-with-php/</guid><description>If you have Excel files that need to be imported into MySQL, you can import them easily with PHP. First, you will need to download some prerequisites:
PHPExcelReader - http://sourceforge.net/projects/phpexcelreader/
Spreadsheet_Excel_Writer - http://pear.php.net/package/Spreadsheet_Excel_Writer
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded both items, upload them to your server. Your directory listing on your server should have two directories: Excel (from PHPExcelReader) and Spreadsheet_Excel_Writer-x.x.x (from Spreadsheet_Excel_Writer). To work around a bug in PHPExcelReader, copy oleread.inc from the Excel directory into a new path:</description></item><item><title>SquirrelMail: 127 Can’t execute command</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/08/squirrelmail-127-cant-execute-command/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/08/squirrelmail-127-cant-execute-command/</guid><description>I found a Plesk 8.3 server running RHEL 4 last month that was presenting errors when users attempted to send e-mail via SquirrelMail:
ERROR: Email delivery error Server replied: 127 Can't execute command '/usr/sbin/sendmail -i -t -fsomeuser@somedomain.com'. The error was appearing because safe_mode was enabled and SquirrelMail was unable to drop e-mails into /usr/sbin/squirrelmail. After disabling safe_mode on the server, the users were able to send e-mails via SquirrelMail.</description></item><item><title>Strange error with Horde 3.1.3 and Plesk 8.1.1</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/10/strange-error-with-horde-313-and-plesk-811/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 02:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/10/strange-error-with-horde-313-and-plesk-811/</guid><description>I saw a ticket the other day where a customer received this error from Horde when trying to expand items on the left pane of the interface:
Fatal error: Cannot use string offset as an array in /www/horde/lib/Horde/Block/Layout/Manager.php on line 389
It turns out that Plesk 8.1.1 bundles Horde 3.1.3 which has an occasional bug within the interface. Upgrading to Plesk 8.2.0 corrects the issue as Horde 3.1.4 is installed with the upgrade.</description></item></channel></rss>