<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>radio on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/radio/</link><description>Recent content in radio on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ham Radio FAQ</title><link>https://major.io/ham-radio-faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/ham-radio-faq/</guid><description>Welcome! This page is a work in progress!
The world of amateur, or ham, radio is huge and it&amp;rsquo;s what you want to make of it. The itch struck me in the middle of 2017 and I learned a lot since then.
People often ask me questions about all kinds of amateur radio topics and I decided to compile all of the answers into a big page that I can update over time.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with ham radio repeaters</title><link>https://major.io/2018/12/13/getting-started-with-ham-radio-repeaters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/12/13/getting-started-with-ham-radio-repeaters/</guid><description>Amateur radio is a fun way to mess around with technology, meet new people, and communicate off the grid. Talking directly to another radio on a single frequency (also called simplex) is the easiest way to get started. However, it can be difficult to communicate over longer distances without amplifiers, proper wiring, and antennas. This is where a radio repeater can help.
What&amp;rsquo;s in scope This post is focused on fairly local communication on VHF/UHF bands.</description></item><item><title>Takeaways from my foray into amateur radio</title><link>https://major.io/2018/01/06/takeaways-from-my-foray-into-amateur-radio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/01/06/takeaways-from-my-foray-into-amateur-radio/</guid><description>The Overland Expo in Asheville last year was a great event, and one of my favorite sessions covered the basics about radio communications while overlanding. The instructors shared their radios with us and taught us some tips and tricks for how to save power and communicate effectively on the trail.
Back at the office, I was surprised to discover how many of my coworkers had an FCC license already. They gave me tips on getting started and how to learn the material for the exam.</description></item></channel></rss>