<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bluetooth on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/bluetooth/</link><description>Recent content in bluetooth on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:14:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/bluetooth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Restoring wireless and Bluetooth state after reboot in Fedora 22</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/19/restoring-wireless-and-bluetooth-state-after-reboot-in-fedora-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/19/restoring-wireless-and-bluetooth-state-after-reboot-in-fedora-22/</guid><description>My upgrade to Fedora 22 on the ThinkPad X1 Carbon was fairly uneventful and the hiccups were minor. One of the more annoying items that I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with for quite some time is how to boot up with the wireless LAN and Bluetooth disabled by default. Restoring wireless and Bluetooth state between reboots is normally handled quite well in Fedora.
In Fedora 21, NetworkManager saved my settings between reboots. For example, if I shut down with wifi off and Bluetooth on, the laptop would boot up later with wifi off and Bluetooth on.</description></item><item><title>Log Android events remotely to a syslog server</title><link>https://major.io/2012/11/04/log-android-events-remotely-to-a-syslog-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 20:47:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/11/04/log-android-events-remotely-to-a-syslog-server/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m still quite pleased with my Samsung Galaxy SIII but there are some finicky Bluetooth issues with my car that I simply can&amp;rsquo;t figure out. After discovering logcat, I wondered if there was a way to get logs sent from an Android device to a remote syslog server. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly possible and it actually works quite well.
My phone is currently rooted with CyanogenMod 10 installed. Some of these steps will require rooting your device.</description></item></channel></rss>