<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>yum on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/yum/</link><description>Recent content in yum on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 13:53:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/yum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install testing kernels in Fedora</title><link>https://major.io/2018/02/28/install-testing-kernels-in-fedora/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/02/28/install-testing-kernels-in-fedora/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re on the latest Fedora release, you&amp;rsquo;re already running lots of modern packages. However, there are those times when you may want to help with testing efforts or try out a new feature in a newer package.
Most of my systems have the updates-testing repository enabled in one way or another. This repository contains packages that package maintainers have submitted to become the next stable package in Fedora. For example, if there is a bug fix for nginx, the package maintainer submits the changes and publish a release.</description></item><item><title>Keep old kernels with yum and dnf</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/18/keep-old-kernels-with-yum-and-dnf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 14:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/18/keep-old-kernels-with-yum-and-dnf/</guid><description>When you upgrade packages on Red Hat, CentOS and Fedora systems, the newer package replaces the older package. That means that files managed by RPM from the old package are removed and replaced with files from the newer package.
There&amp;rsquo;s one exception here: kernel packages.
Upgrading a kernel package with yum and dnf leaves the older kernel package on the system just in case you need it again. This is handy if the new kernel introduces a bug on your system or if you need to work through a compile of a custom kernel module.</description></item><item><title>Automatic package updates with dnf</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/11/automatic-package-updates-with-dnf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 01:22:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/11/automatic-package-updates-with-dnf/</guid><description>With Fedora 22&amp;rsquo;s release date quickly approaching, it&amp;rsquo;s time to familiarize yourself with dnf. It&amp;rsquo;s especially important since clean installs of Fedora 22 won&amp;rsquo;t have yum.
Almost all of the command line arguments are the same but automated updates are a little different. If you&amp;rsquo;re used to yum-updatesd, then you&amp;rsquo;ll want to look into dnf-automatic.
Installation Getting the python code and systemd unit files for automated dnf updates is a quick process:</description></item><item><title>Start Jenkins on Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/13/get-jenkins-start-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 14:39:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/13/get-jenkins-start-fedora-20/</guid><description>Installing Jenkins on Fedora 20 is quite easy thanks to the available Red Hat packages, but I ran into problems when I tried to start Jenkins. Here are the installation steps I followed:
wget -O /etc/yum.repos.d/jenkins.repo http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/redhat/jenkins.repo rpm --import http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/redhat/jenkins-ci.org.key yum -y install jenkins systemctl enable jenkins systemctl start jenkins Your first error will show up if Java isn&amp;rsquo;t installed. You can fix that by installing Java:
yum -y install java-1.</description></item><item><title>Install Debian packages without starting daemons</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/26/install-debian-packages-without-starting-daemons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 20:39:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/26/install-debian-packages-without-starting-daemons/</guid><description>My work at Rackspace has involved working with a bunch of Debian chroots lately. One problem I had was that daemons tried to start in the chroot as soon as I installed them. That created errors and made my ansible output look terrible.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to prevent daemons from starting after installing a package, just toss a few lines into /usr/sbin/policy-rc.d:
cat &amp;gt; /usr/sbin/policy-rc.d &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF #!/bin/sh echo &amp;#34;All runlevel operations denied by policy&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2 exit 101 EOF Now, install any packages that you need and the daemons will remain stopped until you start them (or reboot the server).</description></item><item><title>CoreOS vs. Project Atomic: A Review</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/13/coreos-vs-project-atomic-a-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 03:57:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/13/coreos-vs-project-atomic-a-review/</guid><description>This post hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in quite some time.Many of these comparisons still hold true but some don&amp;rsquo;t. Updating this post is on my list of to-do&amp;rsquo;s. - MH 2015-04-25
You&amp;rsquo;ve probably been living under a rock if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about Docker. It simplifies the deployment and management of Linux containers better than anything else I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far. Many ecosystems are growing with Docker at the core and two of the most popular hosting platforms for Docker are CoreOS and Project Atomic.</description></item><item><title>openssl heartbleed updates for Fedora 19 and 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/07/openssl-heartbleed-updates-for-fedora-19-and-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 01:18:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/07/openssl-heartbleed-updates-for-fedora-19-and-20/</guid><description>The openssl heartbleed bug has made the rounds today and there are two new testing builds or openssl out for Fedora 19 and 20:
Fedora 19 Fedora 20 Both builds are making their way over into the updates-testingstable repository thanks to some quick testing and karma from the Fedora community.
If the stable updates haven&amp;rsquo;t made it into your favorite mirror yet, you can live on the edge and grab the koji builds:</description></item><item><title>Keeping bwm-ng 0.6 functional on Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/19/keeping-bwm-ng-0-6-functional-on-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/19/keeping-bwm-ng-0-6-functional-on-fedora-19/</guid><description>If you run bwm-ng and you&amp;rsquo;ve run a yum upgrade lately on Fedora 19, you have probably seen this:
---&amp;gt; Package libstatgrab.x86_64 0:0.17-4.fc19 will be updated --&amp;gt; Processing Dependency: libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) for package: bwm-ng-0.6-10.fc19.x86_64 --&amp;gt; Finished Dependency Resolution Error: Package: bwm-ng-0.6-10.fc19.x86_64 (@fedora) Requires: libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) Removing: libstatgrab-0.17-4.fc19.x86_64 (@fedora) libstatgrab.so.6()(64bit) Updated By: libstatgrab-0.90-1.fc19.x86_64 (updates) ~libstatgrab.so.9()(64bit) You could try using --skip-broken to work around the problem You could try running: rpm -Va --nofiles --nodigest The error message mentions that libstatgrab needs to be updated to version 0.</description></item><item><title>Moving from OS X to Linux: Day One</title><link>https://major.io/2013/08/26/moving-from-os-x-to-linux-day-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 03:05:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/08/26/moving-from-os-x-to-linux-day-one/</guid><description>The thought of using Linux as a manager in a highly Windows- and Mac-centric corporate environment isn&amp;rsquo;t something to be taken lightly. Integrating with Active Directory, wrangling email with Microsoft Exchange, and taming quirky Microsoft office documents can be a challenge even with a well-equipped Mac. I decided to make a change after using a Mac at Rackspace for six years.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get one thing straight: I&amp;rsquo;m not a Windows or Mac basher.</description></item><item><title>A humble farewell to Seth Vidal</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</guid><description>I was shocked to see Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s email today about Seth Vidal&amp;rsquo;s passing. He was the victim of a hit and run accident while he was cycling last night. The suspect has turned himself in as of tonight.
I first met Seth at FUDCon Tempe back in 2011. We had talked off and on via email and IRC about cloud-related topics. He was interested in how we assembled our cloud offering at Rackspace and I was eager to talk to him about building cloud images and handling mirrors.</description></item><item><title>Installing the Xen hypervisor on Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/02/installing-the-xen-hypervisor-on-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 04:27:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/02/installing-the-xen-hypervisor-on-fedora-19/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while since I last posted about installing Xen on Fedora, so I figured that Fedora 19&amp;rsquo;s beta release was as good a time as any to write a new post. To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get Fedora 19 installed on your favorite hardware (or virtual machine).
Install the Xen hypervisor and tools. Also, ensure that both of the necessary daemons are running on each boot:</description></item><item><title>Automatic package updates in CentOS 6</title><link>https://major.io/2012/09/21/automatic-package-updates-in-centos-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 13:21:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/09/21/automatic-package-updates-in-centos-6/</guid><description>Automating package updates in CentOS 6 is a quick process and it ensures that your system receives the latest available security patches, bugfixes and enhancements. Although it&amp;rsquo;s easy and available right from yum on a normal CentOS 6 system, I still find that many people aren&amp;rsquo;t aware of it.
Before you enable automatic updates, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re excluding certain packages which may be integral to your system. You can either make a list of those packages now or configure the automated updates so that you&amp;rsquo;re emailed a report of what needs to be installed rather than having those packages installed automatically.</description></item><item><title>Get notifications instead of automatic updates in Scientific Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/04/get-notifications-instead-of-automatic-updates-in-scientific-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 19:01:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/04/get-notifications-instead-of-automatic-updates-in-scientific-linux/</guid><description>Scientific Linux installations have a package called yum-autoupdate by default and the package contains two files:
# rpm -ql yum-autoupdate /etc/cron.daily/yum-autoupdate /etc/sysconfig/yum-autoupdate The cron job contains the entire script to run automatic updates once a day and the configuration file controls its behavior. However, you can&amp;rsquo;t get the same functionality as Fedora&amp;rsquo;s yum-updatesd package where you can receive notifications for updates rather than automatically updating the packages.
To get those notifications in Scientific Linux, just make two small edits to this portion of /etc/cron.</description></item><item><title>Automatically upgrading to new point releases of Scientific Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2011/11/23/automatically-upgrading-to-new-point-releases-of-scientific-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/11/23/automatically-upgrading-to-new-point-releases-of-scientific-linux/</guid><description>When you install Scientific Linux, it will keep you on the same point release that you installed. For example, if you install it from a 6.0 DVD, you&amp;rsquo;ll stay on 6.0 and get security releases for that point release only.
Getting it to behave like Red Hat Enterprise Linux and CentOS is a painless process. Just install the sl6x repository with yum:
yum install yum-conf-sl6x Check to ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re getting updates from the new repository:</description></item><item><title>Live upgrade Fedora 15 to Fedora 16 using yum</title><link>https://major.io/2011/11/14/live-upgrading-fedora-15-to-fedora-16-using-yum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 04:37:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/11/14/live-upgrading-fedora-15-to-fedora-16-using-yum/</guid><description>Before we get started, I really ought to drop this here:
This begs the question: When should you use another method to upgrade Fedora? What other methods are there?
You have a few other methods to get the upgrade done:
Toss in a CD or DVD: You can upgrade via the anaconda installer provided on the CD, DVD or netinstall media. My experiences with this method for Fedora (as well as CentOS, Scientific Linux, and Red Hat) haven&amp;rsquo;t been too positive, but your results may vary.</description></item><item><title>Receive e-mail reports for SELinux AVC denials</title><link>https://major.io/2011/09/15/receive-e-mail-reports-for-selinux-avc-denials/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 04:17:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/09/15/receive-e-mail-reports-for-selinux-avc-denials/</guid><description>SELinux isn&amp;rsquo;t a technology that&amp;rsquo;s easy to tackle for newcomers. However, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of work to smooth out the rough edges while still keeping a tight grip on what applications and users are allowed to do on a Linux system. One of the biggest efforts has been around setroubleshoot.
The purpose behind setroubleshoot is to let users know when access has been denied, help them resolve it if necessary, and to reduce overall frustration while working through tight security restrictions in the default SELinux policies.</description></item><item><title>Keep all old kernels when upgrading via yum</title><link>https://major.io/2011/06/16/keep-all-old-kernels-when-upgrading-via-yum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 12:50:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/06/16/keep-all-old-kernels-when-upgrading-via-yum/</guid><description>Some might call me paranoid, but I get nervous when my package manager automatically removes a kernel. I logged into my Fedora 15 VM this morning and found this:
================================================================================ Package Arch Version Repository Size ================================================================================ Installing: kernel x86_64 2.6.35.13-92.fc14 updates 22 M Removing: kernel x86_64 2.6.35.11-83.fc14 @updates 104 M Transaction Summary ================================================================================ Install 1 Package(s) Remove 1 Package(s) Fedora 15&amp;rsquo;s default behavior is to keep three kernels: the latest one and the two previous versions.</description></item><item><title>Locate RPM packages which contain a certain file</title><link>https://major.io/2010/12/08/locate-rpm-packages-which-contain-a-certain-file/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/12/08/locate-rpm-packages-which-contain-a-certain-file/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy remembering which RPM packages contain certain files. If I asked you which files you&amp;rsquo;d find in packages like postfix-2.7.1-1.fc14 and bash-4.1.7-3.fc14, you would be able to name some obvious executables. However, would you be able to do the same if I mentioned a package like util-linux-ng-2.18-4.6.fc14? If the RPM is already installed, you can quickly use rpm -ql to list the files within it.
However, what if the RPM isn&amp;rsquo;t installed already?</description></item><item><title>Tap into your Linux system with SystemTap</title><link>https://major.io/2010/12/07/tap-into-your-linux-system-with-systemtap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 02:27:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/12/07/tap-into-your-linux-system-with-systemtap/</guid><description>One of the most interesting topics I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far during my RHCA training at Rackspace this week is SystemTap. In short, SystemTap allows you to dig out a bunch of details about your running system relatively easily. It takes scripts, converts them to C, builds a kernel module, and then runs the code within your script.
HOLD IT:The steps below are definitely not meant for those who are new to Linux.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Fedora 13 to Fedora 14 on Slicehost and Rackspace Cloud Servers</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/03/upgrading-fedora-13-to-fedora-14-on-slicehost-and-rackspace-cloud-servers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 20:02:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/03/upgrading-fedora-13-to-fedora-14-on-slicehost-and-rackspace-cloud-servers/</guid><description>On most systems, using Fedora&amp;rsquo;s preupgrade package is the most reliable way to update to the next Fedora release. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case with Slicehost and Rackspace Cloud Servers.
Here are the steps for an upgrade from Fedora 13 to Fedora 14 via yum:
yum -y upgrade wget http://mirror.rackspace.com/fedora/releases/14/Fedora/x86_64/os/Packages/fedora-release-14-1.noarch.rpm rpm -Uvh fedora-release-14-1.noarch.rpm yum -y install yum yum -y upgrade If you happen to be upgrading a 32-bit instance on Slicehost, simply replace x86_64 with i386 in the url shown above.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Fedora 11 to 12 using yum</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/07/upgrading-fedora-11-to-12-using-yum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 02:28:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/07/upgrading-fedora-11-to-12-using-yum/</guid><description>As with the Fedora 10 to 11 upgrade, you can upgrade Fedora 11 to Fedora 12 using yum. I find this to be the easiest and most reliable way to upgrade a Fedora installation whether you use it as a server or desktop.
To reduce the total data downloaded, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend installing the yum-presto package first. It downloads delta RPM&amp;rsquo;s and builds them on the fly, which allows you to upgrade packages without having to download the entire RPM&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 11 httpd: alloc_listener: failed to get a socket for (null)</title><link>https://major.io/2009/08/14/fedora-11-httpd-alloc_listener-failed-to-get-a-socket-for-null/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 17:14:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/08/14/fedora-11-httpd-alloc_listener-failed-to-get-a-socket-for-null/</guid><description>If you use Fedora 11 in a virtualized environment, you may have seen this error recently if you&amp;rsquo;ve updated to apr-1.3.8-1:
The issue is related to three kernel calls that are used in apr-1.3.8-1: accept4(), dup3() and epoll_create1(). Without these calls, apache is unable to start.
Update on August 17, 2009:the Fedora team has pushed apr-1.3.8-2 into the stable repositories for Fedora 11, which eliminates the need for the temporary fix shown below.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading from Fedora 10 (Cambridge) to Fedora 11 (Leonidas)</title><link>https://major.io/2009/06/11/upgrading-from-fedora-10-cambridge-to-fedora-11-leonidas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 17:48:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/06/11/upgrading-from-fedora-10-cambridge-to-fedora-11-leonidas/</guid><description>There are two main ways to upgrade Fedora 10 (Cambridge) to Fedora 11 (Leonidas):
» What the Fedora developers suggest:
Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re doing this on a Fedora desktop, you can use preupgrade (rather than preupgrade-cli) to upgrade with a GUI.
» The method I prefer (and it works properly on Slicehost):
At this point, you would normally just start upgrading packages, but the Fedora developers threw us a curveball.</description></item><item><title>rpmdb: Lock table is out of available locker entries</title><link>https://major.io/2007/05/27/rpmdb-lock-table-is-out-of-available-locker-entries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2007 16:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/05/27/rpmdb-lock-table-is-out-of-available-locker-entries/</guid><description>If up2date throws some horrible Python errors and rpm says “rpmdb: Lock table is out of available locker entries”, you can restore your system to normality with the following:
The errors:
rpmdb: Lock table is out of available locker entries error: db4 error(22) from db-&amp;gt;close: Invalid argument error: cannot open Packages index using db3 - Cannot allocate memory (12) error: cannot open Packages database in /var/lib/rpm Make a backup of /var/lib/rpm in case you break something:</description></item></channel></rss>