<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>syslog on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/syslog/</link><description>Recent content in syslog on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:55:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/syslog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure remote syslog for XenServer via the command line</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/03/configure-remote-syslog-for-xenserver-via-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:55:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/03/configure-remote-syslog-for-xenserver-via-the-command-line/</guid><description>Citrix has some helpful documentation online about configuring remote syslog support for XenServer using the XenCenter GUI. However, if you need to do this via configuration management or scripts, using a GUI isn&amp;rsquo;t an option.
Getting it done via the command line is relatively easy:
HOSTUUID=`xe host-list --minimal` SYSLOGHOST=syslog.example.com xe host-param-set uuid=${HOSTUUID} logging:syslog_destination=${SYSLOGHOST} xe host-syslog-reconfigure host-uuid=${HOSTUUID} Removing the configuration and going back to only local logging is easy as well:</description></item><item><title>Log Android events remotely to a syslog server</title><link>https://major.io/2012/11/04/log-android-events-remotely-to-a-syslog-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 20:47:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/11/04/log-android-events-remotely-to-a-syslog-server/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m still quite pleased with my Samsung Galaxy SIII but there are some finicky Bluetooth issues with my car that I simply can&amp;rsquo;t figure out. After discovering logcat, I wondered if there was a way to get logs sent from an Android device to a remote syslog server. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly possible and it actually works quite well.
My phone is currently rooted with CyanogenMod 10 installed. Some of these steps will require rooting your device.</description></item><item><title>Piping log files to a syslog server</title><link>https://major.io/2009/04/21/piping-log-files-to-a-syslog-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 22:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/04/21/piping-log-files-to-a-syslog-server/</guid><description>If you have a centralized syslog server, or you use Splunk for log tracking, you may find the need to get older log files into a syslog port on that server.
Edit: Using logger (as suggested by David and Jerry below) will give you a more reliable way to send the data to a syslog server:
You&amp;rsquo;ll also be able to set a label for the text before it&amp;rsquo;s piped into the syslog server, which would be handy if you&amp;rsquo;re sorting or parsing the data later on.</description></item></channel></rss>