<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>encryption on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/encryption/</link><description>Recent content in encryption on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 13:47:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/encryption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTTP/2 for the blog and icanhazip.com</title><link>https://major.io/2016/09/13/http2-for-the-blog-and-icanhazip-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 13:47:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/09/13/http2-for-the-blog-and-icanhazip-com/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated this blog and icanhazip.com to enable HTTP/2! This probably won&amp;rsquo;t have much of an effect on users who query icanhazip.com with automated tools, but it should deliver the content on this blog a little faster. If you&amp;rsquo;re using an older, non-HTTP/2 client - don&amp;rsquo;t worry. All of the sites will continue working for you as they always have.
Head on over to Wikipedia to learn more about HTTP/2 and its benefits.</description></item><item><title>Quick access to OpenPGP tasks with GPGTools in OS X</title><link>https://major.io/2013/02/08/quick-access-to-openpgp-tasks-with-gpgtools-in-os-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 19:05:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/02/08/quick-access-to-openpgp-tasks-with-gpgtools-in-os-x/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of the GPGTools suite for Mac for quite a while but I discovered some neat features when right-clicking on a file in Finder today. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit disappointing that I didn&amp;rsquo;t find these sooner!
Encrypting files is simple: just click OpenPGP: Encrypt File and a window will pop asking you which key you&amp;rsquo;d like to use for encryption. You also have the option of encrypting it with a password.</description></item><item><title>Private network interfaces: the forgotten security hole</title><link>https://major.io/2010/03/01/private-network-interfaces-the-forgotten-security-hole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:55:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/03/01/private-network-interfaces-the-forgotten-security-hole/</guid><description>Regardless of the type of hosting you&amp;rsquo;re using - dedicated or cloud - it&amp;rsquo;s important to take network interface security seriously. Most often, threats from the internet are the only ones mentioned. However, if you share a private network with other customers, you have just as much risk on that interface.
Many cloud providers allow you access to a private network environment where you can exchange data with other instances or other services offered by the provider.</description></item><item><title>Encrypted filesystems and partitions on RHEL 5</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/01/encrypted-filesystems-and-partitions-on-rhel-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 01:55:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/01/encrypted-filesystems-and-partitions-on-rhel-5/</guid><description>I spoke with a customer last week who was curious about enabling encrypted partitions on a DAS connected to their server. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely sure if it was possible in RHEL 5 since I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember if it was available in Fedora 6. According to Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s release notes, it is possible. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from their release notes:  Encrypted Swap Partitions and Non-root File Systems
Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 now provides basic support for encrypted swap partitions and non-root file systems.</description></item></channel></rss>