<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>auditd on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/auditd/</link><description>Recent content in auditd on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 15:53:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/auditd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Display auditd messages with journalctl</title><link>https://major.io/2017/01/05/display-auditd-messages-with-journalctl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 15:53:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/01/05/display-auditd-messages-with-journalctl/</guid><description>All systems running systemd come with a powerful tool for reviewing the system journal: journalctl. It allows you to get a quick look at the system journal while also allowing you to heavily customize your view of the log.
I logged into a server recently that was having a problem and I found that the audit logs weren&amp;rsquo;t going into syslog. That&amp;rsquo;s no problem - they&amp;rsquo;re in the system journal. The system journal was filled with tons of other messages, so I decided to limit the output only to messages from the auditd unit:</description></item><item><title>augenrules fails with “rule exists” when loading rules into auditd</title><link>https://major.io/2017/01/03/augenrules-fails-with-rule-exists-when-loading-rules-into-auditd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 19:01:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/01/03/augenrules-fails-with-rule-exists-when-loading-rules-into-auditd/</guid><description>When I came back from the holiday break, I found that the openstack-ansible-security role wasn&amp;rsquo;t passing tests any longer. The Ansible playbook stopped when augenrules ran to load the new audit rules. The error wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly helpful:
/usr/sbin/augenrules: No change Error sending add rule data request (Rule exists) There was an error in line 5 of /etc/audit/audit.rules A duplicated rule? I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on lots of changes to implement the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG) and I assumed I put in the same rule twice with an errant copy and paste.</description></item></channel></rss>