<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>presentation on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/presentation/</link><description>Recent content in presentation on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevConf.CZ 2019 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2019/01/31/devconf.cz-2019-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/01/31/devconf.cz-2019-recap/</guid><description>DevConf.CZ 2019 wrapped up last weekend and it was a great event packed with lots of knowledgeable speakers, an engaging hallway track, and delicious food. This was my first trip to any DevConf and it was my second trip to Brno.
Lots of snow showed up on the second day and more snow arrived later in the week!
First talk of 2019 I co-presented a talk with one of my teammates, Nikolai, about some of the fun work we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing at Red Hat to improve the quality of the Linux kernel in an automated way.</description></item><item><title>Reaching the fork in the road</title><link>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:18:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</guid><description>Walt Disney said it best:
We keep moving forward, opening new doors, and doing new things, because we&amp;rsquo;re curious and curiosity keeps leading us down new paths.
The world of technology is all about change. We tear down the old things that get in our way and we build new technology that takes us to new heights. Tearing down these old things can often be difficult and that forces us to make difficult choices.</description></item><item><title>Talk Recap: Holistic Security for OpenStack Clouds</title><link>https://major.io/2016/10/31/talk-recap-holistic-security-for-openstack-clouds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 15:52:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/10/31/talk-recap-holistic-security-for-openstack-clouds/</guid><description>Thanks to everyone who attended my talk at the OpenStack Summit in Barcelona! I really enjoyed sharing some tips with the audience and it was great to meet some attendees in person afterwards.
If you weren&amp;rsquo;t able to make it, don&amp;rsquo;t fret! This post will cover some of the main points of the talk and link to the video and slides.
Purpose OpenStack clouds are inherently complex. Operating a cloud involves a lot of moving pieces in software, hardware, and networking.</description></item><item><title>Talking to college students about information security</title><link>https://major.io/2015/11/10/talking-to-college-students-about-information-security/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:50:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/11/10/talking-to-college-students-about-information-security/</guid><description>I was recently asked to talk to Computer Information Systems students at the University of the Incarnate Word here in San Antonio about information security in the business world. The students are learning plenty of the technical parts of information security and the complexity that comes from dealing with complicated computer networks. As we all know, it&amp;rsquo;s the non-technical things that are often the most important in those tough situations.</description></item><item><title>Impostor syndrome talk: FAQs and follow-ups</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/02/impostor-syndrome-talk-faqs-and-follow-ups/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 15:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/02/impostor-syndrome-talk-faqs-and-follow-ups/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a great time talking to people about my &amp;ldquo;Be an inspiration, not an impostor&amp;rdquo; talk that I delivered in August. I spoke to audiences at Fedora Flock 2015, Texas Linux Fest, and at Rackspace. The biggest lesson I learned is that delivering talks is exhausting!
Frequently Asked Questions Someone asked a good one at Fedora Flock:
How do you deal with situations where you are an impostor for a reason you can&amp;rsquo;t change?</description></item><item><title>Slides from my Texas Linux Fest 2015 talk</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/22/slides-from-my-texas-linux-fest-2015-talk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 19:42:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/22/slides-from-my-texas-linux-fest-2015-talk/</guid><description>Thanks to all of the people who attended my &amp;ldquo;Be an inspiration, not an impostor&amp;rdquo; talk at Texas Linux Fest 2015. Some A/V issues caused my time slot to get squeezed and the audience had to put up with the &amp;ldquo;ludicrous speed&amp;rdquo; version of the presentation.
The slides are a little different from the slides at Fedora Flock, but they&amp;rsquo;re mainly the same:</description></item><item><title>Fedora Flock 2015: Keynote slides</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/14/fedora-flock-2015-keynote-slides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 15:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/14/fedora-flock-2015-keynote-slides/</guid><description>Fedora Flock 2015 is still going here in Rochester, New York, and I kicked off our second day with a keynote talk about overcoming impostor syndrome.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to review the slides, they&amp;rsquo;re on SlideShare:
Quite a few people came up after the talk and throughout the day to share some of their stories and challenges. It was extremely rewarding to have those conversations and share solutions.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing the talk once more at Texas Linux Fest in San Marcos on August 22.</description></item></channel></rss>