<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>red hat on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/red-hat/</link><description>Recent content in red hat on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/red-hat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevConf.CZ 2019 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2019/01/31/devconf.cz-2019-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/01/31/devconf.cz-2019-recap/</guid><description>DevConf.CZ 2019 wrapped up last weekend and it was a great event packed with lots of knowledgeable speakers, an engaging hallway track, and delicious food. This was my first trip to any DevConf and it was my second trip to Brno.
Lots of snow showed up on the second day and more snow arrived later in the week!
First talk of 2019 I co-presented a talk with one of my teammates, Nikolai, about some of the fun work we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing at Red Hat to improve the quality of the Linux kernel in an automated way.</description></item><item><title>How to thrive at a technical conference</title><link>https://major.io/2018/05/09/how-to-thrive-at-a-tech-conference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 23:54:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/05/09/how-to-thrive-at-a-tech-conference/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m at the 2018 Red Hat Summit this week in San Francisco and I am enjoying the interactions between developers, executives, vendors, and engineers. It&amp;rsquo;s my seventh Summit (but my first as a Red Hat employee!), but I regularly meet people who are attending their first technical conference.
The question inevitably comes up: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. How do you survive these events?&amp;rdquo;
One attendee asked me to write a blog post on my tips and tricks.</description></item><item><title>Changes in RHEL 7 Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 1, Release 3</title><link>https://major.io/2017/11/02/changes-in-rhel-7-security-technical-implementation-guide-version-1-release-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/11/02/changes-in-rhel-7-security-technical-implementation-guide-version-1-release-3/</guid><description>The latest release of the Red Hat Enterprise Linux Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG) was published last week. This release is Version 1, Release 3, and it contains four main changes:
V-77819 - Multifactor authentication is required for graphical logins V-77821 - Datagram Congestion Control Protocol (DCCP) kernel module must be disabled V-77823 - Single user mode must require user authentication V-77825 - Address space layout randomization (ASLR) must be enabled Deep dive Let&amp;rsquo;s break down this list to understand what each one means.</description></item><item><title>RHEL 7 STIG v1 updates for openstack-ansible-security</title><link>https://major.io/2017/04/05/rhel-7-stig-v1-updates-for-openstack-ansible-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 17:46:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/04/05/rhel-7-stig-v1-updates-for-openstack-ansible-security/</guid><description>DISA&amp;rsquo;s final release of the Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 7 Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG) came out a few weeks ago and it has plenty of improvements and changes. The openstack-ansible-security role has already been updated with these changes.
Quite a few duplicated STIG controls were removed and a few new ones were added. Some of the controls in the pre-release were difficult to implement, especially those that changed parameters for PKI-based authentication.</description></item><item><title>Talk recap: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2016/06/28/talk-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 03:43:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/06/28/talk-recap/</guid><description>The 2016 Red Hat Summit is underway in San Francisco this week and I delivered a talk with Robyn Bergeron earlier today. Our talk, When flexibility met simplicity: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible, explained how Ansible can reduce the complexity of OpenStack environments without sacrificing the flexibility that private clouds offer.
The talk started at the same time as lunch began and the Partner Pavilion first opened, so we had some stiff competition for attendees' attention.</description></item><item><title>My list of must-see sessions at Red Hat Summit 2016</title><link>https://major.io/2016/06/26/almost-time-red-hat-summit-2016/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 10:52:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/06/26/almost-time-red-hat-summit-2016/</guid><description>The Red Hat Summit starts this week in San Francisco, and a few folks asked me about the sessions that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss. The schedule can be overwhelming for first timers and it can be difficult at times to discern the technical sessions from the ones that are more sales-oriented.
If you&amp;rsquo;re in San Francisco, and you want to learn a bit more about using Ansible to manage OpenStack environments, come to the session that I am co-presenting with Robyn Bergeron: When flexibility met simplicity: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible.</description></item><item><title>New SELinux shirts are available</title><link>https://major.io/2016/06/16/new-selinux-shirts-available/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 21:22:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/06/16/new-selinux-shirts-available/</guid><description>With the upcoming Red Hat Summit 2016 in San Francisco almost upon us, I decided to update the old SELinux shirts with two new designs:
You can buy these now over at Spreadshirt! There are styles there for men and women and I&amp;rsquo;ve priced them as low as the store will allow.
Spreadshirt is also running a sale for 15% off T-shirts until June 21st with the code TSHIRT16. Let&amp;rsquo;s make SELinux enforcing again!</description></item><item><title>Research Paper: Securing Linux Containers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/14/research-paper-securing-linux-containers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 20:45:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/14/research-paper-securing-linux-containers/</guid><description>It seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a new way to run containers every week. The advantages and drawbacks of each approach are argued about on mailing lists, in IRC channels, and in person, around the world. However, the largest amount of confusion seems to be around security.
Launching secure containers I&amp;rsquo;ve written about launching secure containers on this blog many times before:
Launch secure LXC containers on Fedora 20 using SELinux and sVirt Improving LXC template security Try out LXC with an Ansible playbook CoreOS vs.</description></item><item><title>Allow new windows to steal focus in GNOME 3</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/06/allow-new-windows-to-steal-focus-in-gnome-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 12:36:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/06/allow-new-windows-to-steal-focus-in-gnome-3/</guid><description>GNOME 3 generally works well for me but it has some quirks. One of those quirks is that new windows don&amp;rsquo;t actually pop up on the screen with focus as they do in Windows and OS X. When opening a new window, you get a “[Windowname] is ready” notification:
My preference is for new windows to pop in front and steal focus. I can see why that&amp;rsquo;s not the default since it might cause you to type something in another window where you weren&amp;rsquo;t expecting to.</description></item><item><title>Improving LXC template security</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/18/improving-lxc-template-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 19:52:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/18/improving-lxc-template-security/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting involved with the Fedora Security Team lately and we&amp;rsquo;re working as a group to crush security bugs that affect Fedora, CentOS (via EPEL) and Red Hat Enterprise Linux (via EPEL). During some of this work, I stumbled upon a group of Red Hat Bugzilla tickets talking about LXC template security.
The gist of the problem is that there&amp;rsquo;s a wide variance in how users and user credentials are handled by the different LXC templates.</description></item><item><title>Keep old kernels with yum and dnf</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/18/keep-old-kernels-with-yum-and-dnf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 14:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/18/keep-old-kernels-with-yum-and-dnf/</guid><description>When you upgrade packages on Red Hat, CentOS and Fedora systems, the newer package replaces the older package. That means that files managed by RPM from the old package are removed and replaced with files from the newer package.
There&amp;rsquo;s one exception here: kernel packages.
Upgrading a kernel package with yum and dnf leaves the older kernel package on the system just in case you need it again. This is handy if the new kernel introduces a bug on your system or if you need to work through a compile of a custom kernel module.</description></item><item><title>Creating a bridge for virtual machines using systemd-networkd</title><link>https://major.io/2015/03/26/creating-a-bridge-for-virtual-machines-using-systemd-networkd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 13:17:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/03/26/creating-a-bridge-for-virtual-machines-using-systemd-networkd/</guid><description>There are plenty of guides out there for making ethernet bridges in Linux to support virtual machines using built-in network scripts or NetworkManager. I decided to try my hand with creating a bridge using only systemd-networkd and it was surprisingly easy.
First off, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a version of systemd with networkd support. Fedora 20 and 21 will work just fine. RHEL/CentOS 7 and Arch Linux should also work. Much of the networkd support has been in systemd for quite a while, but if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for fancier network settings, like bonding, you&amp;rsquo;ll want at least systemd 216.</description></item><item><title>Install sysstat on Fedora 21</title><link>https://major.io/2014/12/12/install-sysstat-fedora-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 17:55:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/12/12/install-sysstat-fedora-21/</guid><description>One of the first tools I learned about after working with Red Hat was sysstat. It can write down historical records about your server at regular intervals. This can help you diagnose CPU usage, RAM usage, or network usage problems. In addition, sysstat also provides some handy command line utilities like vmstat, iostat, and pidstat that give you a live view of what your system is doing.
On Debian-based systems (including Ubuntu), you install the sysstat package and enable it with a quick edit to /etc/default/sysstat and the cron job takes it from there.</description></item><item><title>Trust an IP address with firewalld’s rich rules</title><link>https://major.io/2014/11/24/trust-ip-address-firewallds-rich-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/11/24/trust-ip-address-firewallds-rich-rules/</guid><description>Managing firewall rules with iptables can be tricky at times. The rule syntax itself isn&amp;rsquo;t terribly difficult but you can quickly run into problems if you don&amp;rsquo;t save your rules to persistent storage after you get your firewall configured. Things can also get out of hand quickly if you run a lot of different tables with jumps scattered through each.
Why FirewallD? FirewallD&amp;rsquo;s goal is to make this process a bit easier by adding a daemon to the mix.</description></item><item><title>A response to Infoworld’s confusing article about Fedora</title><link>https://major.io/2014/11/19/response-infoworlds-confusing-article-fedora/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 14:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/11/19/response-infoworlds-confusing-article-fedora/</guid><description>Working with the Fedora community is something I really enjoy in my spare time and I was baffled by a article I saw in Infoworld earlier last week. Here&amp;rsquo;s a link:
Red Hat confuses Linux users with latest Fedora moves
The article dives into the productization of Fedora 21 that hopes to deliver a better experience for workstation, server, and cloud users. The article suggests that Red Hat drove Fedora development and that the goals of Red Hat and Fedora are closely aligned.</description></item><item><title>Install Debian packages without starting daemons</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/26/install-debian-packages-without-starting-daemons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 20:39:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/26/install-debian-packages-without-starting-daemons/</guid><description>My work at Rackspace has involved working with a bunch of Debian chroots lately. One problem I had was that daemons tried to start in the chroot as soon as I installed them. That created errors and made my ansible output look terrible.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to prevent daemons from starting after installing a package, just toss a few lines into /usr/sbin/policy-rc.d:
cat &amp;gt; /usr/sbin/policy-rc.d &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF #!/bin/sh echo &amp;#34;All runlevel operations denied by policy&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2 exit 101 EOF Now, install any packages that you need and the daemons will remain stopped until you start them (or reboot the server).</description></item><item><title>Performance benchmarks: KVM vs. Xen</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/22/performance-benchmarks-kvm-vs-xen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/22/performance-benchmarks-kvm-vs-xen/</guid><description>After having some interesting discussions last week around KVM and Xen performance improvements over the past years, I decided to do a little research on my own. The last complete set of benchmarks I could find were from the Phoronix Haswell tests in 2013. There were some other benchmarks from 2011 but those were hotly debated due to the Xen patches headed into kernel 3.0.
The 2011 tests had a good list of benchmarks and I&amp;rsquo;ve done my best to replicate that list here three years later.</description></item><item><title>Getting Dell’s racadm working in Fedora 20</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/20/getting-dells-racadm-working-in-fedora-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 14:39:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/20/getting-dells-racadm-working-in-fedora-20/</guid><description>Dell provides the racadm software on Linux that allows you to manage Dell hardware from a Linux system. Getting it installed on a very modern distribution like Fedora 20 isn&amp;rsquo;t supported, but here are some steps that might help you along the way:
First off, go to Dell&amp;rsquo;s site and review the racadm download instructions. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend following the Remote RACADM instructions so that you can manage multiple systems from your Fedora installation.</description></item><item><title>Text missing in chrome on Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/17/text-missing-in-chrome-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 04:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/17/text-missing-in-chrome-on-linux/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of trying Fedora 20 on my retina MacBook and I ran into a peculiar issue with Chrome. Some sites would load up normally and I could read everything on the page. Other sites would load up and only some of the text would be displayed. Images were totally unaffected.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t this way on the initial installation of Fedora but it cropped up somewhere along the way as I installed software.</description></item><item><title>Launch secure LXC containers on Fedora 20 using SELinux and sVirt</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/21/launch-secure-lxc-containers-on-fedora-20-using-selinux-and-svirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 04:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/21/launch-secure-lxc-containers-on-fedora-20-using-selinux-and-svirt/</guid><description>Getting started with LXC is a bit awkward and I&amp;rsquo;ve assembled this guide for anyone who wants to begin experimenting with LXC containers in Fedora 20. As an added benefit, you can follow almost every step shown here when creating LXC containers on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Beta (which is based on Fedora 19).
You&amp;rsquo;ll need a physical machine or a VM running Fedora 20 to get started. (You could put a container in a container, but things get a little dicey with that setup.</description></item><item><title>CentOS and Red Hat join forces</title><link>https://major.io/2014/01/08/centos-and-red-hat-join-forces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 20:23:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/01/08/centos-and-red-hat-join-forces/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to congratulate the CentOS project on their big news yesterday. The CentOS website received a refresh and there&amp;rsquo;s a new concept of variants being proposed. After talking to Karanbir Singh and Robyn Bergeron yesterday, it was obvious that they&amp;rsquo;re both really excited about the changes.
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for more details on the changes, here are some handy links:
Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s blog post Red Hat and CentOS FAQ The media coverage has some entertaining headlines:</description></item><item><title>A humble farewell to Seth Vidal</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</guid><description>I was shocked to see Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s email today about Seth Vidal&amp;rsquo;s passing. He was the victim of a hit and run accident while he was cycling last night. The suspect has turned himself in as of tonight.
I first met Seth at FUDCon Tempe back in 2011. We had talked off and on via email and IRC about cloud-related topics. He was interested in how we assembled our cloud offering at Rackspace and I was eager to talk to him about building cloud images and handling mirrors.</description></item><item><title>Supermicro X9SCI/X9SCA server does a shutdown rather than a reboot</title><link>https://major.io/2013/06/03/supermicro-x9scix9sca-server-does-a-shutdown-rather-than-a-reboot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 14:45:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/06/03/supermicro-x9scix9sca-server-does-a-shutdown-rather-than-a-reboot/</guid><description>Most of my websites run on a pair of Supermicro servers that I purchased from Silicon Mechanics (and I can&amp;rsquo;t say enough good things about them and their servers). One problem that kept cropping up was that the servers would become unresponsive during a reboot. If I issued the reboot command in Linux, the machine would begin the reboot process, power off, and remain powered off.
Needless to say, this is highly annoying.</description></item><item><title>Migrate KVM virtual machines from CentOS 6 to Fedora 18 without the luxury of shared storage</title><link>https://major.io/2013/05/22/migrate-kvm-virtual-machines-from-centos-6-to-fedora-18-without-the-luxury-of-shared-storage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 15:15:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/05/22/migrate-kvm-virtual-machines-from-centos-6-to-fedora-18-without-the-luxury-of-shared-storage/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve converted one of my KVM hypervisors from CentOS 6 to Fedora 18 and now comes the task of migrating my virtual machines off of my single remaining CentOS 6 hypervisor. This is definitely on a budget, so there&amp;rsquo;s no shared storage to make this process easier.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it:
Migrate the logical volume
My first VM to migrate is my Fedora development VM where I build and test new packages.</description></item><item><title>Handling terminal color escape sequences in less</title><link>https://major.io/2013/05/21/handling-terminal-color-escape-sequences-in-less/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 02:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/05/21/handling-terminal-color-escape-sequences-in-less/</guid><description>This post is a quick one but I wanted to share it since I taught it to someone new today. When you have bash output with colors, less doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle the color codes properly by default:
$ colordiff chunk/functions.php chunk-old/functions.php | less ESC[0;32m22a23,27ESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; * Load up our functions for grabbing content from postsESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; */ESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; require( get_template_directory() . '/content-grabbers.php' );ESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; ESC[0;0m Toss in the -R flag and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see the colors properly (no colors to see here, but use your imagination):</description></item></channel></rss>