<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fedora on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/fedora/</link><description>Recent content in fedora on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/fedora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Efficient emojis with rofimoji</title><link>https://major.io/2021/05/15/efficient-emojis-with-rofimoji/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/05/15/efficient-emojis-with-rofimoji/</guid><description>Emojis brighten up any message or document. They also serve as excellent methods for testing whether your application handles strings appropriately. (This can be a lot of fun.) 🤭
I constantly obsess with efficiency and shortening the time and effort required to get my work done. I noticed that I could type short text emoticons like :) and ;) so much faster than I could use emojis. This simply would not do.</description></item><item><title>Build AWS images with Image Builder</title><link>https://major.io/2020/06/19/build-aws-images-with-imagebuilder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/06/19/build-aws-images-with-imagebuilder/</guid><description>The AMIs provided by most Linux distributions in AWS work well for most use cases. However, there are those times when you need a customized image to support a certain configuration or to speed up CI processes.
You can get a customized image via a few methods:
Build from an existing AMI, customize it, and snapshot it. Use an automated tool, such as Packer, to automate #1. Build your own image locally in KVM, VMware, or Virtualbox and upload the image into S3, import it into an EC2, and create an AMI from the snapshot.</description></item><item><title>Make diacritics easy in Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2020/02/13/make-diacritics-easy-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/02/13/make-diacritics-easy-in-linux/</guid><description>Diacritics are all of the small things that are added on, above, or below certain characters in various languages. Some examples include tildes (ñ), accents (á), or other marks (š). These marks are little hints that help you know how to pronounce a word properly (and they sometimes change the definition of a word entirely).
They are often skipped by non-native language speakers, and sometimes even by native speakers, but I have done my best to make a habit of including them when I can.</description></item><item><title>Disable Nvidia GPU on the Thinkpad T490</title><link>https://major.io/2020/01/24/disable-nvidia-gpu-thinkpad-t490/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/01/24/disable-nvidia-gpu-thinkpad-t490/</guid><description>I wrote about installing Linux on the Lenovo ThinkPad T490 last month and one of the biggest challenges was getting graphics working properly. The T490 comes with an option where you can get a discrete Nvidia MX250 GPU and it packs plenty of power in a small footprint.
It also brings along a few issues.
Awful battery life There are many times where it would be helpful to fully disable the Nvidia card to extend battery life when graphics processing is not needed.</description></item><item><title>Bring Back Fedora's Beefy Miracle boot splash</title><link>https://major.io/2019/12/16/bring-back-fedora-beefy-miracle-boot-splash.md/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/12/16/bring-back-fedora-beefy-miracle-boot-splash.md/</guid><description>Way back in 2012 when Fedora releases had names, there was one release that many of us in the Fedora community will never forget. Fedora 17&amp;rsquo;s code name was &amp;ldquo;Beefy Miracle&amp;rdquo; and it caused plenty of giggles and lots of consternation (especially in vegetarian and vegan circles).
No matter how you feel about the code name, the mascot was really good:
Major and the beefy miracle in 2012</description></item><item><title>Thinkpad T490 Fedora install tips</title><link>https://major.io/2019/12/12/thinkpad-t490-fedora-install-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/12/12/thinkpad-t490-fedora-install-tips/</guid><description>🔨 WORK IN PROGRESS! I&amp;rsquo;m still finding some additional issues and I&amp;rsquo;ll write those up here as soon as I find some solutions.
Thinkpad T490 With my 4th Gen X1 Carbon beginning to age (especially the battery), it was time for an upgrade. I now have a T490 with a 10th gen Intel CPU and a discrete NVIDIA MX250 GPU. This laptop spec was just released on Black Friday!</description></item><item><title>Monitor CyberPower UPS wattage</title><link>https://major.io/2019/11/08/monitor-cyberpower-ups-wattage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/11/08/monitor-cyberpower-ups-wattage/</guid><description>I have a CyberPower CP1350AVRLCD under my desk at home and I use it to run my computer, monitors, speakers, and a lamp. My new computer is a little more power hungry than my old one since I just moved to to a Ryzen 3700x and Nvidia GeForce 2060 and I like to keep tabs on how much energy it is consuming.
Some power supplies offer a monitoring interface where you can watch your power consumption in real time, but I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to spend that much money.</description></item><item><title>Install Chromium with VAAPI on Fedora 30</title><link>https://major.io/2019/10/20/install-chromium-with-vaapi-on-fedora-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/10/20/install-chromium-with-vaapi-on-fedora-30/</guid><description>UPDATE: The chromium-vaapi package is now chromium-freeworld. This post was updated on 2019-11-06 to include the change. See the end of the post for the update steps.
If you use a web browser to watch videos on a laptop, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably noticed that some videos play without much impact on the battery. Other videos cause the fans to spin wildly and your battery life plummets.
Intel designed a specification called VA API, often called VAAPI (without the space), and it offers up device drivers to applications running on your system.</description></item><item><title>Customize GNOME from i3</title><link>https://major.io/2019/09/22/customize-gnome-from-i3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/09/22/customize-gnome-from-i3/</guid><description>i3 has been my window manager of choice for a while and I really enjoy its simplicity and ease of use. I use plenty of gtk applications, such as Firefox and Evolution, and configuring them within i3 can be confusing.
This post covers a few methods to change configurations for GNOME and gtk applications from i3.
lxappearance Almost all of the gtk theming settings are available in lxappearance. You can change fonts, mouse cursors, icons, and colors.</description></item><item><title>Get faster GitLab runners with a ramdisk</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/16/get-faster-gitlab-runners-with-a-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/16/get-faster-gitlab-runners-with-a-ramdisk/</guid><description>When you build tons of kernels every day like my team does, you look for speed improvements anywhere you can. Caching repositories, artifacts, and compiled objects makes kernel builds faster and it reduces infrastructure costs.
Need for speed We use GitLab CI in plenty of places, and that means we have a lot of gitlab-runner configurations for OpenShift (using the kubernetes executor) and AWS (using the docker-machine executor). The runner&amp;rsquo;s built-in caching makes it easy to upload and download cached items from object storage repositories like Google Cloud Storage or Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>buildah error: vfs driver does not support overlay.mountopt options</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/13/buildah-error-vfs-driver-does-not-support-overlay-mountopt-options/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/13/buildah-error-vfs-driver-does-not-support-overlay-mountopt-options/</guid><description>Buildah and podman make a great pair for building, managing and running containers on a Linux system. You can even use them with GitLab CI with a few small adjustments, namely the switch from the overlayfs to vfs storage driver.
I have some regularly scheduled GitLab CI jobs that attempt to build fresh containers each morning and I use these to get the latest packages and find out early when something is broken in the build process.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 30 on Google Compute Engine</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/07/fedora-30-on-google-compute-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/07/fedora-30-on-google-compute-engine/</guid><description>Fedora 30 is my primary operating system for desktops and servers, so I usually try to take it everywhere I go. I was recently doing some benchmarking for kernel compiles on different cloud plaforms and I noticed that Fedora isn&amp;rsquo;t included in Google Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s default list of operating system images.
(Note: Fedora does include links to quick start an Amazon EC2 instance with their pre-built AMI&amp;rsquo;s. They are superb!)</description></item><item><title>Stop audio pops on Intel HD Audio</title><link>https://major.io/2019/03/04/stop-audio-pops-on-intel-hd-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/03/04/stop-audio-pops-on-intel-hd-audio/</guid><description>I recently picked up a Dell Optiplex 7060 and I&amp;rsquo;m using it as my main workstation now. The Fedora installation was easy, but I noticed a variety of &amp;ldquo;pop&amp;rdquo; or clicking sounds when audio played, especially terminal bells.
If everything was quiet and I triggered a terminal bell, I would hear a loud pop just before the terminal bell sound. However, if I played music and then triggered a terminal bell, the pop was gone.</description></item><item><title>Automatic floating windows in i3</title><link>https://major.io/2019/02/08/automatic-floating-windows-in-i3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/02/08/automatic-floating-windows-in-i3/</guid><description>The i3 window manager is a fast window manager that helps you keep all of your applications in the right place. It automatically tiles windows and can manage those tiles across multiple virtual desktops.
However, there are certain applications that I really prefer in a floating window. Floating windows do not get tiled and they can easily be dragged around with your mouse. They&amp;rsquo;re the type of windows you expect to see on other non-tiling desktops such as GNOME or KDE.</description></item><item><title>Using the pressure stall information interface in kernel 4.20</title><link>https://major.io/2019/01/27/using-the-pressure-stall-information-interface-in-kernel-4.20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/01/27/using-the-pressure-stall-information-interface-in-kernel-4.20/</guid><description>Fedora 29 now has kernel 4.20 available and it has lots of new features. One of the more interesting and easy to use features is the pressure stall information interface.
Load average We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with the load average measurement on Linux machines, even if the numbers do seem a bit cryptic:
$ w 10:55:46 up 11 min, 1 user, load average: 0.42, 0.39, 0.26 The numbers denote how many processes were active over the last one, five and 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Running Home Assistant in a Docker container with a Z-Wave USB stick</title><link>https://major.io/2019/01/14/running-home-assistant-in-a-docker-container-with-zwave-usb-stick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/01/14/running-home-assistant-in-a-docker-container-with-zwave-usb-stick/</guid><description>The Home Assistant project provides a great open source way to get started with home automtion that can be entirely self-contained within your home. It already has plenty of integrations with external services, but it can also monitor Z-Wave devices at your home or office.
Here are my devices:
Monoprice Z-Wave Garade Door Sensor Aeotec Z-Stick Gen5 (ZW090) Fedora Linux server with Docker installed Install the Z-Wave stick Start by plugging the Z-Stick into your Linux server.</description></item><item><title>Allow a port range with firewalld</title><link>https://major.io/2019/01/04/allow-port-range-with-firewalld/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/01/04/allow-port-range-with-firewalld/</guid><description>Managing iptables gets a lot easier with firewalld. You can manage rules for the IPv4 and IPv6 stacks using the same commands and it provides fine-grained controls for various &amp;ldquo;zones&amp;rdquo; of network sources and destinations.
Quick example Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of allowing an arbitrary port (for netdata) through the firewall with iptables and firewalld on Fedora:
## iptables iptables -A INPUT -j ACCEPT -p tcp --dport 19999 ip6tables -A INPUT -j ACCEPT -p tcp --dport 19999 service iptables save service ip6tables save ## firewalld firewall-cmd --add-port=19999/tcp --permanent In this example, firewall-cmd allows us to allow a TCP port through the firewall with a much simpler interface and the change is made permanent with the --permanent argument.</description></item><item><title>How to thrive at a technical conference</title><link>https://major.io/2018/05/09/how-to-thrive-at-a-tech-conference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 23:54:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/05/09/how-to-thrive-at-a-tech-conference/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m at the 2018 Red Hat Summit this week in San Francisco and I am enjoying the interactions between developers, executives, vendors, and engineers. It&amp;rsquo;s my seventh Summit (but my first as a Red Hat employee!), but I regularly meet people who are attending their first technical conference.
The question inevitably comes up: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. How do you survive these events?&amp;rdquo;
One attendee asked me to write a blog post on my tips and tricks.</description></item><item><title>Reaching the fork in the road</title><link>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:18:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</guid><description>Walt Disney said it best:
We keep moving forward, opening new doors, and doing new things, because we&amp;rsquo;re curious and curiosity keeps leading us down new paths.
The world of technology is all about change. We tear down the old things that get in our way and we build new technology that takes us to new heights. Tearing down these old things can often be difficult and that forces us to make difficult choices.</description></item><item><title>Install testing kernels in Fedora</title><link>https://major.io/2018/02/28/install-testing-kernels-in-fedora/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/02/28/install-testing-kernels-in-fedora/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re on the latest Fedora release, you&amp;rsquo;re already running lots of modern packages. However, there are those times when you may want to help with testing efforts or try out a new feature in a newer package.
Most of my systems have the updates-testing repository enabled in one way or another. This repository contains packages that package maintainers have submitted to become the next stable package in Fedora. For example, if there is a bug fix for nginx, the package maintainer submits the changes and publish a release.</description></item><item><title>Takeaways from my foray into amateur radio</title><link>https://major.io/2018/01/06/takeaways-from-my-foray-into-amateur-radio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/01/06/takeaways-from-my-foray-into-amateur-radio/</guid><description>The Overland Expo in Asheville last year was a great event, and one of my favorite sessions covered the basics about radio communications while overlanding. The instructors shared their radios with us and taught us some tips and tricks for how to save power and communicate effectively on the trail.
Back at the office, I was surprised to discover how many of my coworkers had an FCC license already. They gave me tips on getting started and how to learn the material for the exam.</description></item><item><title>Ensuring keepalived starts after the network is ready</title><link>https://major.io/2017/12/15/ensuring-keepalived-starts-network-ready/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/12/15/ensuring-keepalived-starts-network-ready/</guid><description>After a recent OpenStack-Ansible (OSA) deployment on CentOS, I found that keepalived was not starting properly at boot time:
Keepalived_vrrp[801]: Cant find interface br-mgmt for vrrp_instance internal !!! Keepalived_vrrp[801]: Truncating auth_pass to 8 characters Keepalived_vrrp[801]: VRRP is trying to assign ip address 172.29.236.11/32 to unknown br-mgmt interface !!! go out and fix your conf !!! Keepalived_vrrp[801]: Cant find interface br-mgmt for vrrp_instance external !!! Keepalived_vrrp[801]: Truncating auth_pass to 8 characters Keepalived_vrrp[801]: VRRP is trying to assign ip address 192.</description></item><item><title>Changes in RHEL 7 Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 1, Release 3</title><link>https://major.io/2017/11/02/changes-in-rhel-7-security-technical-implementation-guide-version-1-release-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/11/02/changes-in-rhel-7-security-technical-implementation-guide-version-1-release-3/</guid><description>The latest release of the Red Hat Enterprise Linux Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG) was published last week. This release is Version 1, Release 3, and it contains four main changes:
V-77819 - Multifactor authentication is required for graphical logins V-77821 - Datagram Congestion Control Protocol (DCCP) kernel module must be disabled V-77823 - Single user mode must require user authentication V-77825 - Address space layout randomization (ASLR) must be enabled Deep dive Let&amp;rsquo;s break down this list to understand what each one means.</description></item><item><title>Import RPM repository GPG keys from other keyservers temporarily</title><link>https://major.io/2017/09/20/import-rpm-repository-keys-from-other-keyservers-temporarily/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 15:24:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/09/20/import-rpm-repository-keys-from-other-keyservers-temporarily/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through some patches to OpenStack-Ansible lately to optimize how we configure yum repositories in our deployments. During that work, I ran into some issues where pgp.mit.edu was returning 500 errors for some requests to retrieve GPG keys.
Ansible was returning this error:
curl: (22) The requested URL returned error: 502 Proxy Error error: http://pgp.mit.edu:11371/pks/lookup?op=get&amp;amp;search=0x61E8806C: import read failed(2) How does the rpm command know which keyserver to use? Let&amp;rsquo;s use the --showrc argument to show how it is configured:</description></item><item><title>Thunderbird changes fonts in some messages, not all</title><link>https://major.io/2017/08/02/thunderbird-changes-fonts-messages-not/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 12:54:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/08/02/thunderbird-changes-fonts-messages-not/</guid><description>Thunderbird is a great choice for a mail client on Linux systems if you prefer a GUI, but I had some problems with fonts in the most recent releases. The monospace font used for plain text messages was difficult to read.
I opened Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Display and clicked Advanced to the right of Fonts &amp;amp; Colors. The default font for monospace text was &amp;ldquo;Monospace&amp;rdquo;, and that one isn&amp;rsquo;t terribly attractive.</description></item></channel></rss>