<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>email on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/email/</link><description>Recent content in email on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 18:08:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Customize LDAP autocompletion format in Thunderbird</title><link>https://major.io/2017/07/18/customize-ldap-autocompletion-format-in-thunderbird/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 18:08:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/07/18/customize-ldap-autocompletion-format-in-thunderbird/</guid><description>Thunderbird can connect to an LDAP server and autocomplete email addresses as you type, but it needs some adjustment for some LDAP servers. One of the LDAP servers that I use regularly returns email addresses like this in the thunderbird interface:
username &amp;lt;firstname.lastname@domain.tld&amp;gt; The email address looks fine, but I&amp;rsquo;d much rather have the person&amp;rsquo;s full name instead of the username. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for:
Firstname Lastname &amp;lt;firstname.lastname@domain.tld&amp;gt; In older Thunderbird versions, setting ldap_2.</description></item><item><title>Custom keyboard shortcuts for Evolution in GNOME</title><link>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 05:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/11/27/custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-evolution-in-gnome/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Thunderbird for years, but it lacks features in some critical areas. For example, I need Microsoft Exchange and Google Apps connectivity for my mail and contacts, but Thunderbird needs some extensions to make that connectivity easier. There are some great extensions available, but they lack polish since they&amp;rsquo;re not part of the core product.
My muscle memory for keyboard shortcuts in Thunderbird left me fumbling in Evolution.</description></item><item><title>Show originating IP address in Apple Mail</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/18/show-originating-ip-address-in-apple-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 14:20:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/18/show-originating-ip-address-in-apple-mail/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received some very sophisticated phishing emails lately and I was showing some of them to my coworkers. One of my coworkers noticed that my Apple Mail client displays the X-Originating-IP header for all of the emails I receive.
You can enter that IP into a whois search and get a better idea of who sent you the message without diving into the headers. If someone that regularly exchanges email with me suddenly has an originating IP in another country that would be unusual for them to travel to, I can approach the message with more caution.</description></item><item><title>One month using a Linux laptop at work: Back to the Mac</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/22/one-month-using-a-linux-laptop-at-work-back-to-the-mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 02:38:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/22/one-month-using-a-linux-laptop-at-work-back-to-the-mac/</guid><description>This post has been a bit delayed, but I want to follow up on the post I wrote last month about moving from OS X to Linux at work. I started out with a Lenovo Thinkpad X1 Carbon along with Fedora 19 and KDE. Although most things went really well, there were a few deal-breakers that sent me back to the Mac.
Just to give you an idea of my daily workflow, much of my day revolved around my calendar and email.</description></item><item><title>Receive e-mail reports for SELinux AVC denials</title><link>https://major.io/2011/09/15/receive-e-mail-reports-for-selinux-avc-denials/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 04:17:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/09/15/receive-e-mail-reports-for-selinux-avc-denials/</guid><description>SELinux isn&amp;rsquo;t a technology that&amp;rsquo;s easy to tackle for newcomers. However, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of work to smooth out the rough edges while still keeping a tight grip on what applications and users are allowed to do on a Linux system. One of the biggest efforts has been around setroubleshoot.
The purpose behind setroubleshoot is to let users know when access has been denied, help them resolve it if necessary, and to reduce overall frustration while working through tight security restrictions in the default SELinux policies.</description></item><item><title>Sending binary e-mail attachments from the command line with mutt</title><link>https://major.io/2011/01/10/sending-binary-e-mail-attachments-from-the-command-line-with-mutt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 01:10:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/01/10/sending-binary-e-mail-attachments-from-the-command-line-with-mutt/</guid><description>E-mailing a binary e-mail attachment from a Linux server has always been difficult for me because I never found a reliable method to get it done. I&amp;rsquo;ve used uuencode to pipe data into mail on various systems but the attachment is often unreadable by many e-mail clients.
Someone finally showed me a simple, fool-proof method to send binary attachments reliably from various Linux systems:
echo &amp;quot;Cheeseburger&amp;quot; | mutt -s &amp;quot;OHAI!&amp;quot; -a lolcat.</description></item><item><title>Deleting all e-mail messages in your inbox with mutt</title><link>https://major.io/2009/06/19/deleting-all-e-mail-messages-in-your-inbox-with-mutt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 17:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/06/19/deleting-all-e-mail-messages-in-your-inbox-with-mutt/</guid><description>Occasionally, I&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a mailbox full of random data, alerts, or other useless things. If you have SSH access to the server, you can always clear out your mail spool, but if you connect to an IMAP server, you can use mutt to do the same thing.
First, use mutt to connect to your server remotely (via IMAP over SSL in this example):
mutt -f imaps://mail.yourdomain.com/ Once you&amp;rsquo;ve connected and logged in, press SHIFT-D (uppercase d).</description></item></channel></rss>