<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>perl on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/perl/</link><description>Recent content in perl on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 13:20:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/perl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing broken DNS lookups in spamassassin</title><link>https://major.io/2014/06/20/fixing-broken-dns-lookups-in-spamassassin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 13:20:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/06/20/fixing-broken-dns-lookups-in-spamassassin/</guid><description>I talked about the joys of running my own mail server last week only to find that my mail server was broken yesterday. Spamassassin stopped doing DNS lookups for RBL and SPF checks.
I had one of these moments:
My logs looked like this:
plugin: eval failed: available_nameservers: No DNS servers available! plugin: eval failed: available_nameservers: No DNS servers available! rules: failed to run NO_DNS_FOR_FROM RBL test, skipping: (available_nameservers: [.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner v1.3.0</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/21/mysqltuner-v1-3-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/21/mysqltuner-v1-3-0/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been three long years since the last MySQLTuner release but you&amp;rsquo;ll now find version 1.3.0 available on GitHub. You can get it from the git repository or via these extremely simple methods:
wget -O mysqltuner.pl mysqltuner.pl wget --trust-server-names mysqltuner.pl There are a bunch of new features and fixes that you can find in the list of commits from today (2014-02-21). Some of the bigger adjustments include:
Basic support for MariaDB 10.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner mentioned at the O’Reilly MySQL Conference</title><link>https://major.io/2011/04/15/mysqltuner-mentioned-at-the-oreilly-mysql-conference/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 01:56:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/04/15/mysqltuner-mentioned-at-the-oreilly-mysql-conference/</guid><description>If you push play, the video should scoot out to about the 14m40s mark where MySQLTuner appears on one of the slides. Thanks to Trent Hornibrook for letting me know!</description></item><item><title>CPAN: Automatically install dependencies without confirmation</title><link>https://major.io/2009/01/01/cpan-automatically-install-dependencies-without-confirmation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 01:44:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/01/01/cpan-automatically-install-dependencies-without-confirmation/</guid><description>I enjoy using CPAN because it installs Perl modules with a simple interface, fetches dependencies, and warns you when things are about to end badly. However, one of my biggest complaints is when it constantly confirms installing dependencies. While this is an annoyance if you have to install a module with many dependencies (or if you&amp;rsquo;re working with CPAN on a new server), you can tell CPAN to automatically confirm the installation of dependencies.</description></item><item><title>MySQLTuner 0.9.9 is now available</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/07/mysqltuner-099-is-now-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 02:05:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/07/mysqltuner-099-is-now-available/</guid><description>MySQLTuner 0.9.9 is now available for download. There&amp;rsquo;s a new wiki for the script at wiki.mysqltuner.com. The new wiki contains links to downloads, changelogs, and other details.
If you want to know when the latest releases are available, there are multiple options:
Follow RackerHacker on Twitter Sign up for the MySQLTuner mailing list Use the --checkversion option when you run the script</description></item><item><title>CentOS/RHEL x86_64 + VMWare: Use of uninitialized value in string</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/03/centosrhel-x86_64-vmware-use-of-uninitialized-value-in-string/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 17:06:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/03/centosrhel-x86_64-vmware-use-of-uninitialized-value-in-string/</guid><description>I was working with a CentOS 5 x86_64 installation running VMWare server last week when I stumbled upon this error:
Use of uninitialized value in string eq at /usr/lib64/perl5/site_perl/5.8.8/x86_64-linux-thread-multi/VMware/VmPerl.pm line 114. You can run the vmware-cmd application with this error (it&amp;rsquo;s not a fatal error) and keep going with your normal business. However, if you want to remove the error, comment out lines 114 and 115 in the Perl module referenced by the error:</description></item><item><title>Adjusting CPAN mirror list</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/16/adjusting-cpan-mirror-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 17:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/16/adjusting-cpan-mirror-list/</guid><description>One of the most frustrating aspects of CPAN is connecting to mirrors via FTP. Most of the time, the mirrors are extraordinarily slow when it comes to FTP logins, and they often fail. As we all know, RHEL enjoys pulling some shenanigans (Scalar::Util - enough said) when perl receives an upgrade, and when I need CPAN to work quickly, it often does the opposite.
I was struggling to find a way to reconfigure CPAN to use HTTP mirrors rather than FTP, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out where CPAN was holding this data.</description></item><item><title>Backing up MySQL to Amazon’s S3</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/05/backing-up-mysql-to-amazons-s3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:18:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/05/backing-up-mysql-to-amazons-s3/</guid><description>I received an e-mail from Tim Linden about a post he made in his blog about backing up MySQL data to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3.
The article goes over installing the Net::Amazon::S3 Perl module via WHM (which is handy for the cPanel users). However, if you&amp;rsquo;re not a cPanel user, you can install it via CPAN:
# perl -MCPAN -e 'install Net::Amazon::S3' If you&amp;rsquo;d rather install it through Webmin, go to the &amp;lsquo;Others&amp;rsquo; section, and click &amp;lsquo;Perl Modules&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Red Hat Perl Issues: unable to call function somefunction on undefined value</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/19/red-hat-perl-issues-unable-to-call-function-somefunction-on-undefined-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 18:19:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/19/red-hat-perl-issues-unable-to-call-function-somefunction-on-undefined-value/</guid><description>Apparently, a recent Red Hat Enterprise Linux update for ES3, 4 and 5 caused some Perl applications to throw errors like these:
unable to call function somefunction on undefined value Of course, replace somefunction with your function of choice. To correct the issue, you can force CPAN to bring back a more sane version of Scalar::Util:
# perl -MCPAN -e shell cpan&amp;gt; force install Scalar::Util</description></item></channel></rss>