<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build AWS images with Image Builder</title><link>https://major.io/2020/06/19/build-aws-images-with-imagebuilder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/06/19/build-aws-images-with-imagebuilder/</guid><description>The AMIs provided by most Linux distributions in AWS work well for most use cases. However, there are those times when you need a customized image to support a certain configuration or to speed up CI processes.
You can get a customized image via a few methods:
Build from an existing AMI, customize it, and snapshot it. Use an automated tool, such as Packer, to automate #1. Build your own image locally in KVM, VMware, or Virtualbox and upload the image into S3, import it into an EC2, and create an AMI from the snapshot.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 30 on Google Compute Engine</title><link>https://major.io/2019/08/07/fedora-30-on-google-compute-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2019/08/07/fedora-30-on-google-compute-engine/</guid><description>Fedora 30 is my primary operating system for desktops and servers, so I usually try to take it everywhere I go. I was recently doing some benchmarking for kernel compiles on different cloud plaforms and I noticed that Fedora isn&amp;rsquo;t included in Google Compute Engine&amp;rsquo;s default list of operating system images.
(Note: Fedora does include links to quick start an Amazon EC2 instance with their pre-built AMI&amp;rsquo;s. They are superb!)</description></item><item><title>Reaching the fork in the road</title><link>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:18:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2018/03/07/reaching-the-fork-in-the-road/</guid><description>Walt Disney said it best:
We keep moving forward, opening new doors, and doing new things, because we&amp;rsquo;re curious and curiosity keeps leading us down new paths.
The world of technology is all about change. We tear down the old things that get in our way and we build new technology that takes us to new heights. Tearing down these old things can often be difficult and that forces us to make difficult choices.</description></item><item><title>OpenStack isn’t dead. It’s boring. That’s a good thing.</title><link>https://major.io/2017/02/24/openstack-isnt-dead-its-boring-thats-a-good-thing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 16:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/02/24/openstack-isnt-dead-its-boring-thats-a-good-thing/</guid><description>NOTE: The opinions shared in this post are mine alone and are not related to my employer in any way.
The first OpenStack Project Teams Gathering (PTG) event was held this week in Atlanta. The week was broken into two parts: cross-project work on Monday and Tuesday, and individual projects Wednesday through Friday. I was there for the first two days and heard a few discussions that started the same way.</description></item><item><title>A humble farewell to Seth Vidal</title><link>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/07/09/a-humble-farewell-to-seth-vidal/</guid><description>I was shocked to see Robyn Bergeron&amp;rsquo;s email today about Seth Vidal&amp;rsquo;s passing. He was the victim of a hit and run accident while he was cycling last night. The suspect has turned himself in as of tonight.
I first met Seth at FUDCon Tempe back in 2011. We had talked off and on via email and IRC about cloud-related topics. He was interested in how we assembled our cloud offering at Rackspace and I was eager to talk to him about building cloud images and handling mirrors.</description></item><item><title>Red Hat Summit 2012: Wednesday</title><link>https://major.io/2012/06/28/red-hat-summit-2012-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 06:03:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/06/28/red-hat-summit-2012-wednesday/</guid><description>Wednesday was action-packed with dramatic keynotes and great sessions. The morning was kicked off by Paul Cormier and he talked about some new products coming from Red Hat. Much of the product releases were centered around cloud offerings (like Openshift) and his talk was mainly aimed at CIO&amp;rsquo;s and decision makers. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of technical detail within his talk but it was refreshing to hear a Linux vendor talk about their products as being revolutionary steps in pulling away from vendor lock-in and proprietary solutions.</description></item><item><title>First day of the Red Hat Summit</title><link>https://major.io/2012/06/26/first-day-of-the-red-hat-summit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 02:49:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/06/26/first-day-of-the-red-hat-summit/</guid><description>The Red Hat Summit 2012 kicked off with an evening keynote by Jim Whitehurst explaining the changes in business value over time from the raw materials to the industry that profited from standardization.
He made some excellent points and summaries about what cloud is and isn&amp;rsquo;t. The root of his keynote was around what cloud can do for companies and not so much about what cloud really is. His key point was that the value didn&amp;rsquo;t reside in the nuts and bolts that hold a cloud together.</description></item><item><title>Tracing a build through OpenStack Compute (Nova)</title><link>https://major.io/2011/11/07/tracing-a-build-through-openstack-compute-nova/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 15:05:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/11/07/tracing-a-build-through-openstack-compute-nova/</guid><description>My work at Rackspace has changed a bit in the last few weeks and I&amp;rsquo;ve shifted from managing a team of engineers to a full technical focus on OpenStack Nova. Although it was difficult to leave my management position, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to get back to my roots and dig into the technical stuff again.
One of the first things I wanted to tackle was understanding how a build request flows through Nova to a XenServer hypervisor.</description></item><item><title>Xen Summit 2011: My Takeways</title><link>https://major.io/2011/08/08/xen-summit-2011-my-takeways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/08/08/xen-summit-2011-my-takeways/</guid><description>Quite a few people who couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to Xen Summit 2011 this year asked me to write a post summarizing my takeaways from the event. I&amp;rsquo;m not generally one to back down from peer pressure, so read on if you&amp;rsquo;re interested about the discussions at this year&amp;rsquo;s Summit.
The feeling I had at last year&amp;rsquo;s summit is that Xen was on the verge of losing traction in the market. Very few distributions still had Xen support going forward and much of the discussion was around the lack of dom0 support in upstream Linux kernels.</description></item><item><title>Xen 4.1 on Fedora 15 with Linux 3.0</title><link>https://major.io/2011/08/05/xen-4-1-on-fedora-15-with-linux-3-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 04:34:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/08/05/xen-4-1-on-fedora-15-with-linux-3-0/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed already, full Xen dom0 support was added in the Linux 3.0 kernel. This means there&amp;rsquo;s no longer a need to drag patches forward from old kernels and work from special branches and git repositories when building a kernel for dom0.
Something else you might not have noticed is that the Fedora kernel team has quietly slipped Linux 3.0 into Fedora 15&amp;rsquo;s update channels in disguise. Click that link, scroll down, and you&amp;rsquo;ll see “Rebase to 3.</description></item><item><title>Accessing Rackspace Cloud Servers and Slicehost slices privately via OpenVPN</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/16/accessing-rackspace-cloud-servers-and-slicehost-slices-privately-via-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/16/accessing-rackspace-cloud-servers-and-slicehost-slices-privately-via-openvpn/</guid><description>Diagram: OpenVPN to Rackspace Cloud Servers and Slicehost
A recent blog post from Mixpanel inspired me to write a quick how-to for Fedora users on using OpenVPN to talk to instances privately in the Rackspace Cloud.
The diagram at the right gives an idea of what this guide will allow you to accomplish. Consider a situation where you want to talk to the MySQL installation on db1 directly without requiring extra ssh tunnels or MySQL over SSL via the public network.</description></item><item><title>A nerd’s perspective on cloud hosting</title><link>https://major.io/2010/08/25/a-nerds-perspective-on-cloud-hosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 13:03:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/08/25/a-nerds-perspective-on-cloud-hosting/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s go ahead and get this out of the way: The following post contains only my personal opinions. These are not the opinions of my employer and should not be considered as such. The term &amp;ldquo;cloud hosting&amp;rdquo; has become more popular over the past few years and it seems like everyone is talking about it. I&amp;rsquo;m often asked by customers and coworkers about what cloud hosting really is. Where does traditional dedicated hosting end and cloud begin?</description></item><item><title>Rackspace Cloud Tech Podcast Episode 2</title><link>https://major.io/2010/03/08/rackspace-cloud-tech-podcast-episode-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 01:51:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/03/08/rackspace-cloud-tech-podcast-episode-2/</guid><description>I participated in a podcast for the Rackspace Cloud with Robert Collazo last week. We covered some important topics including network security and convenient deployment tools.</description></item><item><title>Private network interfaces: the forgotten security hole</title><link>https://major.io/2010/03/01/private-network-interfaces-the-forgotten-security-hole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:55:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/03/01/private-network-interfaces-the-forgotten-security-hole/</guid><description>Regardless of the type of hosting you&amp;rsquo;re using - dedicated or cloud - it&amp;rsquo;s important to take network interface security seriously. Most often, threats from the internet are the only ones mentioned. However, if you share a private network with other customers, you have just as much risk on that interface.
Many cloud providers allow you access to a private network environment where you can exchange data with other instances or other services offered by the provider.</description></item></channel></rss>