<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:25:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenStack Summit Boston 2017 Recap</title><link>https://major.io/2017/05/11/openstack-summit-boston-2017-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:25:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/05/11/openstack-summit-boston-2017-recap/</guid><description>The OpenStack Summit wrapped up today in Boston and it was a great week! There were plenty of informative breakouts and some interesting keynotes.
Keynotes Beth Cohen shared some of the work that Verizon has done with software-defined WAN on customer-premises equipment (CPE). She showed a demo of how customers could easily provision virtual network hardware, such as firewalls or intrusion detection systems, without waiting for hardware or cabling changes. I&amp;rsquo;m less familiar with the world of telcos, so I found this really interesting.</description></item><item><title>OpenStack isn’t dead. It’s boring. That’s a good thing.</title><link>https://major.io/2017/02/24/openstack-isnt-dead-its-boring-thats-a-good-thing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 16:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/02/24/openstack-isnt-dead-its-boring-thats-a-good-thing/</guid><description>NOTE: The opinions shared in this post are mine alone and are not related to my employer in any way.
The first OpenStack Project Teams Gathering (PTG) event was held this week in Atlanta. The week was broken into two parts: cross-project work on Monday and Tuesday, and individual projects Wednesday through Friday. I was there for the first two days and heard a few discussions that started the same way.</description></item><item><title>Why should students learn to write code?</title><link>https://major.io/2016/10/10/why-should-students-learn-to-write-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 04:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/10/10/why-should-students-learn-to-write-code/</guid><description>There are lots of efforts underway to get students (young and old) to learn to write code. There are far-reaching efforts, like the Hour of Code, and plenty of smaller, more focused projects, such as the Design and Technology Academy (part of Northeast ISD here in San Antonio, Texas). These are excellent programs that enrich the education of many students.
I often hear a question from various people about these programs:</description></item><item><title>What’s Happening in OpenStack-Ansible (WHOA) – September 2016</title><link>https://major.io/2016/09/30/whats-happening-in-openstack-ansible-whoa-september-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 14:33:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/09/30/whats-happening-in-openstack-ansible-whoa-september-2016/</guid><description>Welcome to the fourth post in the series of What&amp;rsquo;s Happening in OpenStack-Ansible (WHOA) posts that I&amp;rsquo;m assembling each month. OpenStack-Ansible is a flexible framework for deploying enterprise-grade OpenStack clouds. In fact, I use OpenStack-Ansible to deploy the OpenStack cloud underneath the virtual machine that runs this blog!
My goal with these posts is to inform more people about what we&amp;rsquo;re doing in the OpenStack-Ansible community and bring on more contributors to the project.</description></item><item><title>What’s Happening in OpenStack-Ansible (WHOA) – August 2016</title><link>https://major.io/2016/08/23/whats-happening-in-openstack-ansible-whoa-august-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 20:35:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/08/23/whats-happening-in-openstack-ansible-whoa-august-2016/</guid><description>Welcome to the third post in the series of What&amp;rsquo;s Happening in OpenStack-Ansible (WHOA) posts that I&amp;rsquo;m assembling each month. OpenStack-Ansible is a flexible framework for deploying enterprise-grade OpenStack clouds. In fact, I use OpenStack-Ansible to deploy the OpenStack cloud underneath the virtual machine that runs this blog!
My goal with these posts is to inform more people about what we&amp;rsquo;re doing in the OpenStack-Ansible community and bring on more contributors to the project.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with gertty</title><link>https://major.io/2016/05/11/getting-started-gertty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 13:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/05/11/getting-started-gertty/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re ready to commit code in an OpenStack project, your patch will eventually land in a Gerrit queue for review. The web interface works well for most users, but it can be challenging to use when you have a large amount of projects to monitor. I recently became a core developer on the OpenStack-Ansible project and I searched for a better solution to handle lots of active reviews.
This is where gertty can help.</description></item><item><title>Automated Let’s Encrypt DNS challenges with Rackspace Cloud DNS</title><link>https://major.io/2016/03/31/automated-lets-encrypt-dns-challenges-with-rackspace-cloud-dns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 19:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/03/31/automated-lets-encrypt-dns-challenges-with-rackspace-cloud-dns/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt has taken the world by storm by providing free SSL certificates that can be renewed via automated methods. They have issued over 1.4 million certificates since launch in the fall of 2015.
If you are not familiar with how Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt operates, here is an extremely simple explanation:
Create a private key Make a request for a new certificate Complete the challenge process You have a certificate! That is highly simplified, but there is plenty of detail available on how the whole system works.</description></item><item><title>Fight cynicism with curiosity</title><link>https://major.io/2016/02/17/fight-cynicism-curiosity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 15:30:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/02/17/fight-cynicism-curiosity/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always interested to talk to college students about technology and business in general. They have amazing ideas and they don&amp;rsquo;t place any limits on themselves. In particular, their curiosity is limitless.
A great question I joined several other local employers at the University of Texas at San Antonio last week for mock interviews with computer science students. We went through plenty of sample questions and gave feedback to the students on their content and delivery during the mock interviews.</description></item><item><title>Segmentation faults with sphinx and pyenv</title><link>https://major.io/2016/02/09/segmentation-faults-with-sphinx-and-pyenv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 14:09:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/02/09/segmentation-faults-with-sphinx-and-pyenv/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the pyenv project because it makes installing multiple python versions a simple process. However, I kept stumbling into a segmentation fault whenever I tried to build documentation with sphinx in Python 2.7.11:
writing output... [100%] unreleased [app] emitting event: 'doctree-resolved'(&amp;lt;document: &amp;lt;section &amp;quot;current series release notes&amp;quot;...&amp;gt;&amp;gt;, u'unreleased') [app] emitting event: 'html-page-context'(u'unreleased', 'page.html', {'file_suffix': '.html', 'has_source': True, 'show_sphinx': True, 'last generating indices... genindex[app] emitting event: 'html-page-context'('genindex', 'genindex.html', {'pathto': &amp;lt;function pathto at 0x7f4279d51230&amp;gt;, 'file_suffix': '.</description></item><item><title>Nobody is using your software project. Now what?</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/15/nobody-using-software-project-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 17:35:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/15/nobody-using-software-project-now/</guid><description>Working with open source software is an amazing experience. The collaborative process around creation, refinement, and even maintenance, drives more developers to work on open source software more often. However, every developer finds themselves writing code that very few people actually use.
For some developers, this can be really bothersome. You offer your code up to the world only to find that the world is much less interested than you expected.</description></item><item><title>Automated testing for Ansible CIS playbook on RHEL/CentOS 6</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/05/automated-testing-for-ansible-cis-playbook-on-rhelcentos-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 13:13:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/05/automated-testing-for-ansible-cis-playbook-on-rhelcentos-6/</guid><description>I started working on the Ansible CIS playbook for CentOS and RHEL 6 back in 2014 and I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes to increase quality and make it easier to use.
First off, the role itself is no longer a submodule. You can now just clone the repository and get rolling. This should reduce the time it takes to get started.
Also, all pull requests to the repository now go through integration testing at Rackspace.</description></item><item><title>Making things more super with supernova 2.0</title><link>https://major.io/2015/07/18/making-things-more-super-with-supernova-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 17:42:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/07/18/making-things-more-super-with-supernova-2-0/</guid><description>I started supernova a little over three years ago with the idea of making it easier to use novaclient. Three years and a few downloads later, it manages multiple different OpenStack clients, like nova, glance, and trove along with some handy features for users who manage a large number of environments.
What&amp;rsquo;s new? With some help from some friends who are much better at writing Python than I am (thanks Paul, Matt and Jason), I restructured supernova to make it more testable.</description></item><item><title>Improving LXC template security</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/18/improving-lxc-template-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 19:52:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/18/improving-lxc-template-security/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting involved with the Fedora Security Team lately and we&amp;rsquo;re working as a group to crush security bugs that affect Fedora, CentOS (via EPEL) and Red Hat Enterprise Linux (via EPEL). During some of this work, I stumbled upon a group of Red Hat Bugzilla tickets talking about LXC template security.
The gist of the problem is that there&amp;rsquo;s a wide variance in how users and user credentials are handled by the different LXC templates.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from a kernel bisection</title><link>https://major.io/2015/02/09/lessons-learned-kernel-bisection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 14:39:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/02/09/lessons-learned-kernel-bisection/</guid><description>[][1]I&amp;rsquo;m far from being a kernel developer, but I found myself staring down a [peculiar touchpad problem][2] with my new Dell XPS 13. Before kernel 3.17, the touchpad showed up as a standard PS/2 mouse, which certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal. That robbed the pad of its multi-touch capabilities. Kernel 3.17 added the right support for the pad but freezes began to occur somewhere between 3.17 and 3.19.
Bisecting It became apparent that bisecting the kernel would be required.</description></item><item><title>A response to Infoworld’s confusing article about Fedora</title><link>https://major.io/2014/11/19/response-infoworlds-confusing-article-fedora/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 14:24:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/11/19/response-infoworlds-confusing-article-fedora/</guid><description>Working with the Fedora community is something I really enjoy in my spare time and I was baffled by a article I saw in Infoworld earlier last week. Here&amp;rsquo;s a link:
Red Hat confuses Linux users with latest Fedora moves
The article dives into the productization of Fedora 21 that hopes to deliver a better experience for workstation, server, and cloud users. The article suggests that Red Hat drove Fedora development and that the goals of Red Hat and Fedora are closely aligned.</description></item><item><title>Audit RHEL/CentOS 6 security benchmarks with ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2014/08/19/audit-rhelcentos-6-security-benchmarks-ansible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/08/19/audit-rhelcentos-6-security-benchmarks-ansible/</guid><description>Securing critical systems isn&amp;rsquo;t easy and that&amp;rsquo;s why security benchmarks exist. Many groups and communities distribute recommendations for securing servers, including NIST, the US Department of Defense (DoD), and the Center for Internet Security (CIS).
Although NIST and DoD are catching up quickly with newer OS releases, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the CIS benchmarks are updated very regularly. CIS distributes auditing tools (with paid memberships) that require Java and they&amp;rsquo;re cumbersome to use, especially on servers where Java isn&amp;rsquo;t normally installed.</description></item><item><title>Adventures in live booting Linux distributions</title><link>https://major.io/2014/07/29/adventures-in-live-booting-linux-distributions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 13:05:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/07/29/adventures-in-live-booting-linux-distributions/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with live booting Linux distributions. Almost every Linux distribution under the sun has a method for making live CD&amp;rsquo;s, writing live USB sticks, or booting live images over the network. The primary use case for some distributions is on a live medium (like KNOPPIX).
However, I embarked on an adventure to look at live booting Linux for a different use case. Sure, many live environments are used for demonstrations or installations - temporary activities for a desktop or a laptop.</description></item><item><title>Enjoy supernova 1.0.0</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/27/enjoy-supernova-1-0-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 13:19:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/27/enjoy-supernova-1-0-0/</guid><description>The first supernova commit to GitHub appeared just over two years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s been stable for quite some time, but it&amp;rsquo;s made it to version 1.0.0 today!
As always, you can get supernova from PyPi using pip:
pip install -U supernova All of the documentation has moved to ReadTheDocs and it looks much better than the giant README file in GitHub that served as the documentation for so long. Thanks to everyone that has committed code, found bugs, or called out my inability to write Python!</description></item><item><title>DevOps and enterprise inertia</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/17/devops-and-enterprise-inertia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 17:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/17/devops-and-enterprise-inertia/</guid><description>As I wait in the airport to fly back home from this year&amp;rsquo;s Red Hat Summit, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking back over the many conversations I had over breakfast, over lunch, and during the events. One common theme that kept cropping up was around bringing DevOps to the enterprise. I stumbled upon Mathias Meyer&amp;rsquo;s post, The Developer is Dead, Long Live the Developer, and I was inspired to write my own.
Before I go any further, here&amp;rsquo;s my definition of DevOps: it&amp;rsquo;s a mindset shift where everyone is responsible for the success of the customer experience.</description></item><item><title>Xen hackathon coming up in London</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/27/xen-hackathon-coming-up-in-london/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 13:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/27/xen-hackathon-coming-up-in-london/</guid><description>If you enjoy using Xen, join members of the Xen Project community and Rackspace at the Xen Hackathon in London. The two day event starts on May 29th.
Use these links to get more information:
Hackathon announcement and travel/venue/registration information Discussion topics You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a developer to join the event. It&amp;rsquo;s a great networking opportunity and you can take time to learn more about virtualization and how Xen works under the hood.</description></item><item><title>icanhaz more domains: icanhazepoch.com</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/21/icanhaz-more-domains-icanhazepoch-com/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 02:41:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/21/icanhaz-more-domains-icanhazepoch-com/</guid><description>Sometimes I can&amp;rsquo;t help myself. I like to buy domains and use them for interesting activities. This tweet cropped up in my stream tonight:
You can give it a try now: icanhazepoch.com
$ curl icanhazepoch.com 1393036551 I&amp;rsquo;m doing my best to keep the server time in sync, so it should be relatively reliable. However, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend using it for launching satellites or timing anything where someone&amp;rsquo;s life is held in the balance.</description></item><item><title>Hierarchy of DevOps Needs from DevOps Weekly</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/02/hierarchy-of-devops-needs-from-devops-weekly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 02:30:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/02/hierarchy-of-devops-needs-from-devops-weekly/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made posts about the DevOps Weekly mailing list before. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t signed up yet, do so now. You&amp;rsquo;ll thank me later.
Aaron Suggs' Hierarchy of DevOps Needs gives a great summary of the building blocks of a solid development culture and how they relate to one another. I laughed a bit when I saw his pyramid because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many development groups build the pyramid upside down in the past.</description></item><item><title>This is why we can’t have nice things: malware callbacks to icanhazip.com</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/17/this-is-why-we-cant-have-nice-things-malware-callbacks-to-icanhazip-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 19:54:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/17/this-is-why-we-cant-have-nice-things-malware-callbacks-to-icanhazip-com/</guid><description>I figured it would only be a matter of time until people used icanhazip.com for evil deeds. Someone linked me to these Sophos analysis pages:
Detailed Analysis - Troj/Agent-ADRF
Detailed Analysis - Troj/Mdrop-FIM
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with a couple of these vendors to get my site removed from their products' blacklists but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long that will stay in place. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to hunt down user agents so that I can deny requests from certain malicious scripts and other malware but I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough intel on the malware to get started.</description></item><item><title>drbd 8.4.3 package on the way for Fedora 19</title><link>https://major.io/2013/08/02/drbd-8-4-3-package-on-the-way-for-fedora-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/08/02/drbd-8-4-3-package-on-the-way-for-fedora-19/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a drbd-8.4.3-1 package waiting in the testing repository for Fedora 19. The DRBD kernel module for kernel 3.10 is up to 8.4.3 but the client tools within Fedora 19 (currently at 8.4.2) should work fine. The API versions are the same for both the kernel modules and user tools.
If you&amp;rsquo;re eager to see a changelog between 8.4.2 and 8.4.3, check DRBD&amp;rsquo;s git repository. The majority of the changes are within the kernel module itself.</description></item><item><title>Automate CentOS 6 deployments with CIS Security Benchmarks already applied</title><link>https://major.io/2013/04/26/automate-centos-6-deployments-with-cis-security-benchmarks-already-applied/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 14:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/04/26/automate-centos-6-deployments-with-cis-security-benchmarks-already-applied/</guid><description>A coworker heard me grumbling about Linux system administration standards and recommended that I review the CIS Security Benchmarks. After downloading the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 security benchmark PDF, I quickly started to see the value of the document. Some of the standards were the installation defaults, some were often forgotten settings, and some were completely brand new to me.
Automating the standards can be a little treacherous simply due to the number of things to adjust and check.</description></item></channel></rss>