<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slicehost on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/slicehost/</link><description>Recent content in slicehost on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 15:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/slicehost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reaching a new milestone and making some big changes</title><link>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/11/26/reaching-a-new-milestone-and-making-some-big-changes/</guid><description>This is my 500th post on this blog! I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful for the constant comments, questions, and even the complaints (really!) that I receive about the topics discussed here throughout the years. The sole reason I keep this blog going is for the readers and I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to get value out of it over time. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t, be sure to let me know so I can make some changes.</description></item><item><title>Accessing Rackspace Cloud Servers and Slicehost slices privately via OpenVPN</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/16/accessing-rackspace-cloud-servers-and-slicehost-slices-privately-via-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/16/accessing-rackspace-cloud-servers-and-slicehost-slices-privately-via-openvpn/</guid><description>Diagram: OpenVPN to Rackspace Cloud Servers and Slicehost
A recent blog post from Mixpanel inspired me to write a quick how-to for Fedora users on using OpenVPN to talk to instances privately in the Rackspace Cloud.
The diagram at the right gives an idea of what this guide will allow you to accomplish. Consider a situation where you want to talk to the MySQL installation on db1 directly without requiring extra ssh tunnels or MySQL over SSL via the public network.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Fedora 13 to Fedora 14 on Slicehost and Rackspace Cloud Servers</title><link>https://major.io/2010/11/03/upgrading-fedora-13-to-fedora-14-on-slicehost-and-rackspace-cloud-servers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 20:02:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/11/03/upgrading-fedora-13-to-fedora-14-on-slicehost-and-rackspace-cloud-servers/</guid><description>On most systems, using Fedora&amp;rsquo;s preupgrade package is the most reliable way to update to the next Fedora release. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the case with Slicehost and Rackspace Cloud Servers.
Here are the steps for an upgrade from Fedora 13 to Fedora 14 via yum:
yum -y upgrade wget http://mirror.rackspace.com/fedora/releases/14/Fedora/x86_64/os/Packages/fedora-release-14-1.noarch.rpm rpm -Uvh fedora-release-14-1.noarch.rpm yum -y install yum yum -y upgrade If you happen to be upgrading a 32-bit instance on Slicehost, simply replace x86_64 with i386 in the url shown above.</description></item></channel></rss>