<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>options on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/options/</link><description>Recent content in options on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Free resources for the stock market</title><link>https://major.io/2021/04/22/free-resources-for-the-stock-market/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/04/22/free-resources-for-the-stock-market/</guid><description>Every new trader in the stock market must wade through a myriad of tools, platforms, and websites that claim to have the best stock market research around. Some are free, some are not, and some cost so much that they eat into plenty of your profits.
This post rounds up all of the best research options out there that you can have for free (or almost free). I&amp;rsquo;m sure I missed a few, but these are the ones I rely on most often.</description></item><item><title>Defending losing options trades</title><link>https://major.io/2021/02/10/defending-losing-options-trades/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/02/10/defending-losing-options-trades/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading. If you are new to options trading, you may want to start with some of my earlier posts.
You did your research. You waited for a good time to sell a put option. You received a decent premium for your option trade. Now your trade has turned into a loss. What can you do now?
There are good choices for these situations, but there&amp;rsquo;s something important to remember.</description></item><item><title>Which stock broker should you use?</title><link>https://major.io/2021/01/24/which-stock-broker-should-you-use/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/01/24/which-stock-broker-should-you-use/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading. If you are new to options trading, you may want to start with some of my earlier posts.
One of my sports coaches in high school used to say: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the tool, it&amp;rsquo;s the fool.&amp;rdquo; This was his reminder that when something goes wrong in the game, it&amp;rsquo;s usually the fault of the person and not the equipment.</description></item><item><title>Choosing options to sell</title><link>https://major.io/2021/01/23/choosing-options-to-sell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/01/23/choosing-options-to-sell/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading. If you are new to options trading, you may want to start with some of my earlier posts.
You know your terminology, you know your max loss, and you are ready to start. Now you&amp;rsquo;re faced with the difficult question all new options traders face:
How do I choose which option to sell?
At first, you learn to look for the trades that are right for you.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from selling puts</title><link>https://major.io/2021/01/04/lessons-learned-from-selling-puts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2021/01/04/lessons-learned-from-selling-puts/</guid><description>🤔 This is another post in a set of posts on options trading on the blog. If you are confused on terminology, go back and start with the first post and the series and work your way to this one.
My options trading journey started back in September 2020 and I learned a lot in a short amount of time. This post covers some of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>Know your max loss</title><link>https://major.io/2020/12/09/know-your-max-loss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/12/09/know-your-max-loss/</guid><description>This is the third post in a series of posts on options trading. You can read this one out of order since it applies to almost everything you do in the stock market, including buying shares of stock.
What is &amp;ldquo;max loss&amp;rdquo; The maximum loss on a trade is the worst outcome possible. Knowing this number helps you protect your account from huge losses and avoids terrible situations such as margin calls.</description></item><item><title>The Dark Side: Selling Options</title><link>https://major.io/2020/12/07/the-dark-side-selling-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/12/07/the-dark-side-selling-options/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started a series of posts on options trading and if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read yesterdays post, Options trading introduction, you should start there first.
Recap: Buying calls and puts Just to recap the introductory post:
Buying a call gives you the right to buy a stock at a certain strike price Buying a put gives you the right to sell a stock at a certain strike price Buying calls is a great way to capture gains from a stock that is trending upwards an buying puts provides an insurance policy in case your stock drops.</description></item><item><title>Options trading introduction</title><link>https://major.io/2020/12/06/options-trading-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2020/12/06/options-trading-introduction/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always on the hunt for new things to learn and one of my newer interests is around trading options on the stock market. Much like technology, it becomes much easier to understand when you peel back the layers of archaic terminology, snake oil salespeople, and debunked data.
Stay tuned for additional posts that go into greater detail. This post covers the basics about what an option is (and is not) and how you can compare it to other investment vehicles, like stocks.</description></item></channel></rss>