<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apple on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in apple on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 14:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Show originating IP address in Apple Mail</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/18/show-originating-ip-address-in-apple-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 14:20:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/18/show-originating-ip-address-in-apple-mail/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received some very sophisticated phishing emails lately and I was showing some of them to my coworkers. One of my coworkers noticed that my Apple Mail client displays the X-Originating-IP header for all of the emails I receive.
You can enter that IP into a whois search and get a better idea of who sent you the message without diving into the headers. If someone that regularly exchanges email with me suddenly has an originating IP in another country that would be unusual for them to travel to, I can approach the message with more caution.</description></item><item><title>One week with Android</title><link>https://major.io/2012/09/06/one-week-with-android/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 03:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/09/06/one-week-with-android/</guid><description>After getting Android-envy at LinuxCon, I decided to push myself out of my comfort zone and ditch my iPhone 4 for a Samsung Galaxy S III. It surprised a lot of people I know since I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big iPhone fan since the original model was released in 2007. I&amp;rsquo;ve carried the original iPhone, the 3GS, and then the 4. There have been good times and bad times, but the devices have served me pretty well overall.</description></item><item><title>Single boot Linux on an Intel Mac Mini</title><link>https://major.io/2011/01/26/single-boot-linux-on-an-intel-mac-mini/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 13:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2011/01/26/single-boot-linux-on-an-intel-mac-mini/</guid><description>After reading the title of this post, you might wonder “Why would someone pay for a Mac Mini and then not use OS X with it?” Well, if you have a somewhat older Mac Mini you want to use as a server with Linux, these instructions will come in handy.
To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a few things:
Mac OS X Install Disc Your favorite Linux distribution&amp;rsquo;s install or live CD/DVD A CD with refit on it First off, boot the Mac into your normal OS X installation first and mute the sound.</description></item><item><title>Disable acceleration for Apple’s Magic Mouse</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/03/disable-acceleration-for-apples-magic-mouse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 13:55:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/03/disable-acceleration-for-apples-magic-mouse/</guid><description>Edit: After further research, I found that this fix only adjusts the speed at which your mouse moves. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything for the acceleration curve.
I recently picked up a Magic Mouse and discovered that I like almost all of its features. The biggest headache is the funky mouse acceleration curve that it applies by default. When you make small movements, they barely even register on the screen. When you make big movements and slow down a little mid-move, the pointer slows down much too rapidly.</description></item><item><title>Syncing an iPhone with a new Mac without hassles</title><link>https://major.io/2008/11/02/syncing-an-iphone-with-a-new-mac-without-hassles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 16:56:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/11/02/syncing-an-iphone-with-a-new-mac-without-hassles/</guid><description>I know I usually talk about Linux server related topics on this blog, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud of what I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out this morning on my Mac. As you know, the iPhone can really only fully sync with one machine, and if you want to connect it to a new Mac that you&amp;rsquo;ve purchased, you have to fully erase the iPhone and start over. (Of course, if you used the Migration Assistant to set up your new Mac, this won&amp;rsquo;t be necessary.</description></item></channel></rss>