<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wordpress on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in wordpress on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:11:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflecting on 10 years of (mostly) technical blogging</title><link>https://major.io/2017/03/10/reflecting-on-10-years-of-mostly-technical-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:11:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/03/10/reflecting-on-10-years-of-mostly-technical-blogging/</guid><description>It all started shortly after I joined Rackspace in December of 2006. I needed a place to dump the huge amounts of information I was learning as an entry-level Linux support technician and I wanted to store everything in a place where it could be easily shared. The blog was born!
The blog now has over 700 posts on topics ranging from Linux system administration to job interview preparation. I&amp;rsquo;ll get an email or a tweet once every few weeks from someone saying: &amp;ldquo;I ran into a problem, Googled for it, and found your blog!</description></item><item><title>Woot! Eight years of my blog</title><link>https://major.io/2015/04/14/woot-eight-years-of-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:53:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/04/14/woot-eight-years-of-my-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>The spring of 2015 marks eight years of this blog! I&amp;rsquo;ve learned plenty of tough lessons along the way and I&amp;rsquo;ve made some changes recently that might be handy for other people. After watching &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sashalaund">Sasha Laundy&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> video from her awesome talk at Pycon 2015&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, I&amp;rsquo;m even more energized to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with other people. &lt;em>(Seriously: Go watch that video or review the slides whether you work in IT or not. It&amp;rsquo;s worth your time.)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrade OpenSSL, then upgrade WordPress</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/10/upgrade-openssl-then-upgrade-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 13:06:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/10/upgrade-openssl-then-upgrade-wordpress/</guid><description>The internet has been buzzing about the heartbleed OpenSSL vulnerability but another critical update came out this week: WordPress 3.8.2. The update fixes two CVE&amp;rsquo;s and a few other security issues.
eWeek has an informative article with additional details on the update.</description></item><item><title>Five years of rackerhacker.com</title><link>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2012/02/14/five-years-of-rackerhacker-com/</guid><description>Today marks the fifth year that this blog has existed on the internet. I bought the domain on February 14th, 2007 and tossed together a quick WordPress installation (I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember the version now!) to hold my notes that I was gathering at work.
Rackspace as an entry-level Linux system administrator. The abrupt change from &amp;ldquo;top dog at the startup&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;wow, I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Linux&amp;rdquo; caught me by surprise and I was trying to stuff as much knowledge into my brain as quickly as I could.</description></item><item><title>One month with GlusterFS in production</title><link>https://major.io/2010/08/11/one-month-with-glusterfs-in-production/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 13:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/08/11/one-month-with-glusterfs-in-production/</guid><description>As many of you might have noticed from my previous GlusterFS blog post and my various tweets, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with GlusterFS in production for my personal hosting needs for just over a month. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been learning quite a bit from some of the folks in the #gluster channel on Freenode. On a few occasions I&amp;rsquo;ve even been able to help out with some configuration problems from other users.</description></item><item><title>WordPress + W3 Total Cache + MaxCDN How-To</title><link>https://major.io/2010/02/13/wordpress-w3-total-cache-maxcdn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 03:56:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2010/02/13/wordpress-w3-total-cache-maxcdn/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of WordPress as a blog and CMS platform. While it does have its problems, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple to set up, it&amp;rsquo;s extensible, and - when properly configured - it has great performance. The WP Super Cache plugin has been a staple on my WordPress blogs for quite some time and it has solved almost all of my performance problems.
However, when you load up quite a few plugins or a heavy theme, the performance will dip due to the increased number of stylesheets, javascript files, and images.</description></item><item><title>WordPress and PHP 5.3.x: update_comment_type_cache() expected to be a reference</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/21/wordpress-and-php-5-3-x-update_comment_type_cache-expected-to-be-a-reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/21/wordpress-and-php-5-3-x-update_comment_type_cache-expected-to-be-a-reference/</guid><description>I upgraded a Fedora 11 instance to Fedora 12 and found the following error at the top of one of my WordPress blogs:
Parameter 1 to update_comment_type_cache() expected to be a reference, value given in wp-includes/plugin.php on line 166 The problem wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a plugin, actually. It was within my theme&amp;rsquo;s (R755-light) functions.php:
function update_comment_type_cache(&amp;amp;$queried_posts) { The temporary fix is to remove the &amp;amp; from that line so it looks like this:</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.9</title><link>https://major.io/2009/12/21/upgraded-to-wordpress-2-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 13:47:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/12/21/upgraded-to-wordpress-2-9/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t upgraded your WordPress installation to version 2.9 yet, you might want to consider doing that soon. There are quite a few improvements, bug fixes and security features available in the new version.
The automatic upgrade via the admin interface actually worked just fine for me. Of course, I backed up my database and files first, just to be sure.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.8.6 with some theme changes</title><link>https://major.io/2009/11/16/upgraded-to-wordpress-2-8-6-with-some-theme-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 04:32:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/11/16/upgraded-to-wordpress-2-8-6-with-some-theme-changes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded the blog to WordPress 2.8.6 after I read about the registered user exploits.
Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped the Adsimple theme I was using, and I&amp;rsquo;m now using a slightly modified Dojo theme. It&amp;rsquo;s a little easier on the eyes, but it&amp;rsquo;s still lightweight enough to be fast on mobile broadband connections.
Let me know what you think!</description></item><item><title>Requiring SSL encryption for WordPress administration</title><link>https://major.io/2009/07/31/requiring-ssl-encryption-for-wordpress-administration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 13:13:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/07/31/requiring-ssl-encryption-for-wordpress-administration/</guid><description>I was digging around for WordPress plugins last night that would allow me to secure the administrative login page for my WordPress installations. Most of the plugins are only compatible with WordPress 2.7.x or earlier, so I was a little concerned about them working with WordPress 2.8.2.
Then I stumbled upon the WordPress documentation that shows you how to require SSL with no plugins at all. If you&amp;rsquo;re using WordPress 2.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded WordPress to 2.8.2</title><link>https://major.io/2009/07/29/upgraded-wordpress-to-2-8-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 22:22:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/07/29/upgraded-wordpress-to-2-8-2/</guid><description>I finally made it around to upgrading WordPress to 2.8.2 and it seems to be working like a charm. It looks like there were some bug fixes and a XSS vulnerability was patched.</description></item><item><title>Ugly upgrade path from WordPress 2.7.1 to 2.8</title><link>https://major.io/2009/06/13/ugly-upgrade-path-from-wordpress-2-7-1-to-2-8/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 17:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/06/13/ugly-upgrade-path-from-wordpress-2-7-1-to-2-8/</guid><description>When I tried to do an automatic upgrade from WordPress 2.7.1 to 2.8 yesterday, it failed miserably. The files were all put in place, but when I tried to load /wp-admin/upgrade.php, this error popped up:
I was perplexed at the error, so I restored from a backup and began upgrading manually. The manual upgrades have always worked well for me in the past, so I figured this would probably fix the problem.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.7</title><link>https://major.io/2008/12/25/upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 03:45:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/12/25/upgraded-to-wordpress-27/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded the blog successfully to WordPress 2.7 (with a bit of frustration). When I attempted the upgrade, I received this error:
Call to undefined method wpdb::has_cap() in schema.php on line 22
Even though I followed the instructions on the WordPress site, and I disabled all of my plugins, the error kept appearing. The only parts of the site that remained unchanged after the upgrade were the wp-config.php page and the wp-content directory.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.6.5</title><link>https://major.io/2008/12/01/upgraded-to-wordpress-265/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 00:18:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/12/01/upgraded-to-wordpress-265/</guid><description>If you run a WordPress blog, and you haven&amp;rsquo;t upgraded to WordPress 2.6.5, you might want to make the move soon. There were a few bugs and security issues fixed, along with other changes.</description></item><item><title>Working hard on PleskHacker</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/25/working-hard-on-pleskhacker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/25/working-hard-on-pleskhacker/</guid><description>Some of you may have already noticed from my Twitter feed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve started a complete re-write of pleskhacker.com in an easier-to-use format. The old site was done in Dokuwiki, and I found that it didn&amp;rsquo;t scale too well. The new site uses WordPress, and the performance is already improving.
Another improvement to the site is that it is now hosted on Mosso. This should allow the site to handle a lot more traffic and be more redundant than the original configuration.</description></item><item><title>New look</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/20/new-look/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 20:19:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/20/new-look/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to adjust the look of this blog to make it easier to read and faster to download. My old Mandigo theme was great, but it required each user to download about 200kb worth of content to see the blog. The new theme is about 30-40kb per download and it renders faster in all the browsers I&amp;rsquo;ve tested.
Leave a comment and let me know what you think of the changes.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.6.2</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/09/upgraded-to-wordpres-262/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 03:16:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/09/upgraded-to-wordpres-262/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the blog to WordPress 2.6.2 tonight. There are some relatively serious security concerns with some of the code in WordPress 2.6.1, so I&amp;rsquo;d recommend upgrading at your earliest convenience.
Slide on over to the WordPress site and download it now.</description></item><item><title>Upgraded to WordPress 2.6.1</title><link>https://major.io/2008/08/30/upgraded-to-wordpress-261/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 02:17:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/08/30/upgraded-to-wordpress-261/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just upgraded this blog to WordPress 2.6.1. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t upgraded yours, you may want to get started. You can review the changelog as well.</description></item><item><title>First post using the WordPress iPhone application</title><link>https://major.io/2008/07/22/first-post-using-the-wordpress-iphone-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 14:50:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/07/22/first-post-using-the-wordpress-iphone-application/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t downloaded the new WordPress application for the iPhone yet, you might want to check it out. So far, it seems to work really well!</description></item><item><title>WordPress 2.6</title><link>https://major.io/2008/07/15/wordpress-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 20:30:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/07/15/wordpress-26/</guid><description>WordPress 2.6 is now available, and I&amp;rsquo;ve just upgraded today. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t upgraded yet, download it and follow the instructions.</description></item><item><title>WordPress upgraded to 2.3.3</title><link>https://major.io/2008/02/05/wordpress-upgraded-to-233/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:48:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/02/05/wordpress-upgraded-to-233/</guid><description>I botched my upgrade to 2.3.3 for a short while (sorry for the errors!), but everything is back to normal now. There&amp;rsquo;s a critical XMLRPC vulnerability in 2.3.2, so you might want to upgrade soon!</description></item><item><title>Why you should use caching for WordPress blogs</title><link>https://major.io/2007/12/06/why-you-should-use-caching-for-wordpress-blogs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 18:09:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/12/06/why-you-should-use-caching-for-wordpress-blogs/</guid><description>I had some time to do some testing of my blog&amp;rsquo;s performance today, and I discovered how much of a difference the WP-Cache plugin makes.
This blog runs on a server with dual Xeon Woodcrest CPU&amp;rsquo;s, 64-bit CentOS 4.5 and a 100mbit network connection. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first test with WP-Cache turned off:
$ http_load -parallel 10 -seconds 30 urltocheck.txt &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;346&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; fetches, 10 max parallel, 1.78616e+07 bytes, in 30 seconds 51623.2 mean bytes/connection 11.</description></item></channel></rss>