<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>plesk on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/plesk/</link><description>Recent content in plesk on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:04:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/plesk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Plesk: Upgrade to 8.4 causes “no such user” error in maillog</title><link>https://major.io/2008/11/06/plesk-upgrade-to-84-causes-no-such-user-error-in-maillog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 17:04:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/11/06/plesk-upgrade-to-84-causes-no-such-user-error-in-maillog/</guid><description>If you have a Plesk server where short mail names are enabled, upgrading to Plesk 8.4 can cause some issues. Valid logins may be rejected, and they&amp;rsquo;ll appear in your /usr/local/psa/var/log/maillog as &amp;ldquo;no such user&amp;rdquo;. You can correct the issue by switching to long mail names (click Server -&amp;gt; Mail in Plesk), or you can run a shell script provided by Parallels.
For further details, refer to the Plesk KB article &amp;ldquo;Mail users cannot get or send mail after upgrade to Plesk 8.</description></item><item><title>Working hard on PleskHacker</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/25/working-hard-on-pleskhacker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/25/working-hard-on-pleskhacker/</guid><description>Some of you may have already noticed from my Twitter feed, but I&amp;rsquo;ve started a complete re-write of pleskhacker.com in an easier-to-use format. The old site was done in Dokuwiki, and I found that it didn&amp;rsquo;t scale too well. The new site uses WordPress, and the performance is already improving.
Another improvement to the site is that it is now hosted on Mosso. This should allow the site to handle a lot more traffic and be more redundant than the original configuration.</description></item><item><title>SquirrelMail: 127 Can’t execute command</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/08/squirrelmail-127-cant-execute-command/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/08/squirrelmail-127-cant-execute-command/</guid><description>I found a Plesk 8.3 server running RHEL 4 last month that was presenting errors when users attempted to send e-mail via SquirrelMail:
ERROR: Email delivery error Server replied: 127 Can't execute command '/usr/sbin/sendmail -i -t -fsomeuser@somedomain.com'. The error was appearing because safe_mode was enabled and SquirrelMail was unable to drop e-mails into /usr/sbin/squirrelmail. After disabling safe_mode on the server, the users were able to send e-mails via SquirrelMail.</description></item><item><title>Enabling Ruby on Rails support for a domain in Plesk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/08/11/enabling-ruby-on-rails-support-for-a-domain-in-plesk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 01:16:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/08/11/enabling-ruby-on-rails-support-for-a-domain-in-plesk/</guid><description>If you have Plesk 8.1 or later, you have support available for Ruby on Rails. Unfortunately, clicking the FastCGI checkbox in Plesk won&amp;rsquo;t get you all of the support you need (and expect). The folks over at Parallels created a relatively simple process to get Ruby on Rails working properly on your site:
Go to your domain that you want to adjust, and click Setup. Make sure the CGI and FastCGI options are enabled.</description></item><item><title>Plesk 8.4.0: Unable to use short names for POP3/IMAP</title><link>https://major.io/2008/07/28/plesk-840-unable-to-use-short-names-for-pop3imap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 16:08:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/07/28/plesk-840-unable-to-use-short-names-for-pop3imap/</guid><description>If you recently upgraded to Plesk 8.4.0 with short names enabled, you may have found that it&amp;rsquo;s working with SMTP, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with POP3 or IMAP. There&amp;rsquo;s a bug in the Plesk version that prevents the courier configuration from being updated.
To correct the issue, first make sure that Plesk has short names enabled (Server &amp;gt; Mail). Once you&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed that Plesk thinks it&amp;rsquo;s enabled, add SHORTNAMES=1 to the following configuration files:</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding statistics from previous months on Plesk 8.3</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/20/rebuilding-statistics-from-previous-months-on-plesk-83/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 17:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/20/rebuilding-statistics-from-previous-months-on-plesk-83/</guid><description>There was a bug in versions of Plesk prior to 8.3 where the AWStats statistics for the previous months were unavailable. It was a bug within Plesk&amp;rsquo;s AWStat&amp;rsquo;s implementation, and it was fixed in Plesk 8.3.
However, the fix only corrected the issue moving forward after the upgrade. There was no automated way to rebuild the previous months' statistics, even though the AWStats data was right there on the disk!</description></item><item><title>Why I use Plesk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/06/17/why-i-use-plesk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/06/17/why-i-use-plesk/</guid><description>It seems like I have a conversation like this one at least once a week:
Them: &amp;ldquo;Hey Major, you&amp;rsquo;re a pretty nerdy guy, what server distro do you use?&amp;rdquo;
Me: &amp;ldquo;I use CentOS 4 right now.&amp;rdquo;
Them: &amp;ldquo;CentOS? Why not use something more cutting edge, like Fedora or Gentoo?&amp;rdquo;
Me: &amp;ldquo;Well, I like those, but Plesk works really well with CentOS.&amp;rdquo;
Them: &amp;ldquo;Seriously? You use Plesk? WHY?&amp;rdquo;
My CentOS server hosts a fair amount of domains for people I know and people I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>Parallels Summit 2008 – Day 1</title><link>https://major.io/2008/05/19/parallels-summit-2008-day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 03:52:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/05/19/parallels-summit-2008-day-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying the Parallels Summit in Washington D.C. this week. The folks from Parallels have been great, and the vendors we have met are selling some pretty tremendous products.
Lots of folks have been asking for a summary of what&amp;rsquo;s going on after my Twitter posts appeared earlier today. Here&amp;rsquo;s the latest information I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and heard today:
Parallels Development Strategy
» Create an SMB edition, solidity the Application Packaging Standard (APS), and further integrate billing</description></item><item><title>Forcing qmail to process e-mail in the queue</title><link>https://major.io/2008/05/02/forcing-qmail-to-process-e-mail-in-the-queue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 17:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/05/02/forcing-qmail-to-process-e-mail-in-the-queue/</guid><description>Normally, qmail will be able to process the mail queue without any interaction from the system administrator, however, if you want to force it to process everything that is in the queue right now, you can do so:
kill -ALRM `pgrep qmail-send` If for some peculiar reason you don&amp;rsquo;t have pgrep on your server, you can go about it a slightly different way:
kill -ALRM `ps ax | grep qmail-send | grep -v grep | awk '{print $1}'` Your logs should begin filling up with data about e-mails rolling through the queue.</description></item><item><title>After Plesk upgrade, “Cannot initialize InnoDB”</title><link>https://major.io/2008/05/01/after-plesk-upgrade-cannot-initialize-innodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/05/01/after-plesk-upgrade-cannot-initialize-innodb/</guid><description>Upgrading Plesk from 7.5.x to 8.x will change your Plesk-related MySQL tables from MyISAM to InnoDB. This allows for better concurrency in the Plesk panel when a lot of users are logged in simultaneously. However, some server administrators will disable InnoDB support in MySQL to save resources. This will cause problems after the upgrade.
Plesk may display an error on a white page that looks something like:
Cannot initialize InnoDB</description></item><item><title>Plesk: Disabling TRACE/TRACK methods globally</title><link>https://major.io/2008/04/23/plesk-disabling-tracetrack-methods-globally/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 23:40:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/04/23/plesk-disabling-tracetrack-methods-globally/</guid><description>UPDATE: The TRACE/TRACK methods are disabled in Plesk 8.4 right out of the box!
It&amp;rsquo;s always been a bit of a challenge to disable TRACE and TRACK methods with Plesk. The only available options were to create a ton of vhost.conf files or adjust the httpd.include files and prevent modifications with chattr (which is a bad idea on many levels).
Luckily, Parallels has made things easier with a new knowledge base article.</description></item><item><title>mchk: Unable to initialize quota settings for someuser@somedomain.com</title><link>https://major.io/2008/04/14/mchk-unable-to-initialize-quota-settings-for-someusersomedomaincom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/04/14/mchk-unable-to-initialize-quota-settings-for-someusersomedomaincom/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working in Plesk and you receive this error:
mchk: Unable to initialize quota settings for someuser@somedomain.com
Run this command to fix the issue, but be patient:
find /var/qmail/mailnames -type d -name '.*' ! -name '.spamassassin' -ls -exec touch '{}'/maildirfolder \; -exec chown popuser:popuser '{}'/maildirfolder \; Thanks to Mike Jackson for this one.</description></item><item><title>Setting the maximum mail size in qmail</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/24/setting-the-maximum-mail-size-in-qmail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 18:54:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/24/setting-the-maximum-mail-size-in-qmail/</guid><description>On a Plesk server, the maximum size for an individual e-mail sent through qmail is unlimited. You can limit this size by adding a number to the /var/qmail/control/databytes file.
If you wanted to limit this to something like 10MB, you can just run the following command:
echo &amp;quot;10485760&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /var/qmail/control/databytes This will limit the size of messages (including attachments) to 10MB as a maximum.</description></item><item><title>Reduce iowait in Plesk: put qmail’s queue on a ramdisk</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/14/reduce-iowait-in-plesk-put-qmails-queue-on-a-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 18:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/14/reduce-iowait-in-plesk-put-qmails-queue-on-a-ramdisk/</guid><description>I really dislike qmail. But, since I use Plesk, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck with it. However, I found a way to improve it&amp;rsquo;s awful mail queue performance by putting the mail queue onto a ramdisk. This is actually pretty darned easy to do.
First, toss a line like this into your /etc/fstab:
none /mailqueue tmpfs defaults,size=100m,nr_inodes=999k,mode=775 0 0 This will make a 100MB ramdisk on /mailqueue. Now, just symlink /var/qmail/mqueue to /mailqueue and move your e-mail over:</description></item><item><title>Plesk Professional Website Editor hangs at login</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/13/plesk-professional-website-editor-hangs-at-login/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 18:11:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/13/plesk-professional-website-editor-hangs-at-login/</guid><description>One of my biggest Plesk gripes is dealing with the Plesk Professional Website Editor. One of the most common occurrences with PPWSE is that it hangs when you attempt to log into the server. Normally, this happens when a server is behind a firewall, and it is using private IP&amp;rsquo;s.
Plesk will actually query the DNS for the domain (rather than simply connecting to the localhost), try to reach the public IP, and the traffic will be blocked by the firewall.</description></item><item><title>Strange error with Horde 3.1.3 and Plesk 8.1.1</title><link>https://major.io/2008/03/10/strange-error-with-horde-313-and-plesk-811/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 02:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/03/10/strange-error-with-horde-313-and-plesk-811/</guid><description>I saw a ticket the other day where a customer received this error from Horde when trying to expand items on the left pane of the interface:
Fatal error: Cannot use string offset as an array in /www/horde/lib/Horde/Block/Layout/Manager.php on line 389
It turns out that Plesk 8.1.1 bundles Horde 3.1.3 which has an occasional bug within the interface. Upgrading to Plesk 8.2.0 corrects the issue as Horde 3.1.4 is installed with the upgrade.</description></item><item><title>High iowait on RHEL 4 with Plesk and SpamAssassin</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/31/high-iowait-on-rhel-4-with-plesk-and-spamassassin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 18:38:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/31/high-iowait-on-rhel-4-with-plesk-and-spamassassin/</guid><description>One of my biggest complaints on RHEL 4 is the large resource usage by the version of SpamAssassin that is installed. When it runs, it uses a ton of CPU time and causes a lot of disk I/O as well. When running top, you may see multiple spamd processes. For a high-volume e-mail server (like the one I administer), this is simply unacceptable.
I decided to do something about it, and here are the steps:</description></item><item><title>Plesk and MySQL 5</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/30/plesk-and-mysql-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 18:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/30/plesk-and-mysql-5/</guid><description>One of the questions I receive the most is: &amp;ldquo;What version of Plesk works with MySQL 5?&amp;rdquo; The minimum version of Plesk for MySQL 5 is 8.1.0. If you install MySQL 5 on a version prior to 8.1.0, you may be able to access then panel in the other 8.x versions, but your upgrades will fail miserably.
In case you&amp;rsquo;re curious about a slightly older system, full MySQL 4 support was available in Plesk 7.</description></item><item><title>Can’t enable DNSBL/RBL in Plesk because it’s greyed out</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/25/cant-enable-dnsblrbl-in-plesk-because-its-greyed-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 17:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/25/cant-enable-dnsblrbl-in-plesk-because-its-greyed-out/</guid><description>If you have a new Plesk installation and the following option is greyed out in Server -&amp;gt; Mail:
Switch on spam protection based on DNS blackhole lists
Just install the following RPM from Plesk:
psa-qmail-rblsmtpd</description></item><item><title>qmail: This message is looping: it already has my Delivered-To line</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/23/qmail-this-message-is-looping-it-already-has-my-delivered-to-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/23/qmail-this-message-is-looping-it-already-has-my-delivered-to-line/</guid><description>I stumbled upon this peculiar bounce message recently while working on a server:
Hi. This is the qmail-send program at yourmailserver.com. I'm afraid I wasn't able to deliver your message to the following addresses. This is a permanent error; I've given up. Sorry it didn't work out. &amp;lt;user1@domain.com&amp;gt;: This message is looping: it already has my Delivered-To line. (#5.4.6) --- Below this line is a copy of the message.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; Return-Path: &amp;lt;remoteuser@otherdomain.</description></item><item><title>Removing news feeds in Horde</title><link>https://major.io/2008/01/21/removing-news-feeds-in-horde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 18:36:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/01/21/removing-news-feeds-in-horde/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve used newer versions of Horde with Plesk, you have probably noticed the news feed that runs down the left side of the screen. Depending on the types of e-mails you receive, you may get some pretty odd news popping up on the screen.
Luckily, you can remove the news feeds pretty easily. Open the following file in your favorite text editor:
/usr/share/psa-horde/templates/portal/sidebar.inc
Once the file is open, drop down to line 102 and comment out the entire if() statement (lines 102-117).</description></item><item><title>Plesk and qmail: 421 temporary envelope failure (#4.3.0)</title><link>https://major.io/2007/12/04/plesk-and-qmail-421-temporary-envelope-failure-430/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 18:21:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/12/04/plesk-and-qmail-421-temporary-envelope-failure-430/</guid><description>I stumbled upon a server running Plesk 8.2.1 where a certain user could not receive e-mail. I sent an e-mail to the user from my mail client, and I never saw it enter the user&amp;rsquo;s mailbox. It didn&amp;rsquo;t even appear in the logs.
After checking the usual suspects, like MX records, mail account configuration, and firewalls, I was unable to find out why it was occurring. Even after a run of mchk, the emails would not be delivered.</description></item><item><title>Fixing Horde problems in Plesk 8.1.x/8.2.x with PHP 5.2.5</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/28/fixing-horde-problems-in-plesk-81x82x-with-php-525/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 18:33:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/28/fixing-horde-problems-in-plesk-81x82x-with-php-525/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a few issues with PHP 5.2.5 and the version of Horde that is bundled with Plesk 8.1.x and 8.2.x. The PHP include paths that appear in the Apache configuration generated by Plesk conflict with the PHP installation, and that causes the Horde webmail interface to segmentation fault.
To fix the problem, create a file called /etc/httpd/conf.d/zz050a_horde_php_workaround.conf and put the following inside it:
&amp;lt;DirectoryMatch /usr/share/psa-horde&amp;gt; php_admin_value include_path &amp;#34;/usr/share/psa-horde/lib:/usr/share/psa-horde:/usr/share/psa-horde/pear:.&amp;#34; &amp;lt;/DirectoryMatch&amp;gt; Reload the Apache configuration and your Horde installation should work properly with PHP 5.</description></item><item><title>Sort e-mail in Plesk with procmail</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/27/sort-e-mail-in-plesk-with-procmail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 18:27:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/27/sort-e-mail-in-plesk-with-procmail/</guid><description>One of my biggest beefs with Plesk&amp;rsquo;s e-mail handling is the lack of server-side filtering. Plesk will only allow you to throw away e-mails marked as spam, but this won&amp;rsquo;t work for me since SpamAssassin marks some mails as spam that actually aren&amp;rsquo;t. If you set up filters in SquirrelMail or Horde, the filters will only work if you always log into the webmail interface to snag your e-mail.
Luckily, you can do some fancy work with procmail to have the filtering done server-side.</description></item><item><title>Plesk authorization failed: HTTP request error [7]</title><link>https://major.io/2007/11/14/plesk-authorization-failed-http-request-error-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 18:05:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2007/11/14/plesk-authorization-failed-http-request-error-7/</guid><description>I found myself wrestling with a server where the Plesk interface suddenly became unavailable without any user intervention. An attempt to start the service was less than fruitful:
[root@server ~]# service psa start Key file: /opt/drweb/drweb32.key - Key file not found! A path to a valid license key file does not specified. Plesk authorization failed: HTTP request error [7] Error: Plesk Software not running. [FAILED] (Although I included the text from the drweb failure, I later found that it was not related to the issue.</description></item></channel></rss>