<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>general advice on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/general-advice/</link><description>Recent content in general advice on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 01:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/general-advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Takeaways from Bruce Schneier’s talk: “Security and Privacy in a Hyper-connected World”</title><link>https://major.io/2017/03/21/takeaways-from-bruce-schneiers-talk-security-and-privacy-in-a-hyper-connected-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 01:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2017/03/21/takeaways-from-bruce-schneiers-talk-security-and-privacy-in-a-hyper-connected-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_20170321_113057-e1490144858438.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>Bruce Schneier is one of my favorite speakers when it comes to the topic of all things security. His talk from IBM Interconnect 2017, &amp;ldquo;Security and Privacy in a Hyper-connected World&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, covered a wide range of security concerns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were plenty of great quotes from the talk (scroll to the end for those) and I will summarize the main takeaways in this post.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="people-process-and-technology">People, process, and technology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bruce hits this topic a lot and for good reason: a weak link in any of the three could lead to a breach and a loss of data. He talked about the concept of security as a product and a process. Security is part of every product we consume. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the safety of the food that makes it into our homes or the new internet-connected thermostat on the wall, security is part of the product.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The companies that sell these products have a wide variety of strategies for managing security issues. Vulnerabilities in an internet-connected teapot are not worth much since there isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of value there. It&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to assume that a teapot will have many more vulnerabilities than your average Apple or Android mobile device. Vulnerabilities in those devices are extremely valuable because the data we carry on those devices is valuable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="certainty-vs-uncertainty">Certainty vs. uncertainty&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The talk moved into incident response and how to be successful when the worst happens. Automation only works when there&amp;rsquo;s a high degree of certainty in the situation. If there are variables that can be plugged into an algorithm and a result comes out the other end, automation is fantastic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bruce recommended using orchestration when tackling uncertain situations, such as security incident responses. Orchestration involves people following processes and using technology where it makes sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He talked about going through TSA checkpoints where metal detectors and x-ray scanners essentially run the show. Humans are around when these pieces of technology detect a problem. If you put a weapon into your carry on, the x-ray scanner will notify a human and that human can take an appropriate response to escalate the problem. If a regular passenger has a firearm in a carry-on bag, the police should be alerted. If an Air Marshal has one, then the situation is handled entirely differently - by a human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One other aspect he noted was around the uncertainty surrounding our data. Our control over our data, and our control over the systems that hold our data, is decreasing. Bruce remarked that he has more control over what his laptop does than his thermostat.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ooda-loop">OODA loop&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bruce raised awareness around the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OODA_loop">OODA loop&lt;/a> and its value when dealing with security incidents. Savvy readers will remember that the OODA loop was the crux of my &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/MajorHayden/be-an-inspiration-not-an-impostor-texas-linux-fest-2015">Be an inspiration, not an impostor&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; talk about impostor syndrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His point was that the OODA loop is a great way to structure a response during a stressful situation. When the orchestration works well, the defenders can complete an OODA loop faster than their adversaries can. When it works really well, the defenders can find ways to disrupt the adversaries' OODA loops and thwart the attack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why should students learn to write code?</title><link>https://major.io/2016/10/10/why-should-students-learn-to-write-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 04:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/10/10/why-should-students-learn-to-write-code/</guid><description>There are lots of efforts underway to get students (young and old) to learn to write code. There are far-reaching efforts, like the Hour of Code, and plenty of smaller, more focused projects, such as the Design and Technology Academy (part of Northeast ISD here in San Antonio, Texas). These are excellent programs that enrich the education of many students.
I often hear a question from various people about these programs:</description></item><item><title>Preventing critical services from deploying on the same OpenStack host</title><link>https://major.io/2016/08/09/preventing-critical-services-from-deploying-on-the-same-openstack-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:07:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/08/09/preventing-critical-services-from-deploying-on-the-same-openstack-host/</guid><description>OpenStack&amp;rsquo;s compute service, nova, manages all of the virtual machines within a OpenStack cloud. When you ask nova to build an instance, or a group of instances, nova&amp;rsquo;s scheduler system determines which hypervisors should run each instance. The scheduler uses filters to figure out where each instance belongs.
However, there are situations where the scheduler might put more than one of your instances on the same host, especially when resources are constrained.</description></item><item><title>Talk recap: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible</title><link>https://major.io/2016/06/28/talk-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 03:43:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/06/28/talk-recap/</guid><description>The 2016 Red Hat Summit is underway in San Francisco this week and I delivered a talk with Robyn Bergeron earlier today. Our talk, When flexibility met simplicity: The friendship of OpenStack and Ansible, explained how Ansible can reduce the complexity of OpenStack environments without sacrificing the flexibility that private clouds offer.
The talk started at the same time as lunch began and the Partner Pavilion first opened, so we had some stiff competition for attendees' attention.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting OpenStack network connectivity</title><link>https://major.io/2016/05/16/troubleshooting-openstack-network-connectivity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 02:43:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/05/16/troubleshooting-openstack-network-connectivity/</guid><description>NOTE: This post is a work in progress. If you find something that I missed, feel free to leave a comment. I&amp;rsquo;ve made plenty of silly mistakes, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll make a few more. :)
Completing a deployment of an OpenStack cloud is an amazing feeling. There is so much automation and power at your fingertips as soon as you&amp;rsquo;re finished. However, the mood quickly turns sour when you create that first instance and it never responds to pings.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned: Five years of colocation</title><link>https://major.io/2016/04/22/lessons-learned-four-years-colocation-hosting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/04/22/lessons-learned-four-years-colocation-hosting/</guid><description>Back in 2011, I decided to try out a new method for hosting my websites and other applications: colocation. Before that, I used shared hosting, VPS providers (&amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; wasn&amp;rsquo;t a popular thing back then), and dedicated servers. Each had their drawbacks in different areas. Some didn&amp;rsquo;t perform well, some couldn&amp;rsquo;t recover from failure well, and some were terribly time consuming to maintain.
This post will explain why I decided to try colocation and will hopefully help you avoid some of my mistakes.</description></item><item><title>Fight cynicism with curiosity</title><link>https://major.io/2016/02/17/fight-cynicism-curiosity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 15:30:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/02/17/fight-cynicism-curiosity/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always interested to talk to college students about technology and business in general. They have amazing ideas and they don&amp;rsquo;t place any limits on themselves. In particular, their curiosity is limitless.
A great question I joined several other local employers at the University of Texas at San Antonio last week for mock interviews with computer science students. We went through plenty of sample questions and gave feedback to the students on their content and delivery during the mock interviews.</description></item><item><title>Nobody is using your software project. Now what?</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/15/nobody-using-software-project-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 17:35:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/15/nobody-using-software-project-now/</guid><description>Working with open source software is an amazing experience. The collaborative process around creation, refinement, and even maintenance, drives more developers to work on open source software more often. However, every developer finds themselves writing code that very few people actually use.
For some developers, this can be really bothersome. You offer your code up to the world only to find that the world is much less interested than you expected.</description></item><item><title>Talking to college students about information security</title><link>https://major.io/2015/11/10/talking-to-college-students-about-information-security/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 14:50:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/11/10/talking-to-college-students-about-information-security/</guid><description>I was recently asked to talk to Computer Information Systems students at the University of the Incarnate Word here in San Antonio about information security in the business world. The students are learning plenty of the technical parts of information security and the complexity that comes from dealing with complicated computer networks. As we all know, it&amp;rsquo;s the non-technical things that are often the most important in those tough situations.</description></item><item><title>Impostor syndrome talk: FAQs and follow-ups</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/02/impostor-syndrome-talk-faqs-and-follow-ups/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 15:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/02/impostor-syndrome-talk-faqs-and-follow-ups/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a great time talking to people about my &amp;ldquo;Be an inspiration, not an impostor&amp;rdquo; talk that I delivered in August. I spoke to audiences at Fedora Flock 2015, Texas Linux Fest, and at Rackspace. The biggest lesson I learned is that delivering talks is exhausting!
Frequently Asked Questions Someone asked a good one at Fedora Flock:
How do you deal with situations where you are an impostor for a reason you can&amp;rsquo;t change?</description></item><item><title>Fedora Flock 2015: Keynote slides</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/14/fedora-flock-2015-keynote-slides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 15:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/14/fedora-flock-2015-keynote-slides/</guid><description>Fedora Flock 2015 is still going here in Rochester, New York, and I kicked off our second day with a keynote talk about overcoming impostor syndrome.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to review the slides, they&amp;rsquo;re on SlideShare:
Quite a few people came up after the talk and throughout the day to share some of their stories and challenges. It was extremely rewarding to have those conversations and share solutions.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing the talk once more at Texas Linux Fest in San Marcos on August 22.</description></item><item><title>Review: JayBird BlueBuds X Sport Bluetooth Headphones</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/07/review-jaybird-bluebuds-x-sport-bluetooth-headphones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 13:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/07/review-jaybird-bluebuds-x-sport-bluetooth-headphones/</guid><description>As I try to motivate myself to exercise more often, I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled to find suitable headphones for running and other outdoor work. My criteria includes the following:
Needs to stay put on my ears, even when I get sweaty Wireless is preferable so I don&amp;rsquo;t get tangled For wireless, it should last three to four hours at a minimum It needs to sound decent The Bad I went through a slew of headphones.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Linux Kernel Development</title><link>https://major.io/2015/06/21/book-review-linux-kernel-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 15:26:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/06/21/book-review-linux-kernel-development/</guid><description>I picked up a copy of Robert Love&amp;rsquo;s book, Linux Kernel Development, earlier this year and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked my way through it over the past several weeks. A few people recommended the book to me on Twitter and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad they did. This book totally changed how I look at a system running Linux.
You must be this tall to ride this ride I&amp;rsquo;ve never had formal education in computer science or software development in the past.</description></item><item><title>Adventures with GRE and IPSec on Mikrotik routers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/05/27/adventures-with-gre-and-ipsec-on-mikrotik-routers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/05/27/adventures-with-gre-and-ipsec-on-mikrotik-routers/</guid><description>I recently picked up a RB850GX2 from my favorite Mikrotik retailer, r0c-n0c. It&amp;rsquo;s a dual-core PowerPC board with five ethernet ports and some decent performance for the price.
I still have the RB493G in a colocation and I usually connect my home and the colo via OpenVPN or IPSec. Networking is not one of my best skills and I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to learn more about it when I can. I decided to try out a GRE tunnel on top of IPSec this time around.</description></item><item><title>Review: Lenovo X1 Carbon 3rd generation and Linux</title><link>https://major.io/2015/03/30/review-lenovo-x1-carbon-3rd-generation-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/03/30/review-lenovo-x1-carbon-3rd-generation-and-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://major.io/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/ThinkPad-Carbon-X1.jpg" alt="1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a &lt;a href="../../2015/02/03/linux-support-dell-xps-13-9343-2015-model/">boatload of challenges&lt;/a> with what I thought would be my favorite Linux laptop, the &lt;a href="http://www.dell.com/us/p/xps-13-9343-laptop/pd">Dell XPS 13 9343&lt;/a>, I decided to take the plunge on a new &lt;a href="http://shop.lenovo.com/us/en/laptops/thinkpad/x-series/x1-carbon/">Lenovo X1 Carbon (3rd gen)&lt;/a>. My late-2013 MacBook Pro Retina (MacbookPro11,1) had plenty of quirks when running Linux and I was eager to find a better platform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Helpful, low-FUD information security sites, mailing lists, and blogs</title><link>https://major.io/2015/01/08/helpful-low-fud-information-security-sites-mailing-lists-blogs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/01/08/helpful-low-fud-information-security-sites-mailing-lists-blogs/</guid><description>Keeping current with the latest trends and technologies in the realm of information security is critical and there are many options to choose from. However, as with any content on the internet, it takes some effort to find sites with a good signal-to-noise ratio. Information security is a heavily FUD-laden industry and I&amp;rsquo;ve taken some time to compile a list of helpful sites.
General sites Cryptanalys.is: https://cryptanalys.is/ Linux Weekly News (subscription optional but highly recommended): http://lwn.</description></item><item><title>Two months with Google Play Music All Access</title><link>https://major.io/2014/12/29/two-months-google-play-music-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:26:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/12/29/two-months-google-play-music-access/</guid><description>After using Spotify for a couple of months, I decided to try Google Play Music All Access. My experience was quite good from the start:
Music selection My music tastes include some very popular artists as well as some less popular ones. I found that Spotify and Google Play almost always had what I was looking for. Some artists only have portions of their catalog available for streaming and I found the selection of music in both products to be identical.</description></item><item><title>Evade the Breach</title><link>https://major.io/2014/05/24/evade-the-breach/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 18:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/05/24/evade-the-breach/</guid><description>This post appeared on the Rackspace Bloglast week and I copied it here so that readers of this blog will see it.You&amp;rsquo;ve heard it before: information security isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. There&amp;rsquo;s no perfect security policy or piece of technology that will protect your business from all attacks. However, security is a process and processes can always be improved.
Last month, the great folks at Accruent invited me to talk about this topic at the annual Accruent Insights 2014 conference held in Austin, Texas.</description></item><item><title>DevOps and enterprise inertia</title><link>https://major.io/2014/04/17/devops-and-enterprise-inertia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 17:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/04/17/devops-and-enterprise-inertia/</guid><description>As I wait in the airport to fly back home from this year&amp;rsquo;s Red Hat Summit, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking back over the many conversations I had over breakfast, over lunch, and during the events. One common theme that kept cropping up was around bringing DevOps to the enterprise. I stumbled upon Mathias Meyer&amp;rsquo;s post, The Developer is Dead, Long Live the Developer, and I was inspired to write my own.
Before I go any further, here&amp;rsquo;s my definition of DevOps: it&amp;rsquo;s a mindset shift where everyone is responsible for the success of the customer experience.</description></item><item><title>Annoying security requests highlight company silos</title><link>https://major.io/2014/03/10/annoying-security-requests-highlight-company-silos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 13:39:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/03/10/annoying-security-requests-highlight-company-silos/</guid><description>I stumbled upon this video earlier today via Tripwire&amp;rsquo;s Twitter feed:
Some of the requests are hilarious, obviously, but many of them highlight a critical problem. In organizations where security is one department, silos develop and the &amp;ldquo;us versus them&amp;rdquo; mentality sets in quickly.
For organizations to grow and maintain security, the ownership of security and process maturity must be spread throughout the organization. Traditional corporate security teams simply cannot carry this burden alone.</description></item><item><title>Be an inspiration, not an impostor</title><link>https://major.io/2014/02/04/be-an-inspiration-not-an-impostor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 03:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2014/02/04/be-an-inspiration-not-an-impostor/</guid><description>Many of the non-technical posts on the blog are inspired by the comments of others. I stumbled upon this tweet after it was retweeted by someone I follow:
The link in the tweet takes you to a blog post from Erika Owens about impostor syndrome. Erika touches on that uncomfortable feeling that some of us feel when we&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by other people from our field of study or work. These three sentences hit home for me:</description></item><item><title>Information security nuggets from DevOps Weekly #150</title><link>https://major.io/2013/11/17/information-security-nuggets-from-devops-weekly-150/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 21:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/11/17/information-security-nuggets-from-devops-weekly-150/</guid><description>Keeping an eye out for the DevOps Weekly email is something I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed since it started at the end of 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s usually chock full of tips for systems engineers, developers, managers, or anyone who is focused on environments that utilize continuous integration and deployment strategies. Quite a few of the tips are totally relevant for information security professionals who are looking for an edge at work.
This week, there are four links worth reviewing if you work in information security:</description></item><item><title>One year in information security</title><link>https://major.io/2013/11/13/one-year-in-information-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 15:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/11/13/one-year-in-information-security/</guid><description>Going to the dark side. Those were my first thoughts about taking an information security role one year ago. One year later, the situation seems much brighter than I expected.
This role has taught me more about how our business operates, how we set priorities, and how to respond to a setback. I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate enough to meet some extremely intelligent people along the way. Some of them frighten me with their descriptions of past experiences or their adversaries.</description></item><item><title>Need an edge at work? Learn accounting and finance.</title><link>https://major.io/2013/09/16/need-an-edge-at-work-learn-accounting-and-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 04:06:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/09/16/need-an-edge-at-work-learn-accounting-and-finance/</guid><description>I spent two days last week in a class called &amp;ldquo;Accounting and Finance for Non-Financial Managers&amp;rdquo; at UT Austin&amp;rsquo;s Texas Executive Education program. The assigned reading (a book of the same name as the class) was informative but I still felt like it was too advanced for me right off the bat.
My main goal for the class was to learn how my role can have a financial impact as well as an information security impact.</description></item><item><title>Handling terminal color escape sequences in less</title><link>https://major.io/2013/05/21/handling-terminal-color-escape-sequences-in-less/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 02:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2013/05/21/handling-terminal-color-escape-sequences-in-less/</guid><description>This post is a quick one but I wanted to share it since I taught it to someone new today. When you have bash output with colors, less doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle the color codes properly by default:
$ colordiff chunk/functions.php chunk-old/functions.php | less ESC[0;32m22a23,27ESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; * Load up our functions for grabbing content from postsESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; */ESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; require( get_template_directory() . '/content-grabbers.php' );ESC[0;0m ESC[0;34m&amp;gt; ESC[0;0m Toss in the -R flag and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see the colors properly (no colors to see here, but use your imagination):</description></item></channel></rss>