<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>udev on Major Hayden 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/udev/</link><description>Recent content in udev on Major Hayden 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:46:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/udev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tinkering with systemd’s predictable network names</title><link>https://major.io/2016/01/20/tinkering-with-systemds-predictable-network-names/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:46:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2016/01/20/tinkering-with-systemds-predictable-network-names/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about predictable network names (and seemingly unpredictable ones) on the blog before, but some readers asked me how they could alter the network naming to fit a particular situation. Oddly enough, my Supermicro 5028D-T4NT has a problem with predictable names and it&amp;rsquo;s a great example to use here.
The problem There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of detail in my post about the Supermicro 5028D-T4NT, but the basic gist is that something within the firmware is causing the all of the network cards in the server to show up as onboard.</description></item><item><title>Customizing systemd’s network device names</title><link>https://major.io/2015/09/28/customizing-systemds-network-device-names/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 02:08:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/09/28/customizing-systemds-network-device-names/</guid><description>Earlier today, I wrote a post about my first thoughts on the Supermicro 5028D-T4NT server. The 10Gb interfaces on the server came up with the names eth0 and eth1. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I expected. There&amp;rsquo;s tons of detail on the problem in the blog post as well as the Github issue.
Kay Sievers gave a hint about how to adjust the interfacing naming in a more granular way than simply disabling the predictable network names.</description></item><item><title>Understanding systemd’s predictable network device names</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/21/understanding-systemds-predictable-network-device-names/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 21:15:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/21/understanding-systemds-predictable-network-device-names/</guid><description>I talked a bit about systemd&amp;rsquo;s network device name in my earlier post about systemd-networkd and bonding and I received some questions about how systemd rolls through the possible names of network devices to choose the final name. These predictable network device names threw me a curveball last summer when I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how the names were constructed.
Let&amp;rsquo;s walk through this process.
What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? Back in the systemd-networkd bonding post, I dug into a dual port Intel network card that showed up in a hotplug slot:</description></item><item><title>Using systemd-networkd with bonding on Rackspace’s OnMetal servers</title><link>https://major.io/2015/08/21/using-systemd-networkd-with-bonding-on-rackspaces-onmetal-servers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2015/08/21/using-systemd-networkd-with-bonding-on-rackspaces-onmetal-servers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about systemd-networkd in the past and how easy it can be to set up new network devices and tunnels. However, the documentation on systemd-networkd with bonding is a bit lacking (but I have a pull request pending for that).
Rackspace&amp;rsquo;s OnMetal Servers are a good place to test since they have bonded networks configured by default. They&amp;rsquo;re also quite fast and always fun for experiments.
To get started, head on over to the Rackspace Cloud control panel and build a compute-1 OnMetal server and choose Fedora 22 as your operating system.</description></item></channel></rss>