<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vmware on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</title><link>https://major.io/tags/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in vmware on Major Hayden's Blog 🤠</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 01:28:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://major.io/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enabling VNC as a pseudo-KVM with VMWare Server</title><link>https://major.io/2009/03/24/enabling-vnc-as-a-pseudo-kvm-with-vmware-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 01:28:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2009/03/24/enabling-vnc-as-a-pseudo-kvm-with-vmware-server/</guid><description>Mac users feel a little left out when it comes to VMWare Server clients. There&amp;rsquo;s one for Windows and Linux, but Mac users are out of luck. Sure, you can VNC into a Linux box, use X forwarding, or use RDC to access a Windows box, but a real Mac client would really be helpful.
However, I stumbled upon some documentation that will allow you to VNC to a VMWare Server VM&amp;rsquo;s main screen.</description></item><item><title>Listing of VMWare configuration parameters</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/05/listing-of-vmware-configuration-parameters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 17:09:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/05/listing-of-vmware-configuration-parameters/</guid><description>For a recent project, I needed to automatically provision VM&amp;rsquo;s for testing. I wanted to make the .vmx files on the fly with the exact configuration required, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find documentation for the options that are allowed in the .vmx files. Luckily, a fellow named Ulli Hankeln has made an impressive list available on his site.
The listings contain tons of options that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of, and it also provides hints on which ones you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t adjust.</description></item><item><title>CentOS/RHEL x86_64 + VMWare: Use of uninitialized value in string</title><link>https://major.io/2008/09/03/centosrhel-x86_64-vmware-use-of-uninitialized-value-in-string/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 17:06:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://major.io/2008/09/03/centosrhel-x86_64-vmware-use-of-uninitialized-value-in-string/</guid><description>I was working with a CentOS 5 x86_64 installation running VMWare server last week when I stumbled upon this error:
Use of uninitialized value in string eq at /usr/lib64/perl5/site_perl/5.8.8/x86_64-linux-thread-multi/VMware/VmPerl.pm line 114. You can run the vmware-cmd application with this error (it&amp;rsquo;s not a fatal error) and keep going with your normal business. However, if you want to remove the error, comment out lines 114 and 115 in the Perl module referenced by the error:</description></item></channel></rss>